<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="aem_start_421">
		<rus>Что теперь, не будет больше сражений на Арене, закроешь свою лавочку и подашься искать счастья в другие края?</rus>
		<eng>So now what, no more fights in the arena, I assume today you're closing your business and tomorrow you are another seeker of fortune in some different edge of the zone?</eng>
		<ukr>Що тепер, не буде більше битв на Арені, закриєш свою лавочку і подасися шукати щастя в інші краї?</ukr>
		<fra>Et maintenant ? Est-ce que les combats dans l'arène sont finis et que tu vas fermer boutique pour aller courir l'aventure dans la Zone ?</fra>
		<pln>I co teraz, nie będzie już walk na Arenie, zamkniesz interes i pójdziesz szukać szczęścia gdzie indziej?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_4211">
		<rus>Погоди, Меченый, не стоит делать поспешных выводов, то был лишь один турнир из многих.</rus>
		<eng>Hold on a second, Marked One, don’t rush your decisions, it was only a single tournament out of many.</eng>
		<ukr>Стривай, Мічений, не варто робити поспішних висновків, то був лише один турнір з багатьох.</ukr>
		<fra>Non,Strelok. Des tournois ouverts à tous vont bientôt débuter.</fra>
		<pln>Spokojnie, Naznaczony, nie należy pochopnie wyciągać wniosków, to był tylko jeden turniej z wielu.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_42111">
		<rus>Странно, но почему-то я так и думал с самого начала. Ну давай, раскрывай карты.</rus>
		<eng>Weird, but for some reason, this isn't a surprise to me. Alright, let's see your plans.</eng>
		<ukr>Дивно, але чомусь я так і думав з самого початку. Ну давай, розкривай карти.</ukr>
		<fra>J'en étais sûr! Explique-moi comment ça va se passer.</fra>
		<pln>Dziwne, ale z jakiegoś powodu od początku tego się spodziewałem. No to odkrywaj karty.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_421111">
		<rus>Значит так, в этот раз ты победил и стал Чемпионом Арены, но это всего-навсего переходящее звание и оно не даёт гарантий, что в следующем турнире ты не сыграешь в ящик. Турниры проводятся более-менее регулярно - раз или два в сутки, бои идут с 22:00 до 06:00, об открытии Арены узнаешь из сообщений, которые я буду передавать по общему каналу. Пока ты Чемпион у тебя полный доступ по выбору всех анонсированных боёв - это значит только тебе решать с кем, чем и в каком порядке драться. Только вот насчёт оружия есть несколько ограничений - нельзя использовать любые взрывчатые заряды и гранаты, тяжёлое вооружение: РГ-6, РПГ-7 и Гаусс-пушку. Вкратце всё, сейчас Арену нужно немного прибрать, так что пока можешь пойти в бар и хорошенько напиться, только не пропусти открытие. До скорого!</rus>
		<eng>Here how it is, this time you won and became a Champion of the Arena, but this is only a temporary title and it doesn't guarantee that next time you won't find yourself in the coffin. Tournaments are hosted somewhat regularly with an interval of once or twice a day, battles take place from 22:00 to 06:00, and I will be letting you know about the new rounds with messages in the general channel. While you're the Champion, you have a freedom of choice for your opponents, this means that you will be the one to decide against whom you will be fighting. Weapon wise, the only limitations are - no explosive charges, grenades and no heavy arms such as: RG-6, RPG-7 and Gauss-Gun. That's about it, now Arena requires a little clean up which means you have time to visit the Bar and buy a well deserved drink, except don't miss the opening. See you soon!</eng>
		<ukr>Значить так, цього разу ти переміг і став Чемпіоном Арени, але це всього-навсього перехідне звання і воно не дає гарантій, що в наступному турнірі ти не зіграєш в ящик. Турніри проводяться більш-менш регулярно - раз чи два на добу, бої йдуть з 22:00 до 06:00, про відкриття Арени дізнаєшся з повідомлень, які я буду передавати по загальному каналу. Поки ти Чемпіон у тебе повний доступ по вибору всіх анонсованих боїв - це означає тільки тобі вирішувати з ким, чим і в якому порядку битися. Тільки от щодо зброї є кілька обмежень - не можна використовувати будь-які вибухові заряди і гранати, важке озброєння: РГ-6, РПГ-7 і Гаусс-гармату. Коротше, зараз Арену потрібно трохи прибрати, так що поки можеш піти в бар і гарненько напитися, тільки не пропусти відкриття. До скорого!</ukr>
		<fra>Donc voici l'affaire. Tu as gagné et tu es devenu le champion de l'arène, mais ce n'est pas un titre permanent et cela ne donne aucune garantie que tu gagneras le prochain tournoi. Les tournois sont disputés régulièrement, tous les soirs entre 22h00-6h00. Tu seras averti par un message sur ton PDA avant qu'ils commencent. Comme tu es un champion, tu as accès à tous les combats possibles et tu peux décider toi-même des armes qui seront utilisées lors des combats. Nous avons aussi des règles concernant les armes. Les grenades, lance-grenades, fusil Gauss, lance-roquettes et les autres armes lourdes sont interdites. C'est à peu près tout. L'Arène a besoin d'un bon nettoyage, en attendant la réouverture va te payer un coup à boire au Bar. A bientôt, j'espère...!</fra>
		<pln>Znaczy tak, tym razem ty zwyciężyłeś i stałeś się Czempionem Areny, ale to tytuł przechodni i nie daje gwarancji, że w następnym turnieju nie trafisz na lepszego. Turnieje odbywają się w miarę regularnie - raz lub dwa na dobę, walki trwają od 22:00 do 06:00, o otwarciu Areny dowiesz się z wiadomości nadawanych na kanale ogólnym. Dopóki jesteś Czempionem, masz pełny dostęp do wyboru wszystkich zapowiadanych walk - to znaczy, że sam możesz decydować czym, z kim i w jakiej kolejności będziesz się bić. Ale w kwestii broni jest szereg ograniczeń - nie wolno stosować jakichkolwiek materiałów wybuchowych i granatów, ciężkiego wyposażenia: granatników RG-6, RPG-7 i działka gaussa. Pokrótce to wszystko, teraz trzeba Arenę trochę sprzątnąć, więc możesz iść do baru i golnąć sobie, tylko nie przegap otwarcia. Na razie!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_4211111">
		<rus>Перспективы радуют, бывай.</rus>
		<eng>Sweet options you got there, good-bye.</eng>
		<ukr>Перспективи радують, бувай.</ukr>
		<fra>Bonnes options,bien... Salut.</fra>
		<pln>Ciekawe perspektywy, bywaj.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_31">
		<rus>Ну здорово, Чемпион!</rus>
		<eng>Hey! It's the Champion himself!</eng>
		<ukr>Ну привіт, Чемпіон!</ukr>
		<fra>Hé!Salut champion!</fra>
		<pln>Witaj, Czempionie!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_311">
		<rus>Здорово, что у тебя нового?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, what's up?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт, що у тебе нового?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour. Quoi de neuf aujourd'hui?</fra>
		<pln>Witaj, co u ciebie nowego?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_3111">
		<rus>Эх, какой нетерпеливый, ещё участников маловато набралось, позже приходи.</rus>
		<eng>Ergh, you are too impatient, so far we are lacking participants, come back a little later.</eng>
		<ukr>Ех, який нетерплячий, ще учасників малувато набралося, пізніше приходь.</ukr>
		<fra>Eh, tu es bien impatient... Nous n'avons même pas encore réunis assez de candidats. Reviens un peu plus tard.</fra>
		<pln>Coś taki niecierpliwy, jeszcze za mało uczestników, przyjdź później.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_31111">
		<rus>Договорились.</rus>
		<eng>Deal.</eng>
		<ukr>Домовилися.</ukr>
		<fra>Bonne affaire.</fra>
		<pln>Umowa stoi.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_611">
		<rus>Поздравляю, угадал.</rus>
		<eng>Congratulations, you guessed it.</eng>
		<ukr>Вітаю, вгадав.</ukr>
		<fra>Félicitations. Tu as deviné juste.</fra>
		<pln>Gratulacje, zgadłeś.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_621">
		<rus>Не судьба - повезёт в другой раз.</rus>
		<eng>How unfortunate! May be better luck next time.</eng>
		<ukr>Не судьба - пощастить у другий раз.</ukr>
		<fra>Ne t'inquiète pas, la prochaine fois peut-être tu auras plus de chance.</fra>
		<pln>Nie wyszło - następnym razem się uda.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_631">
		<rus>Держи заслуженное.</rus>
		<eng>Here, you earned it.</eng>
		<ukr>Тримай заслужене.</ukr>
		<fra>Voici ton argent durement gagné.</fra>
		<pln>Trzymaj, zasłużyłeś.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_641">
		<rus>Отличный бой! Ты заработал награду и премиальные.</rus>
		<eng>What a fine fight you've put up there! Take your reward.</eng>
		<ukr>Відмінний бій! Ти заробив нагороду і преміальні.</ukr>
		<fra>Quel combat ! Tu mérites une récompense.</fra>
		<pln>Świetna walka! Zasłużyłeś na nagrodę i premię.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_651">
		<rus>Победа не засчитана.</rus>
		<eng>This victory doesn't count.</eng>
		<ukr>Перемога не зарахована.</ukr>
		<fra>Ta victoire ne sera pas prise en compte.</fra>
		<pln>Zwycięstwo nie zaliczone.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_661">
		<rus>Штраф за нарушение правил боя.</rus>
		<eng>A fine for breaking the rules.</eng>
		<ukr>Штраф за порушення правил бою.</ukr>
		<fra>Tu es condamné à une amende pour avoir enfreint les règles du combat.</fra>
		<pln>Kara za naruszenie reguł walki.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_711">
		<rus>Здорово, Чемпион! Решил таки снова заглянуть на Арену. Предлагаю, пока не нашёлся достойный претендент, чтобы отнять твой титул, не расслабляться и продолжать выступления. Как насчёт замочить пару-тройку мутантов? Коготь с парнями как раз свеженьких отловили.</rus>
		<eng>Hello there, Champion! Finally decided to pop by here? While nobody has risked to take your title, I offer you to extend your series of victories. How about sending a few monsters to their hell? Claw and his guys brought a few packs of mutants couple of hours ago.</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, Чемпіон! Вирішив таки знову заглянути на арену. Пропоную, поки не знайшовся гідний претендент щоб відняти твій титул, не розслаблятися і продовжувати виступи. Як щодо замочити пару-трійку мутантів? Кіготь з хлопцями якраз свіженьких відловили.</ukr>
		<fra>Salut à toi, champion ! Alors tu as décidé de revenir sur le devant de la scène, hein ? Je n'ai pas trouvé un adversaire capable de te voler ton titre, mais ne te détends pas encore. Pourquoi ne pas faire un combat aujourd'hui ? Que dis-tu d'un combat contre deux ou trois mutants ? J'en ai attrapé quelques uns pour toi.</fra>
		<pln>Witaj, Czempionie! Widzę, że znowu postanowiłeś zajrzeć na arenę. Proponuję, dopóki nie znajdzie się pretendent który chciałby odebrać ci tytuł, nie relaksować się zbytnio i nadal występować. Co powiesz na zaliczenie dwóch - trzech mutantów? Akurat świeże złowili.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_721">
		<rus>Меченый, слушай, у тебя появилась небольшая проблема. Враждующие группировки решили на время объединиться для борьбы с общим врагом.</rus>
		<eng>Marked One, listen, a new problem arose recently. Previously hostile factions decided to unite in front of a common enemy.</eng>
		<ukr>Мічений, слухай, у тебе з'явилася невелика проблема. Ворогуючі угруповання вирішили на час об'єднатися для боротьби із загальним ворогом.</ukr>
		<fra>Strelok,écoute. Tu as un problème. Les factions ont décidé de s'unir contre un ennemi commun.</fra>
		<pln>Naznaczony, posłuchaj, masz niewielki problem. Wrogie ugrupowania postanowiły tymczasowo zawrzeć rozejm dla walki ze wspólnym przeciwnikiem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_7211">
		<rus>И в чём проблема?</rus>
		<eng>And what is a deal with that?</eng>
		<ukr>І в чому проблема?</ukr>
		<fra>Et en quoi est-ce un problème?</fra>
		<pln>I w czym tu problem?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_72111">
		<rus>Только в том, что этот враг - ты. Попытайся вспомнить, сколько людей ты уже отправил с Арены на тот свет? Вот оставшиеся и отказываются сражаться с тобой... поодиночке.</rus>
		<eng>Oh its not a big deal. Just the fact that the enemy they united against happens to be - you. Remind yourself, how many people were sent to their ancestors by you? That's why the remaining are refusing to duel you ... alone.</eng>
		<ukr>Тільки в тому, що цей ворог - ти. Спробуй згадати, скільки людей ти вже відправив з арени на той світ? От ті що залишилися і відмовляються битися з тобою... поодинці.</ukr>
		<fra>Le problème est que l'ennemi dont je parle... C'est toi. Rappelle-toi combien de personnes tu as envoyé de l'autre côté ? Eh bien, les gars qui sont à ma gauche refusent de se battre contre toi... Seul.</fra>
		<pln>Jedynie w tym, że ten przeciwnik - to ty. Spróbuj sobie przypomnieć, ilu ludzi odprawiłeś z areny na tamten świat? Dlatego pozostali odmawiają walki z tobą... pojedynczo.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_731">
		<rus>Здорово, Меченый. Слышь, тут у нас в последнее время зверья набралось столько, что уже девать некуда. И как на зло, никто с ними воевать не хочет. Может ты возьмёшься?</rus>
		<eng>Yo, Marked One, we have a ton of excess animals here and nobody is willing to take care of this load of meat. How about a little hunt in our cage?</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, Мічений. Чуєш, тут у нас останнім часом звірини набралося стільки, що вже дівати нікуди. І, як на зло, ніхто з ними воювати не хоче. Може ти візьмешся?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé,Strelok!Nous avons reçu plein de mutants frais, nous manquons d'espace dans les enclos. Et comme fait exprès, personne ne veut les combattre. Peut-être que tu pourras libérer de l'espace pour nous?</fra>
		<pln>Witaj, Naznaczony. Słuchaj, ostatnimi czasy nazbierało się u nas tyle zwierząt, że już nie ma gdzie ich trzymać. I jak na złość, nikt z nimi walczyć nie chce. Może ty byś się za nie wziął?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_7311">
		<rus>Посмотрим.</rus>
		<eng>Will see.</eng>
		<ukr>Подивимося.</ukr>
		<fra>Nous verrons.</fra>
		<pln>Zobaczymy.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_73111">
		<rus>Подумай, дело ведь хорошее. И нам поможешь, и сам подзаработаешь.</rus>
		<eng>Think about it, the offer is quite profitable. You are helping us and at the same time enlarging your purse, if you still have one, heh.</eng>
		<ukr>Подумай, діло ж хороше. І нам допоможеш, і сам підзаробищ.</ukr>
		<fra>Il suffit de penser à ce que je viens de te dire. Le travail, c'est la santé. tu vas nous aider, pour divertir les spectateurs, et tu gagneras de l'argent en même temps.</fra>
		<pln>Pomyśl, to dobry interes. I nam pomożesz, i sam zarobisz.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_741">
		<rus>Здорово, Меченый. Арена снова открыта, давай побыстрее выбирай бой, сегодня у нас, как и всегда, очень насыщенная программа.</rus>
		<eng>Hey, Marked One. Arena is open once again, hurry and choose your battle, today, as always, we have a very rich program.</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, Мічений. Арена знову відкрита, давай швидше вибирай бій, сьогодні у нас, як і завжди, дуже насичена програма.</ukr>
		<fra>Hé,Strelok!.L'Arène est ouverte à nouveau, va vite t'inscrire pour un combat. On a un programme chargé aujourd'hui.</fra>
		<pln>Witaj, Naznaczony. Arena znowu otwarta, szybko wybierz walkę. U nas dzisiaj, jak zawsze, bardzo bogaty program.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_81">
		<rus>Приветствую, сталкер!</rus>
		<eng>Greetings, stalker!</eng>
		<ukr>Вітаю, сталкер!</ukr>
		<fra>Salut, Stalker!</fra>
		<pln>Pozdrowienia, stalkerze!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_start_91">
		<rus>Здорово, Меченый.</rus>
		<eng>Hey, Marked One.</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, Мічений.</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour, Strelok.</fra>
		<pln>Witaj, Naznaczony.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_0">
		<rus>У меня просьба.</rus>
		<eng>I have a favour I want to ask you.</eng>
		<ukr>У мене прохання.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai une requête.</fra>
		<pln>Mam prośbę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_1">
		<rus>Какая?</rus>
		<eng>What is it?</eng>
		<ukr>Яке?</ukr>
		<fra>Laquelle?</fra>
		<pln>Jaką?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_2">
		<rus>Включи меня опять в свой список рассылки.</rus>
		<eng>Put me back in your list of Arena notifications.</eng>
		<ukr>Включи мене знову в свій список розсилки.</ukr>
		<fra>Peux-tu me réinscrire sur ta liste pour que je reçoive à nouveau les messages de combats.</fra>
		<pln>Dopisz mnie na swoją listę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_21">
		<rus>Как скажешь.</rus>
		<eng>Done.</eng>
		<ukr>Як скажеш.</ukr>
		<fra>D'accord.</fra>
		<pln>Jak chcesz.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_3">
		<rus>Ты можешь больше не отсылать мне свои сообщения?</rus>
		<eng>Can you stop sending out your messages?</eng>
		<ukr>Ти можеш більше не відсилати мені свої повідомлення?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourrais-tu s'il te plait arrêter de m'envoyer ces messages?</fra>
		<pln>Czy możesz nie wysyłać mi więcej swoich wiadomości?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_31">
		<rus>Запросто, вычёркиваю твой ПДА из списка рассылки.</rus>
		<eng>No problem, your PDA is removed from notification list.</eng>
		<ukr>Запросто, викреслюю твій КПК зі списку розсилки.</ukr>
		<fra>Pas de problème. Je te supprime de la liste des contacts.</fra>
		<pln>Oczywiście, wykreślam twoje PDA z listy.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_4">
		<rus>Ты света на Арене побольше включить можешь?</rus>
		<eng>Can you turn more lights on in the Arena?</eng>
		<ukr>Ти світла на арені побільше ввімкнути можеш?</ukr>
		<fra>Peux-tu mettre un peu plus de lumière dans l'Arène?</fra>
		<pln>Nie mógłbyś dać więcej światła na Arenie?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_41">
		<rus>Попробую.</rus>
		<eng>I'll try.</eng>
		<ukr>Спробую.</ukr>
		<fra>Je vais voir ce que je peux faire.</fra>
		<pln>Spróbuję.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_5">
		<rus>Верни прежнее освещение.</rus>
		<eng>Return previous lighting.</eng>
		<ukr>Поверни колишнє освітлення.</ukr>
		<fra>S'il te plait, remets l'éclairage comme il était avant.</fra>
		<pln>Przywróć poprzednie oświetlenie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_51">
		<rus>То включи, то выключи. Ты уж определись.</rus>
		<eng>Can you make up your mind? Right now off and in five minutes on again?</eng>
		<ukr>То ввімкни, то вимкни. Ти вже визначся.</ukr>
		<fra>Allumer, éteindre... Décide-toi, hein .</fra>
		<pln>To włącz, to wyłącz. Może byś się zdecydował.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_6">
		<rus>УДАЛИТЬ МОД</rus>
		<eng>DELETE THE MODE</eng>
		<ukr>ВИДАЛИТИ МОД</ukr>
		<fra>MODE ELIMINATOIRE</fra>
		<pln>USUNĄĆ MODYFIKACJĘ</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_61">
		<rus>Уверен?</rus>
		<eng>Are you sure?</eng>
		<ukr>Упевнений?</ukr>
		<fra>Es-tu sûr?</fra>
		<pln>Jesteś pewny?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_611">
		<rus>Да.</rus>
		<eng>Yes.</eng>
		<ukr>Так.</ukr>
		<fra>Oui.</fra>
		<pln>Tak.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_612">
		<rus>Нет.</rus>
		<eng>No.</eng>
		<ukr>Ні.</ukr>
		<fra>Non.</fra>
		<pln>Nie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_9">
		<rus>Забудь.</rus>
		<eng>Forget about it.</eng>
		<ukr>Забудь.</ukr>
		<fra>Oublie ça.</fra>
		<pln>Zapomnij.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_quest">
		<rus>Ну, какие бои сегодня будут?</rus>
		<eng>So, what battles are there today?</eng>
		<ukr>Ну, які бої сьогодні будуть?</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, Quel genre de combats as-tu aujourd'hui?</fra>
		<pln>No, to jakie będą dzisiaj walki?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_closed">
		<rus>Пока никаких, подожди до открытия.</rus>
		<eng>None for now, wait until the opening.</eng>
		<ukr>Поки ніяких, почекай до відкриття.</ukr>
		<fra>Aucun à l'heure actuelle, attends l'ouverture.</fra>
		<pln>Na razie żadne, poczekaj do otwarcia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_done">
		<rus>На сегодня всё - желающих больше не осталось.</rus>
		<eng>That's it for today - no more volunteers to go down there.</eng>
		<ukr>На сьогодні все - охочих більше не залишилося.</ukr>
		<fra>C'est tout pour aujourd'hui. Pas beaucoup de gens veulent se battre aujourd'hui.</fra>
		<pln>Na dzisiaj koniec - nie ma już chętnych.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_select">
		<rus>Выбирай...</rus>
		<eng>Choose...</eng>
		<ukr>Вибирай...</ukr>
		<fra>Choisi...</fra>
		<pln>Wybieraj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_reject">
		<rus>Как-нибудь в другой раз.</rus>
		<eng>May be another time.</eng>
		<ukr>Якось іншим разом.</ukr>
		<fra>Peut-être une autre fois.</fra>
		<pln>Raczej innym razem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_group_reject">
		<rus>Я передумал.</rus>
		<eng>I changed my mind.</eng>
		<ukr>Я передумав.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai changé d'avis.</fra>
		<pln>Rozmyśliłem się.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_quest">
		<rus>Если ты абсолютно уверен в своих силах, могу предложить бои на время. Эти сражения, обычно, очень скоротечны и требуют немалого мастерства. Есть возможность получить премиальные или даже удвоить выигрыш, если уложишься в минимально отведённое время. Запомни одно железное правило - нельзя убивать противников после выключения таймера, за нарушение - штраф, равный сумме вознаграждения. Согласись, лучше не получить награду и остаться при своих, чем платить штраф, а живые бойцы мне ещё в других выступлениях пригодятся. Что скажешь, выставлять таймер?</rus>
		<eng>If you are absolutely confident in your skill, I can offer you timed battles. These engagements, usually, are very quick and require a lot of professionalism. There is a possibility of achieving an extra rewards as well as doubling the prise itself, if you make it to the chosen time. Memorize one important rule - you aren't allowed to kill opponents once the timer has stopped, in case that happens - you will be fined by the sum of the promised reward. Isn't it better to not gain an additional reward, but keep your personal savings rather than pay a fine, besides, living power can find its use in other performances. So what do say, timers on?</eng>
		<ukr>Якщо ти абсолютно впевнений у своїх силах, можу запропонувати бої на час. Ці битви, зазвичай, дуже швидкоплинні і вимагають чималої майстерності. Є можливість отримати преміальні або навіть подвоїти виграш, якщо укладешся в мінімально відведений час. Запам'ятай одне залізне правило - не можна вбивати супротивників після виключення таймера, за порушення - штраф, який дорівнює сумі винагороди. Погодься, краще не отримати нагороду і залишитися при своїх, ніж платити штраф, а живі бійці мені ще в інших виступах знадобляться. Що скажеш, виставляти таймер?</ukr>
		<fra>Si tu es absolument sûr de tes capacités, puis-je te suggérer un combat chronomètré ? Ces combats ne durent généralement pas longtemps et demande une certaine maîtrise dans l'art de tuer. Il y a une possibilité d'obtenir des bonus ou même de doubler tes gains si tu gagnes dans le temps le plus court possible. N'oublie pas la règle d'or, tu ne peux pas tuer ton adversaire après le temps défini. Si tu le fais, tu seras condamné à une amende du même montant que tes gains. Je pense que tu seras d'accord, il est préférable de garder son propre cul intact et sans le prix à payer de ce que tu es censé gagner. Et j'ai besoin d'autres candidats pour d'autres combats, afin que tu puisses m'aider en suivant cette règle. Eh bien, qu'en dis-tu ? Comment je règle le chrono?</fra>
		<pln>Jeżeli jesteś absolutnie pewien swoich sił, mogę zaproponować ci walkę na czas. Te walki są zazwyczaj bardzo szybkie i wymagają znacznych umiejętności. Istnieje możliwość otrzymania premii lub nawet podwojenia wygranej, jeżeli zmieścisz się w minimalnym czasie. Zapamiętaj jedną, żelazną regułę - nie wolno zabijać przeciwnika po upływie czasu, za naruszenie zasad - kara, równa wysokości wygranej. Chyba się zgodzisz, że lepiej nie otrzymać nagrody i zostać przy swoim, niż płacić karę, a żywi zawodnicy przydadzą mi się jeszcze w innych walkach. Co na to powiesz, włączać zegar?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_5">
		<rus>5 секунд.</rus>
		<eng>5 seconds.</eng>
		<ukr>5 секунд.</ukr>
		<fra>5 secondes.</fra>
		<pln>5 sekund.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_10">
		<rus>10 секунд.</rus>
		<eng>10 seconds.</eng>
		<ukr>10 секунд.</ukr>
		<fra>10 secondes.</fra>
		<pln>10 sekund.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_15">
		<rus>15 секунд.</rus>
		<eng>15 seconds.</eng>
		<ukr>15 секунд.</ukr>
		<fra>15 secondes.</fra>
		<pln>15 sekund.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_20">
		<rus>20 секунд.</rus>
		<eng>20 seconds.</eng>
		<ukr>20 секунд.</ukr>
		<fra>20 secondes.</fra>
		<pln>20 sekund.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_30">
		<rus>30 секунд.</rus>
		<eng>30 seconds.</eng>
		<ukr>30 секунд.</ukr>
		<fra>30 secondes.</fra>
		<pln>30 sekund.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_40">
		<rus>40 секунд.</rus>
		<eng>40 seconds.</eng>
		<ukr>40 секунд.</ukr>
		<fra>40 secondes.</fra>
		<pln>40 sekund.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_50">
		<rus>50 секунд.</rus>
		<eng>50 seconds.</eng>
		<ukr>50 секунд.</ukr>
		<fra>50 secondes.</fra>
		<pln>50 sekund.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_60">
		<rus>1 минута.</rus>
		<eng>1 minute.</eng>
		<ukr>1 хвилина.</ukr>
		<fra>1 minute.</fra>
		<pln>1 minuta.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_unlimited">
		<rus>Нет.</rus>
		<eng>No.</eng>
		<ukr>Ні.</ukr>
		<fra>Pas de chrono.</fra>
		<pln>Nie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_reject">
		<rus>Я передумал.</rus>
		<eng>I changed my mind.</eng>
		<ukr>Я передумав.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai changé d'avis.</fra>
		<pln>Rozmyśliłem się.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_quest">
		<rus>На кого ставишь?</rus>
		<eng>Who would you like to bet on?</eng>
		<ukr>На кого ставиш?</ukr>
		<fra>Sur qui vas-tu parier?</fra>
		<pln>Na kogo stawiasz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_vs">
		<rus>против</rus>
		<eng>against</eng>
		<ukr>проти</ukr>
		<fra>Contre</fra>
		<pln>Przeciw</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_reject">
		<rus>Ни на кого, передумал я.</rus>
		<eng>On no one, I changed my mind.</eng>
		<ukr>Ні на кого, передумав я.</ukr>
		<fra>Personne. J'ai changé d'avis.</fra>
		<pln>Na nikogo, rozmyśliłem się.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_money">
		<rus>Сколько?</rus>
		<eng>How much?</eng>
		<ukr>Скільки?</ukr>
		<fra>Combien?</fra>
		<pln>Ile?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_money_tm">
		<rus>руб.</rus>
		<eng>rub.</eng>
		<ukr>руб.</ukr>
		<fra>roubles.</fra>
		<pln>rub.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_money_empty">
		<rus>Как-нибудь в другой раз - в карманах пусто.</rus>
		<eng>May be some other time - I'm broke.</eng>
		<ukr>Якось іншим разом - в кишенях порожньо.</ukr>
		<fra>Peut-être une autre fois, mes poches sont vides.</fra>
		<pln>Może innym razem - pusto w kieszeni.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_money_reject">
		<rus>Да ну его.</rus>
		<eng>No, thanks.</eng>
		<ukr>Та ну його.</ukr>
		<fra>Non, je préfère ne pas miser.</fra>
		<pln>Nie, dziękuję.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_ready">
		<rus>Ставки сделаны - ставки больше не принимаются.</rus>
		<eng>Bets are done - new ones are no longer accepted.</eng>
		<ukr>Ставки зроблені - ставки більше не приймаються.</ukr>
		<fra>Tous les paris ont été enregistrés. Plus aucuns ne seront acceptés.</fra>
		<pln>Zakłady obstawione - koniec przyjmowania zakładów.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_go">
		<rus>Поехали.</rus>
		<eng>Let's go.</eng>
		<ukr>Поїхали.</ukr>
		<fra>C'est parti.</fra>
		<pln>To naprzód.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_extra">
		<rus>Тотализатор.</rus>
		<eng>Betting terminal.</eng>
		<ukr>Тоталізатор.</ukr>
		<fra>Totalisateur.</fra>
		<pln>Totalizator.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_extra_info">
		<rus>Хочешь заработать деньжат, не рискуя своим здоровьем, тогда ты обратился по адресу. Можешь делать ставки в двух дисциплинах: Бои с мутантами и Турнир группировок. Всё просто - говоришь мне на кого ставка, платишь наличными и топаешь смотреть бой, если ставка выиграла - получаешь назад деньги и проценты с выигрыша, если проиграла - по крайней мере удовольствие от просмотра боя тебе обеспечено. Что выбираешь?</rus>
		<eng>If you want to make money without risking your health, then you met the right person. You can make bets in two categories: Battles with monsters and a Faction Tournament. It's very simple - you tell me on whom you're betting, pay the cash and enjoy watching the match. If your team wins - you gain your money back with some percents, if it looses - at least you had fun watching the performance. What do you choose?</eng>
		<ukr>Хочеш заробити грошенят, не ризикуючи своїм здоров'ям, тоді ти звернувся за адресою. Можеш робити ставки у двох дисциплінах: Бої з мутантами і Турнір угруповань. Все просто - говориш мені на кого ставка, платиш готівкою і топаєш дивитися бій, якщо ставка виграла - отримуєш назад гроші і відсотки з виграшу, якщо програла - принаймні задоволення від перегляду бою тобі забезпечено. Що вибираєш?</ukr>
		<fra>Tu veux gagner de l'argent sans risquer ton propre cul ? Alors tu es à la bonne adresse. Tu peux placer des paris en deux modes: des combats contre des mutants et des tournois entre factions. C'est simple. Dis-moi sur qui tu paries ton argent, et tu n'as qu'à admirer le combat. Si le gars sur tu as parié gagne, alors tu récuperas ton argent avec des intérets. Tu l'as deviné, au moins tu vas assister à une bagarre intense avec la satisfaction de ne pas se faire tirer dessus. Quel est ton choix?</fra>
		<pln>Jeśli chcesz zarobić kasę, nie ryzykując swoim zdrowiem, to wybrałeś właściwy adres. Możesz obstawiać w dwóch dyscyplinach: Walka z mutantami i Turniej ugrupowań. To proste - mówisz mi na kogo stawiasz, płacisz gotówką i idziesz oglądać walkę. Jeśli trafiłeś - otrzymujesz swoją kasę z powrotem plus procent od wygranej, jeśli nie - w ostateczności masz frajdę z oglądania walki. Co wybierasz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_job_extra_reject">
		<rus>Я передумал.</rus>
		<eng>I changed my mind.</eng>
		<ukr>Я передумав.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai changé d'avis.</fra>
		<pln>Zmieniłem zdanie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_military">
		<rus>На военных.</rus>
		<eng>On the military.</eng>
		<ukr>На військових.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur les soldats.</fra>
		<pln>Na żołnierzy.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_military1">
		<rus>Военные</rus>
		<eng>Military</eng>
		<ukr>Військові</ukr>
		<fra>Les militaires</fra>
		<pln>Wojsko</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_military2">
		<rus>военных.</rus>
		<eng>soldiers.</eng>
		<ukr>військових.</ukr>
		<fra>Les Militaires.</fra>
		<pln>żołnierzy.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_killer">
		<rus>На наёмников.</rus>
		<eng>On mercenaries.</eng>
		<ukr>На найманців.</ukr>
		<fra>Les Mercenaires.</fra>
		<pln>Na najemników.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_killer1">
		<rus>Наёмники</rus>
		<eng>Mercenaries</eng>
		<ukr>Найманці</ukr>
		<fra>Mercenaires</fra>
		<pln>Najemnicy</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_killer2">
		<rus>наёмников.</rus>
		<eng>mercs.</eng>
		<ukr>найманців.</ukr>
		<fra>Mercenaires.</fra>
		<pln>najemników.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_freedom">
		<rus>На Свободу.</rus>
		<eng>On Freedom.</eng>
		<ukr>На Волю.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur la Liberté.</fra>
		<pln>Na Wolność.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_freedom1">
		<rus>Свободовцы</rus>
		<eng>Freedom squad</eng>
		<ukr>Волівці</ukr>
		<fra>Les gars de la Liberté</fra>
		<pln>Wolnościowcy</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_freedom2">
		<rus>свободовцев.</rus>
		<eng>freedom fighters.</eng>
		<ukr>волівців.</ukr>
		<fra>Les gars de la Liberté.</fra>
		<pln>wolnościowców.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_dolg">
		<rus>На Долг.</rus>
		<eng>On Duty.</eng>
		<ukr>На Долг.</ukr>
		<fra>Le Devoir.</fra>
		<pln>Na Powinność.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_dolg1">
		<rus>Долговцы</rus>
		<eng>Duty squad.</eng>
		<ukr>Долгівці</ukr>
		<fra>Les gars du Devoir</fra>
		<pln>Powinnościowcy</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_dolg2">
		<rus>долговцев.</rus>
		<eng>duty fighters.</eng>
		<ukr>долгівців.</ukr>
		<fra>äîëãîâöåâ.</fra>
		<pln>powinnościowców.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_neutral">
		<rus>На нейтралов.</rus>
		<eng>On the neutrals.</eng>
		<ukr>На нейтралів.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur les Solitaires.</fra>
		<pln>Na neutralnych.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_neutral1">
		<rus>Нейтралы</rus>
		<eng>Neutrals</eng>
		<ukr>Нейтрали</ukr>
		<fra>Les Solitaires</fra>
		<pln>Neutralni</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_neutral2">
		<rus>нейтралов.</rus>
		<eng>neutrals.</eng>
		<ukr>нейтралів.</ukr>
		<fra>Les Solitaires.</fra>
		<pln>neutralnych.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bandit">
		<rus>На бандитов.</rus>
		<eng>On the bandits.</eng>
		<ukr>На бандитів.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur les Bandits.</fra>
		<pln>Na bandytów.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bandit1">
		<rus>Бандиты</rus>
		<eng>Bandits</eng>
		<ukr>Бандити</ukr>
		<fra>Bandits</fra>
		<pln>Bandyci</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bandit2">
		<rus>бандитов.</rus>
		<eng>On the dogs.</eng>
		<ukr>бандитів.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur les chiens.</fra>
		<pln>bandytów.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_pseudodog">
		<rus>На собак.</rus>
		<eng>Dogs</eng>
		<ukr>На собак.</ukr>
		<fra>Chiens.</fra>
		<pln>Na psy.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_pseudodog1">
		<rus>Собаки</rus>
		<eng>Dogs</eng>
		<ukr>Собаки</ukr>
		<fra>Chiens</fra>
		<pln>Psy</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_pseudodog2">
		<rus>собак.</rus>
		<eng>dogs.</eng>
		<ukr>собак.</ukr>
		<fra>Chiens.</fra>
		<pln>psów.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_boar">
		<rus>На кабанов.</rus>
		<eng>On the boars.</eng>
		<ukr>На кабанів.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur les Sangliers.</fra>
		<pln>Na dziki.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_boar1">
		<rus>Кабаны</rus>
		<eng>Boars</eng>
		<ukr>Кабани</ukr>
		<fra>Sangliers</fra>
		<pln>Dziki</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_boar2">
		<rus>кабанов.</rus>
		<eng>boars.</eng>
		<ukr>кабанів.</ukr>
		<fra>Sangliers.</fra>
		<pln>dzików.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_snork">
		<rus>На снорков.</rus>
		<eng>On the snorks.</eng>
		<ukr>На снорків.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur les Snorks.</fra>
		<pln>Na snorki.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_snork1">
		<rus>Снорки</rus>
		<eng>Snorks</eng>
		<ukr>Снорки</ukr>
		<fra>Snorks</fra>
		<pln>Snorki</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_snork2">
		<rus>снорков.</rus>
		<eng>snorks.</eng>
		<ukr>снорків.</ukr>
		<fra>Snorks.</fra>
		<pln>snorków.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bloodsucker">
		<rus>На кровососа.</rus>
		<eng>On a bloodsucker.</eng>
		<ukr>На кровососа.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur les Sangsues.</fra>
		<pln>Na pijawkę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bloodsucker1">
		<rus>Кровосос</rus>
		<eng>Bloodsucker</eng>
		<ukr>Кровосос</ukr>
		<fra>Sangsues</fra>
		<pln>Pijawka</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bloodsucker2">
		<rus>кровососа.</rus>
		<eng>blooducker.</eng>
		<ukr>кровососа.</ukr>
		<fra>Sangsues.</fra>
		<pln>pijawki.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_zombie">
		<rus>На неупокоенных.</rus>
		<eng>On the undead.</eng>
		<ukr>На неупокоєнних.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur les Zombies.</fra>
		<pln>Na nieumarłych.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_zombie1">
		<rus>Зомби</rus>
		<eng>Zombie</eng>
		<ukr>Зомбі</ukr>
		<fra>Zombie</fra>
		<pln>Zombie</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_zombie2">
		<rus>зомби.</rus>
		<eng>zombie.</eng>
		<ukr>зомбі.</ukr>
		<fra>Zombie.</fra>
		<pln>zombie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_chimera">
		<rus>На химеру.</rus>
		<eng>On a chimera.</eng>
		<ukr>На химеру.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur la Chimère.</fra>
		<pln>Na chimerę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_chimera1">
		<rus>Химера</rus>
		<eng>Chimera</eng>
		<ukr>Химера</ukr>
		<fra>Chimère</fra>
		<pln>Chimera</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_chimera2">
		<rus>химеры.</rus>
		<eng>chimera.</eng>
		<ukr>химери.</ukr>
		<fra>Chimère.</fra>
		<pln>chimery.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_burer">
		<rus>На бюрера.</rus>
		<eng>On a burer.</eng>
		<ukr>На бюрера.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur le Nain.</fra>
		<pln>Na burera.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_burer1">
		<rus>Бюрер</rus>
		<eng>Burer</eng>
		<ukr>Бюрер</ukr>
		<fra>Nain</fra>
		<pln>Burer</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_burer2">
		<rus>бюрера.</rus>
		<eng>burer.</eng>
		<ukr>бюрера.</ukr>
		<fra>Nain.</fra>
		<pln>burera.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_gigant">
		<rus>На псевдогиганта.</rus>
		<eng>On a pseudogiant.</eng>
		<ukr>На псевдогіганта.</ukr>
		<fra>Sur le Pseudo-géant.</fra>
		<pln>Na pseudogiganta.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_gigant1">
		<rus>Псевдогигант</rus>
		<eng>Pseudogiant</eng>
		<ukr>Псевдогігант</ukr>
		<fra>Pseudo-géant</fra>
		<pln>Pseudogigant</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_team_gigant2">
		<rus>псевдогиганта.</rus>
		<eng>pseudogiant.</eng>
		<ukr>псевдогіганта.</ukr>
		<fra>Pseudo-géant.</fra>
		<pln>pseudogiganta.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants">
		<rus>Живодёрня.</rus>
		<eng>Slaughter.</eng>
		<ukr>Шкуродерня.</ukr>
		<fra>Mutants.</fra>
		<pln>Rzeźnia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_info">
		<rus>Наконец-то Долг возобновил поставки мутантов на Арену, попадаются даже очень редкие экземпляры. Выбирай, кто станет твоей новой жертвой?</rus>
		<eng>Finally the Duty reestablished a supply of monsters on the Arena, sometimes you can encounter a few rare species. Choose your next victim.</eng>
		<ukr>Нарешті Долг відновив постачання мутантів на арену, попадаються навіть дуже рідкісні екземпляри. Вибирай, хто стане твоєю новою жертвою?</ukr>
		<fra>Enfin ! Le Devoir a offert du nouveau pour l'arène, des mutants vivants. Et certains sont même rares. Choisi. Qui sera ta prochaine victime?</fra>
		<pln>W końcu Powinność wznowiła dostawy mutantów na Arenę, zdarzają się nawet bardzo rzadkie egzemplarze. Wybieraj, kto będzie twoją nową ofiarą?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_military">
		<rus>Бой с военными.</rus>
		<eng>Battle against military soldiers.</eng>
		<ukr>Бій з військовими.</ukr>
		<fra>Combat avec les militaires.</fra>
		<pln>Walka z żołnierzami.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_military_info">
		<rus>Казалось бы, какого они делают в Баре, но благодаря обширным связям с командованием военных, долговцы могут позволить себе даже такое. В профессионализме военных сомневаться не приходится, у всех за плечами немалый боевой опыт, полученный ещё до возникновения Зоны и отточенный в регулярных рейдах по зачистке территорий. Вооружены лучшими отечественными стволами.</rus>
		<eng>On a first thought, why are they even staying in the Bar, but thanks to our wide connections with military, Duty organizers can afford to have them perform in the Arena. Nobody can doubt their professionalism, all of them are well-trained soldiers, with a solid experience from the times when Zone didn't even exist and skills sharpened in raids. Equipped with the best domestic weapons.</eng>
		<ukr>Здавалося б, якого вони роблять в Барі, але завдяки великим зв'язкам з командуванням військових, долгівці можуть дозволити собі навіть таке. У професіоналізмі військових сумніватися не доводиться, у всіх за плечима чималий бойовий досвід, отриманий ще до виникнення зони і відточений в регулярних рейдах по зачистці територій. Озброєні кращими вітчизняними стволами.</ukr>
		<fra>La première chose qui vient à l'esprit est : Quel enfer sont ces gars-là, vu ce qu'ils ont fait dans le bar! Pourtant, grâce à leurs nombreuses connexions, les gars du Devoir peuvent se le permettre. Il n'y a pas de doutes quant au professionnalisme de ces soldats. Ils ont tous beaucoup d'expérience derrière eux, ce qui ils ont obtenu avant même que la zone devienne ce qu'elle est. Certains de ces gars-la ont fait la guerre d'Afghanistan, la Georgie et la Tchetchenie, et ils ont même fait un raid de quelques années dans la zone, alors qu'ils sont encore vivants. Ils ont les meilleures armes que leur gouvernement russe peut produire.</fra>
		<pln>Wydawałoby się, że pełną swobodę mają tylko w Barze, ale dzięki szerokim powiązaniom z dowództwem wojskowym, Powinnościowcy mogą sobie pozwolić nawet na to. Nie ma żadnych wątpliwości co do profesjonalizmu żołnierzy, wszyscy mają niemałe doświadczenie bojowe, zdobyte jeszcze przed powstaniem Zony i systematycznie pogłębiane w regularnych rajdach oczyszczających okoliczne terytoria. Wyposażeni w najlepszą krajową broń.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_killer">
		<rus>Бой с наёмниками.</rus>
		<eng>Battle against mercenaries.</eng>
		<ukr>Бій з найманцями.</ukr>
		<fra>Combat avec des Mercenaires.</fra>
		<pln>Walka z najemnikami.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_killer_info">
		<rus>Наёмники - хорошо организованная военная группировка с отличным импортным вооружением. По слухам, выполняют заказы иностранных правительств. Многие местные их недолюбливают, а у вояк они, вообще как кость в горле, но боевая мощь данной организации заставляет всех считаться с их присутствием в Зоне и даже налаживать контакты.</rus>
		<eng>Mercenaries are a well-organized faction with brand new Western weapons. According to some sources, they are executing orders from foreign governments. Not only they are a bane for Ukranian Armu, but many other factions dislike them as well. Although, their combat power and influence forces everyone to put up with mercs...sometimes even become their allies.</eng>
		<ukr>Найманці - добре організоване військове угруповання з відмінним імпортним озброєнням. За чутками, виконують замовлення іноземних урядів. Багато місцевих їх недолюблюють, а у вояк вони, взагалі як кістка в горлі, але бойова міць даної організації змушує всіх рахуватися з їх присутністю в зоні і навіть налагоджувати контакти.</ukr>
		<fra>Les Mercenaires sont un groupe trés organisé, paramilitaire de nombreux entrepreneurs prives. Ils portent des armes importées, de sorte qu'ils ne sont pas a court de liquidités. La rumeur dit qu'ils travaillent pour des intérêts étrangers et les gouvernements, en plus du russe, l'ukrainien, et peut-être même les clients géorgiens. Je les appelle un effet secondaire du gouvernement de l'Ukraine parce qu'ils ont fait tant d'efforts pour adhérer à l'OTAN. Beaucoup d'habitants essayent de rester aussi loin d'eux, car ils peuvent, mais a l'armee, ils sont comme un os pointu dans la gorge. Ils donnent l'mercenaires la plus haute priorite s'ils en place, quel type de me respecter les soldats. La puissance de feu des mercenaires est difficile d'ignorer, ce qui explique pourquoi certains groupes ont meme des contacts entre eux.</fra>
		<pln>Najemnicy - dobrze zorganizowane ugrupowanie paramilitarne, wyposażone w doskonałą broń z importu. Chodzą słuchy, że są wykonawcami zleceń zagranicznych rządów. Wielu miejscowych ich nie znosi, a armii stoją kością w gardle. Jednakże siła zbrojna tej organizacji zmusza wszystkich do liczenia się z ich obecnością w Zonie, a nawet do nawiązywania kontaktów.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_freedom">
		<rus>Бой со свободовцами.</rus>
		<eng>Battle against Freedom</eng>
		<ukr>Бій з волівцями.</ukr>
		<fra>Combat avec la Liberté.</fra>
		<pln>Walka z wolnościowcami.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_freedom_info">
		<rus>Свободовцы - непримиримые враги Долга, на время сражений пользуются неприкосновенностью на территории Бара. В их рядах встречается много перебежчиков из Долга, отказавшихся в своё время от идеологии "последней надежды человечества", поэтому и отношения между группировками, мягко говоря, напряжённые. Хотя в Долге и считают, что свободовцы отмороженные анархисты, тем не менее последние не уступают в силе первым, а их оружие и экипировка так же на высоте.</rus>
		<eng>Freedom - mortal enemy of Duty; however, during the performances they are completely untouchable on the Bar's territory. Quite a few of their members are ex-soldiers of Duty, who refused to accept ideology of "the last hope for humanity", that's why the relationship between these two factions are extremely intense. Even though in the Duty, they think that Freedom fighters are madman anarchists, guys with a wolf on a shoulder are equal or even better. Their equipment is quite dominant as well.</eng>
		<ukr>Волівці - непримиренні вороги Долгу, на час битв користуються недоторканністю на території Бара. У їхніх лавах зустрічається багато перебіжчиків з Долгу, що відмовилися у свій час від ідеології "останньої надії людства", тому й стосунки між угрупованнями, м'яко кажучи, напружені. Хоча у Долгу і вважають, що волівці відморожені анархісти, проте останні не поступаються в силі першим, а їхня зброю і екіпірування так само на висоті.</ukr>
		<fra>les gars de la Liberté sont les ennemis jurés du Devoir. Ils ont beaucoup d'anciens du Devoir dans leurs rangs, ceux qui ont été rejetés, l'idéologie de cette faction: Nous sommes le dernier espoir de l'humanité !. C'est une des raisons pour lesquelles les relations entre les deux factions sont très tendues. Même si Le Devoir considère la Liberté d'etre rien de plus qu'un troupeau d'anarchistes de l'age de pierres, cela n'a pas empêché le Devoir d'engager un dur combat contre la Liberté. La Liberté est certainement plus organisée que le Devoir, et leurs armes et armures ne sont pas si mauvais que ça. Le Devoir a perdu beaucoup de leurs meilleurs combattants qui ont désertés pour la Liberté, de sorte que leur expérience du combat soit enfin respectée. A l'heure actuelle, il y a un cessez-le-feu entre les deux factions, mais il est assez fragile.</fra>
		<pln>Wolnościowcy - nieubłagani wrogowie Powinności, na czas walk korzystają z nietykalności na terenie Baru. W ich szeregach spotyka się wielu uciekinierów z Powinności, którzy w swoim czasie odrzucili ideologię "ostatniej nadziei ludzkości", dlatego też stosunki pomiędzy frakcjami są, łagodnie mówiąc, napięte. Chociaż w Powinności uważają, że wolnościowcy to jeden w drugiego anarchiści, ci ostatni nie ustępują w sile pierwszym, a ich broń i wyposażenie są również na wysokim poziomie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_dolg">
		<rus>Бой с долговцами.</rus>
		<eng>Battle against Duty.</eng>
		<ukr>Бій з Долгівцями.</ukr>
		<fra>Combat avec Le Devoir.</fra>
		<pln>Walka z powinnościowcami.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_dolg_info">
		<rus>Группировка Долг - наши самопровозглашённые менты. Именно благодаря их командованию, стали проводиться смертельные бои на Арене. Члены группировки постоянно принимают участие в сражениях, оттачивая свои боевые навыки, для подготовки к рейдам в Зону. Вооружены как государственные спецподразделения, образцами отечественного ВПК.</rus>
		<eng>Duty - our self-imposed police. Only as a result of their initiative. we began conducting deadly fights on the Arena. Members of the faction are constantly participate in the battles, sharpening their combat skills, as a preparation for raids in the depths of the Zone. They are equipped similarly to government special forces, with modern domestic weapons.</eng>
		<ukr>Угрупування Долг - наші самопроголошені менти. Саме завдяки їх командуванню стали проводитися смертельні бої на арені. Члени угруповання постійно беруть участь у битвах, відточуючи свої бойові навички, для підготовки до рейдів в зону. Озброєні як державні спецпідрозділи, зразками вітчизняного ВПК.</ukr>
		<fra>La faction de service est notre force de police auto-declarée. C'est grâce à eux que nous avons combatu à mort dans notre humble sphère, en plus de capturer des mutants. Les membres de cette faction participent régulièrement à des combats d'arène pour perfectionner leurs compétences et la pratique pour les futurs raids dans le fin fond de la Zone. Ils sont armés de la même façon que les Spetsnaz de notre gouvernement, avec les meilleurs armes à feu diponibles du Pacte de Varsovie.</fra>
		<pln>Ugrupowanie "Powinność" - nasza samozwańcza policja. To dzięki ich przewodnictwu rozpoczęły się śmiertelne boje na Arenie. Członkowie ugrupowania stale biorą udział w starciach, szlifując swoje umiejętności bojowe, w ramach przygotowań do rajdów w Zonę. Wyposażeni tak, jak rządowe specoddziały, w wyroby krajowego przemysłu zbrojeniowego.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_neutral">
		<rus>Бой с нейтралами.</rus>
		<eng>Battle against neutrals.</eng>
		<ukr>Бій з нейтралами.</ukr>
		<fra>Combat avec les Solitaires.</fra>
		<pln>Walka z neutrałami.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_neutral_info">
		<rus>Обычные сталкеры одиночки, не принадлежащие ни к одной из группировок в Зоне. Возможно, среди них встретятся те, кто перешёл тебе дорогу - будет хороший повод разделаться с конкурентами. Вооружение различное - импортное и отечественное, но слабых стволов нет ни у кого.</rus>
		<eng>Typical independant stalkers, which do not belong to a single faction in the Zone. Their is a chance that you might meet somebody who has crossed your path - you will have an ideal opportunity to pay them back using lead currency. Their equipment, however, is quite diverse, but no nobody is lacking power in their guns.</eng>
		<ukr>Звичайні сталкери одинаки, які не належать ні до одного з угруповань в зоні. Можливо, серед них зустрінуться ті, хто перейшов тобі дорогу - буде хороший привід розправитися з конкурентами. Озброєння різне - імпортне та вітчизняне, але слабких стволів немає ні у кого.</ukr>
		<fra>Les solitaires d'habitude, sont ceux qui sont rester a l'écart ou n'ont pas encore rejoint une faction. Tu peux voir des visages familiers parmi eux, reconnaître même les gars avec qui tu as pu partager une bouteille il y a quelques semaines. C'est une bonne façon de te faire des ennemis ou d'éclaircir le rang de concurrents. Ils sont armés d'une myriade d'armes à feu. Canons du Pacte Varsovie, fusils importés, mais je n'ai pas pu encore voir toutes leurs armes, ce qui me rend fou.</fra>
		<pln>Zwykli stalkerzy samotnicy, nie należący do żadnego z ugrupowań w Zonie. Być może są wśród nich ci, którzy weszli ci w drogę - będziesz miał dobrą okazję wyrównać rachunki z konkurentami. Uzbrojenie różnorodne, zagraniczne i krajowe, ale słabych typów raczej się nie spodziewaj.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_bandit">
		<rus>Бой с бандитами.</rus>
		<eng>Battle against bandits.</eng>
		<ukr>Бій з бандитами.</ukr>
		<fra>Combat avec des Bandits.</fra>
		<pln>Walka z bandytami.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_bandit_info">
		<rus>Очередная партия смертников из Тёмной Долины. Оружие им дали казённое - ареновское, потому не думай, что они в тебя из ржавых берданок палить будут.</rus>
		<eng>Another portion of deadmen from the Dark Valley. We gave them some weapons from the Arena's arsenal...Don't think that all they can do - is finger you.</eng>
		<ukr>Чергова партія смертників з Темної долини. Зброю їм дали казенну - аренівську, тому не думай, що вони в тебе з іржавих берданок палити будуть.</ukr>
		<fra>Le parti des condamnés à mort capturés dans la Vallée obscure. Ils ont eu des canons loués, des armes d'arène, donc ne pense pas un seul instant qu'ils vont te tirer dessus avec un canon double rouillé et avec un Makarov qu'ils ont pris à des flics morts, ils tuent en 75 secondes.</fra>
		<pln>Kolejna partia samobójców z Doliny Mroku. Broń dostali uczciwą - arenową, dlatego nie myśl, że będą do ciebie strzelać z zardzewiałych dwururek.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_special">
		<rus>Бой со сборной Зоны.</rus>
		<eng>Battle against the team of the Zone.</eng>
		<ukr>Бій зі збірною Зони.</ukr>
		<fra>Combat contre l'équipe de la Zone.</fra>
		<pln>Walka z drużyną Zony.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_special_info">
		<rus>В команде представлены все группировки Зоны. Общая численность несколько превышает обычную. И все они серьёзно настроены отомстить тебе за гибель соклановцев на Арене.</rus>
		<eng>This is a combination of men from all sorts of factions with a total number slightly higher than usual. Despite their diversity, trust me - the can't wait to avenge the death of their clanmates</eng>
		<ukr>У команді представлені всі угруповання Зони. Загальна чисельність дещо перевищує звичайну. І всі вони серйозно налаштовані помститися тобі за загибель співкланівців на арені.</ukr>
		<fra>Chaque faction est représentée dans cette équipe. Le nombre des opposants est légèrement plus élevé que d'habitude, et ils sont tous là pour te crever et te faire payer pour tous les camarades que tu as tué.</fra>
		<pln>W grupie znajdują się przedstawiciele wszystkich ugrupowań Zony. Łączna liczebność jest nieco wyższa, niż zwykle. I wszyscy są zdecydowani zemścić się na tobie za śmierć kolegów z klanu na arenie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_special_1">
		<rus>Я понял.</rus>
		<eng>I understood.</eng>
		<ukr>Я зрозумів.</ukr>
		<fra>Je le prends.</fra>
		<pln>Zrozumiałem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_special_warning">
		<rus>Шансов вернуться живым у тебя немного. Ты уверен, что хочешь принять их вызов? Лучше пораскинь мозгами сейчас, чем потом на Арене.</rus>
		<eng>Odds are - you won't survive. Are you sure you want to respond to the callout? Using your brains to think now is a bit better than wiping Arena's floor with them later.</eng>
		<ukr>Шансів повернутися живим у тебе мало. Ти впевнений, що хочеш прийняти їх виклик? Краще розкинь мізками зараз, ніж потім на арені.</ukr>
		<fra>Tu n'as pas beaucoup de chances de revenir. Es-tu sur de vouloir accepter leur défi? Utilise ton cerveau pour penser maintenant est un peu mieux que d’essuyer le sol d’Arena plus tard.</fra>
		<pln>Szans na przeżycie masz niewiele, jesteś pewien, że chcesz przyjąć ich wyzwanie? Lepiej użyć mózgu teraz, niż zostawić go na Arenie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_special_continue">
		<rus>Бывало и похуже. Объявляй бой.</rus>
		<eng>I've been in the worse situations. Announce the battle.</eng>
		<ukr>Бувало й гірше. Оголошуй бій.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai vécu bien pire. Annonce le combat.</fra>
		<pln>Bywało gorzej. Ogłaszaj walkę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_stakes">
		<rus>Бои с мутантами.</rus>
		<eng>Battle with monsters.</eng>
		<ukr>Бої з мутантами.</ukr>
		<fra>Combat avec des mutants.</fra>
		<pln>Walka z mutantami.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_stakes_info">
		<rus>Здесь сталкеры разных группировок выбивают дух из мутантов или наоборот, в общем как получится. Какой бой посмотрим?</rus>
		<eng>Here stalkers from different factions slaughter or become slaughtered by monsters. Which battle would you like to watch?</eng>
		<ukr>Тут сталкери різних угруповань вибивають дух з мутантів або навпаки, в загальному як вийде. Який бій подивимося?</ukr>
		<fra>Voici les différentes factions de Stalkers tués par deux mutants, ou vice-versa, dépend de la chance qu'ils ont eu. Quel combat nous montres-tu aujourd'hui?</fra>
		<pln>Tu stalkerzy z różnych ugrupowań wydzierają życie z mutantów, albo na odwrót, zależy jak wyjdzie Jaką walkę obejrzymy?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_turnament">
		<rus>Турнир группировок.</rus>
		<eng>Faction Tournament.</eng>
		<ukr>Турнір угруповань.</ukr>
		<fra>Faction tournoi.</fra>
		<pln>Turniej ugrupowań.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_turnament_info">
		<rus>Турнир престижа между группировками, каждая пытается продемонстрировать своё превосходство над другими. Также здесь зачастую разрешаются спорные вопросы с минимальными потерями. Правила просты: есть несколько команд, они будут убивать друг друга, пока не останется одна - сильнейшая. Приступим?</rus>
		<eng>Tournament of reputation between the factions, each one is attempting to demonstrate their superiority. Quite often they like to solve their disagreements here without many casualties. Rules are simple: there is a few teams, they will be killing each other, until only one is left. Let's try this?</eng>
		<ukr>Турнір престижу між угрупованнями, кожне намагається продемонструвати свою перевагу над іншими. Також тут часто вирішуються спірні питання з мінімальними втратами. Правила прості: є кілька команд, вони будуть вбивати один одного, поки не залишиться одна - найсильніша. Приступимо?</ukr>
		<fra>Il s'agit d'un tournoi entre les factions. Chacune essaie de prouver qu'ils sont meilleurs que les autres. Les petits conflits et les désaccords entre eux sont également résolus ici avec un minimum de pertes. Les règles sont simples : il y a quelques équipes, ils se tuent les uns les autres jusqu'à ce qu'il en reste un seul, le plus fort, puis il est laissé au repos. Vas-tu commencer?</fra>
		<pln>Rywalizacja o prestiż między ugrupowaniami, gdzie każde próbuje wykazać swoją wyższość nad pozostałymi. Tutaj także często rozsądza się spory z minimalnymi stratami. Zasady są proste: zaczyna kilka oddziałów, które zabijają się wzajemnie, aż zostanie jeden - najsilniejszy. Zaczniemy?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_dog">
		<rus>Собаки.</rus>
		<eng>Dogs.</eng>
		<ukr>Собаки.</ukr>
		<fra>Chiens.</fra>
		<pln>Psy.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_boar">
		<rus>Кабаны.</rus>
		<eng>Boars.</eng>
		<ukr>Кабани.</ukr>
		<fra>Sangliers.</fra>
		<pln>Dziki.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_tushkano">
		<rus>Тушканы.</rus>
		<eng>Tushkanoes.</eng>
		<ukr>Тушкани.</ukr>
		<fra>Gerboises.</fra>
		<pln>Tuszkany.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_snork">
		<rus>Снорки.</rus>
		<eng>Snorks.</eng>
		<ukr>Снорки.</ukr>
		<fra>Snorks.</fra>
		<pln>Snorki.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_bloodsucker">
		<rus>Кровосос.</rus>
		<eng>Bloodsucker.</eng>
		<ukr>Кровосос.</ukr>
		<fra>Sangsues.</fra>
		<pln>Pijawka.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_zombie">
		<rus>Контролёр и зомби.</rus>
		<eng>Controller and zombie.</eng>
		<ukr>Контролер і зомбі.</ukr>
		<fra>Contrôleur et Zombie.</fra>
		<pln>Kontroler i zombie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_chimera">
		<rus>Химера.</rus>
		<eng>Chimera.</eng>
		<ukr>Химера.</ukr>
		<fra>Chimère.</fra>
		<pln>Chimera.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_burer">
		<rus>Бюрер.</rus>
		<eng>Burer.</eng>
		<ukr>Бюрер.</ukr>
		<fra>Burer.</fra>
		<pln>Burer.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_gigant">
		<rus>Псевдогигант.</rus>
		<eng>Pseudogiant.</eng>
		<ukr>Псевдогігант.</ukr>
		<fra>Pseudo-géant.</fra>
		<pln>Pseudogigant.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_fight_1on1">
		<rus>Один на один.</rus>
		<eng>One on one.</eng>
		<ukr>Один на один.</ukr>
		<fra>Un contre un.</fra>
		<pln>Jeden na jednego.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_fight_1on2">
		<rus>Один против двоих.</rus>
		<eng>One against two.</eng>
		<ukr>Один проти двох.</ukr>
		<fra>Un contre deux.</fra>
		<pln>Jeden na dwóch.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_fight_1on3">
		<rus>Один против троих.</rus>
		<eng>One against three.</eng>
		<ukr>Один проти трьох.</ukr>
		<fra>Un contre trois.</fra>
		<pln>Jeden na trzech.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_fight_1on6">
		<rus>Кровавая баня.</rus>
		<eng>Blood bath.</eng>
		<ukr>Кривава баня.</ukr>
		<fra>Un contre six. Un bain de sang, en d'autres termes...</fra>
		<pln>Krwawa łaźnia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_done">
		<rus>Арена закрывается на профилактику. Сегодня боёв больше не будет.</rus>
		<eng>Arena is closing for maintenance. No more battles for today.</eng>
		<ukr>Арена закривається на профілактику. Сьогодні боїв більше не буде.</ukr>
		<fra>L'arène va maintenant fermer pour le nettoyage et l'entretien. Plus aucun combat aujourd'hui.</fra>
		<pln>Arena zamknięta do konserwacji. Dziś już walk nie będzie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_close">
		<rus>Время сражений вышло, Арена закрыта на профилактику. Кто не успел, тот опоздал.</rus>
		<eng>Time for fights ran out, Arena is closed for maintenance. Whoever didn't make it, too bad.</eng>
		<ukr>Час бою вийшов, арена закрита на профілактику. Хто не встиг, той запізнився.</ukr>
		<fra>Le temps des combats est terminé. Celui qui n'a pas pu arriver à temps, tant pis.</fra>
		<pln>Czas walk upłynął, arena zamknięta do konserwacji. Kto nie zdążył, ten się spóźnił.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_open">
		<rus>Итак, Арена снова открыта! Кто первый желает сдать свой литр крови?</rus>
		<eng>Arena is open once again! Who volunteers to be the first one to donate his litre of blood?</eng>
		<ukr>Отже, арена знову відкрита! Хто перший бажає здати свій літр крові?</ukr>
		<fra>Et maintenant l'Arène ouvre à nouveau! Qui veut être le premier à verser le sang?</fra>
		<pln>Arena znowu otwarta! Kto pierwszy chce oddać swój litr krwi?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_3h">
		<rus>Всем желающим принять участие в сражениях на Арене срочно прибыть в Бар. Первый бой состоится уже через 3 часа.</rus>
		<eng>Everyone who wishes to participate in the Arena, start moving toward the Bar. First battle starts off in 3 hours.</eng>
		<ukr>Всім бажаючим взяти участь у боях на арені терміново прибути в бар. Перший бій відбудеться вже через 3 години.</ukr>
		<fra>Quiconque est prêt à participer à un combat dans l'arène, doit venir au Bar immédiatement. Le premier combat commence dans trois heures.</fra>
		<pln>Wszyscy chętni do wzięcia udziału w walkach na Arenie, powinni natychmiast przyjść do Baru. Pierwsza walka odbędzie się za 3 godziny.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_6h">
		<rus>До открытия Арены осталось 6 часов.</rus>
		<eng>6 hours until the opening of the arena.</eng>
		<ukr>До відкриття арени залишилося 6 годин.</ukr>
		<fra>Six heures jusqu'à l'ouverture de l'Arène.</fra>
		<pln>Do otwarcia Areny zostało 6 godzin.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_12h">
		<rus>До открытия Арены осталось 12 часов.</rus>
		<eng>12 hours until the opening of the arena.</eng>
		<ukr>До відкриття арени залишилося 12 годин.</ukr>
		<fra>Douze heures jusqu'à l'ouverture de l'Arène.</fra>
		<pln>Do otwarcia Areny zostało 12 godzin.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_24h">
		<rus>Напоминаю всем, что бои на Арене возобновятся ровно через 24 часа.</rus>
		<eng>Quick reminder, Arena reopens exactly in 24 hours.</eng>
		<ukr>Нагадую всім, що бої на арені поновляться рівно через 24 години.</ukr>
		<fra>Un rappel à tous : les combats reprendront dans l'Arène dans 24 heures exactement.</fra>
		<pln>Przypominam wszystkim, że walki na arenie zostaną wznowione dokładnie za 24 godziny.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_48h">
		<rus>Арена откроется через 48 часов, набор участников продолжается.</rus>
		<eng>Arena starts off in 48 hours, volunteers are still required.</eng>
		<ukr>Арена відкриється через 48 годин, набір учасників триває.</ukr>
		<fra>L'Arène rouvrira ses portes dans 48 heures.</fra>
		<pln>Arena otworzy się za 48 godzin, trwa nabór uczestników.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_72h">
		<rus>Предполагаемое время открытия Арены - трое суток.</rus>
		<eng>Approximate opening of the Arena - three days.</eng>
		<ukr>Передбачуваний час відкриття арени - три доби.</ukr>
		<fra>L'Arène rouvrira ses portes dans plus ou moins 3 jours.</fra>
		<pln>Szacowany czas otwarcia Areny - trzy doby.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_barman">
		<rus>Бармен</rus>
		<eng>Barman</eng>
		<ukr>Бармен</ukr>
		<fra>Barman</fra>
		<pln>Barman</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_admin">
		<rus>Администратор Арены</rus>
		<eng>Administrator of the Arena</eng>
		<ukr>Адміністратор арени</ukr>
		<fra>Administrateur de l'Arène</fra>
		<pln>Administrator Areny</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_arny_dead">
		<rus>Мужики, какая-то сволочь прикончила Арни!!! Если кто найдёт эту скотину - пристрелите на месте. Вознаграждение гарантирую. На данный момент Арена закрывается на неопределённое время, следите за новостями.</rus>
		<eng>Guys, some bastard murdered Arnie!!! If somebody finds this wanker - shoot him on the spot. Reward is guaranteed. For now, Arena is closed for indefinite amount of time, keep up with the upcoming news.</eng>
		<ukr>Мужики, якась сволота прикінчила Арні! Якщо хто знайде цю скотину - пристреліть на місці. Винагороду гарантую. На даний момент арена закривається на невизначений час, стежте за новинами.</ukr>
		<fra>Les gars ! Un dingue a tué Arnie ! Si quelqu'un trouve cette espèce de salopard,s'il vous plait, abattez-le sur place. Récompense assurée. L'Arène est maintenant fermée pour une période de temps indéfini, prêter donc attention aux annonces.</fra>
		<pln>Ludzie, jakiś sukinsyn wykończył Arniego!!! Jeśli ktoś znajdzie tego gnoja - niech go wykończy na miejscu. Gwarantuję nagrodę. Od tej chwili arena zamknięta  na czas nieokreślony, uważajcie na wiadomości.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_restore">
		<rus>Нашёлся новый администратор, работа Арены будет скоро восстановлена.</rus>
		<eng>A new administrator was found, battles on the Arena will return shortly.</eng>
		<ukr>Знайшовся новий адміністратор, робота арени буде скоро відновлена.</ukr>
		<fra>Nous sommes heureux d'annoncer que nous avons trouvé un nouvel administrateur pour l'Arène. L'Arène est de nouveau ouverte.</fra>
		<pln>Znaleziono nowego administratora, działanie Areny będzie wkrótce przywrócone.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_barm_1">
		<rus>Ну что за скотство, опять какая-то мразь завалила администратора Арены! Кто-нибудь, наконец, остановит это бешеное животное?</rus>
		<eng>What's up with this crap, some bastard killed Arena's administrator again! Somebody, please, finish this beast off!!!</eng>
		<ukr>Ну що за скотство, знову якась мерзота завалила адміністратора арени! Хто-небудь, нарешті, зупинить цю скажена тварину?</ukr>
		<fra>Mais qu'est-ce que c'est ?! Des connards ont tué l'administrateur de l'Arène ... Encore ! Quelqu'un peut-il s'il vous plait arrêter ces tarrés?</fra>
		<pln>Co za kurestwo, znowu jakiś sukinsyn załatwił administratora Areny! Czy ktoś w końcu powstrzyma to wściekłe bydlę?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_barm_2">
		<rus>Эй, ты - урод, если я узнаю твоё имя... лучше застрелись сам. Не жди, когда за тобой придут мои парни - они тебя будут долго мучить.</rus>
		<eng>Hey, you - faggot, if your name becomes known to me...it will be better if you kill yourself. Don't wait until my guys show up - they will torture you for weeks.</eng>
		<ukr>Ей, ти - виродок, якщо я дізнаюся твоє ім'я..., краще застрелись сам. Не чекай, коли за тобою прийдуть мої хлопці - вони тебе будуть довго мучити.</ukr>
		<fra>coute-moi, salaud ! Si je découvre ton identité, tu feras mieux de te tirer une balle ! N'attend pas que mes gars trouvent ton petit cul, ils vont s'en occuper, pendant longtemps.</fra>
		<pln>Ej, ty - frajerze, jak poznam twoją ksywę..., lepiej zastrzel się sam, nie czekaj aż przyjdą po ciebie moi chłopcy - nie dadzą ci szybko umrzeć.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_barm_3">
		<rus>Всем сталкерам в Баре, убит управляющий Арены. Ищите убийцу, пора уже прекратить этот беспредел раз и навсегда.</rus>
		<eng>To all the stalkers in the Bar, another manager of the Arena is assassinated. Find the killer, its time to end this chaos once and for all.</eng>
		<ukr>Всім сталкерам в Барі, убитий керуючий арени. Шукайте вбивцю, пора вже припинити це беззаконня раз і назавжди.</ukr>
		<fra>Tous les Stalkers sont au bar! L'administrateur de l'Arène a été tué. Trouvez le tueur, c'est un connard et nous devons l'arrêter une fois pour toutes.</fra>
		<pln>Do wszystkich stalkerów w Barze, zabito administratora Areny. Szukajcie zabójcy, pora wreszcie skończyć z tym bezprawiem raz na zawsze.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_barm_4">
		<rus>Мужики, снова скопытили управляющего Арены, убийца ещё где-то рядом. Найдите его, но не убивайте, просто переломайте все кости и бросьте умирать в костёр. После Долг повесит останки этой мрази на одно из деревьев у входа в Бар.</rus>
		<eng>Guys, Arena's manager was sent to a different world again, murderer is somewhere close. Find him, but don't kill, just break all his bones and leave him to die in fires. After, Duty will hang the remaining of this bastard on the trees near the entrance to the Bar.</eng>
		<ukr>Мужики, знову керуючому арени відкинули копита, вбивця ще десь поруч. Знайдіть його, але не вбивайте, просто переламайте всі кістки і киньте вмирати в багаття. Після цього Долг повісить останки цієї мерзоти на одне з дерев біля входу в Бар.</ukr>
		<fra>Les gars, l'administrateur de l'arène a été tué une fois de plus. Le tueur est toujours dans les environs. Trouvez-le, mais ne le tuez pas. Cassez-lui juste les rotules, coupez-lui les mains et jetez-les dans au feu. Ensuite accrochez-le sur la porte principale.</fra>
		<pln>Ludzie, znowu rozwalili administratora Areny, zabójca gdzieś tu jeszcze jest. Znajdźcie go, ale nie zabijajcie, połamcie mu wszystkie kości i rzućcie umierać do ogniska. Potem Powinność powiesi resztki tego drania na jednym z drzew przy wejściu do Baru.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_arny_spread_out">
		<rus>Тут такое дело... Арни по пьяни влетел в аномалию... короче, порвало его, даже костей не осталось. Так что, сами понимаете, мужики, боёв на Арене пока не будет. Как только найдётся новый управляющий - дам информацию по общему каналу.</rus>
		<eng>Well...Arnie, being dead-drunk, decided to fly in the carousel...anyways, his body shattered without a single bone remaining. No more Arena battles for a while. As soon as we find a new manager - I will let you know in the general channel.</eng>
		<ukr>Тут така справа... Арні по п'яні влетів в аномалію... коротше, порвало його, навіть кісток не залишилося. Так що, самі розумієте, мужики, боїв на арені поки не буде. Як тільки знайдеться новий керуючий - дам інформацію по загальному каналу.</ukr>
		<fra>Il y a un petit problème... Arnie n'est pas dans son état normal à cause d'un truc un peu fort qu'il a bu. Une alcool expérimental distillé dans une anomalie. Ca l'a bien déchiré, héhé !  Alors, vous comprendrez sans doute, les gars, qu'il n'y aura pas de combats dans l'arène jusqu'à ce qu'on trouve un nouvel administrateur. Quand nous l'aurons, je vous le ferai savoir.</fra>
		<pln>Jest taka sprawa... Arnie po pijaku wpadł do anomalii... Roztarło go na miazgę, nawet kości nie zostały. Tak więc, sami rozumiecie, ludzie, walk na Arenie póki co nie będzie. Jak tylko znajdzie się nowy administrator - puszczę informację na kanale ogólnym.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_admin_spread_out">
		<rus>Чёрт побери, куда-то пропал новый администратор Арены. Если кто увидит этого алкаша, немедленно тащите его в Бар. Хотя, скорее всего, уже поздно, наверное, сгинул в аномалии, или ещё какая беда приключилась... В любом случае Арена не откроется до тех пор, пока не найдётся управляющий. Всем спасибо, все свободны.</rus>
		<eng>God damn it, new administrator of the Arena disappeared in the unknown direction. If anyone sees this boozehead, drag him in the Bar immediately, although, its probably too late at this point...He probably took a nap in the anomaly or found some other way to end his life. Anyways, Arena won't open until new manager is found. Thanks to all, everyone is dismissed!</eng>
		<ukr>Чорт забирай, кудись пропав новий адміністратор арени. Якщо хто побачить цього алкаша, негайно тягніть його в бар. Хоча, швидше за все вже пізно, напевно, згинув в аномалії, або ще якась біда трапилася... У будь-якому разі арена не відкриється до тих пір, поки не знайдеться керуючий. Усім спасибі, всі вільні.</ukr>
		<fra>Nom de Dieu, le nouvel administrateur de l'Arène a disparu. Il s'est bourré la gueule et il a disparu. L'arène sera fermée jusqu'à ce que nous le retrouvions ou quelqu'un d'autre pour le remplacer.</fra>
		<pln>Do diabła, gdzieś przepadł nowy administrator Areny. Jeśli ktoś widział tego pijaka, niech go natychmiast przytaszczy do Baru, chociaż pewnie i tak już za późno, na pewno zginął w anomalii, albo mu się co innego przytrafiło... W każdym razie arena pozostanie zamknięta, dopóki nie znajdzie się administrator. Dziękuję wszystkim, jesteście wolni.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_drunk_1">
		<rus>Ушёл в бар жрать водку. До открытия не кантовать.</rus>
		<eng>I'm off to getting wasted in Bar.</eng>
		<ukr>Пішов у бар жерти горілку. До відкриття не кантувати.</ukr>
		<fra>Je vais au bar pour boire un coup. Tous ces combats m'ont donné soif...</fra>
		<pln>Poszedłem do baru chlać wódę. Do otwarcia nie kantować.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_drunk_2">
		<rus>Ушёл в бар пропивать ваши деньги, неудачники.</rus>
		<eng>I'm off to waste your money, losers.</eng>
		<ukr>Пішов у бар пропивати ваші гроші, невдахи.</ukr>
		<fra>Je vais au bar boire ... l'argent que t'as perdu.</fra>
		<pln>Poszedłem do baru przepijać wasze pieniądze, nieudaczniki.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_drunk_3">
		<rus>Если кому понадоблюсь, ищите меня в баре, только предупреждаю сразу, без бутылки разговора не будет.</rus>
		<eng>If somebody needs me, I'm in the Bar, except without a bottle of Casacs - don't even talk to me.</eng>
		<ukr>Якщо кому знадоблюсь, шукайте мене в барі, тільки попереджаю відразу, без пляшки розмови не буде.</ukr>
		<fra>Si quelqu'un a besoin de moi, qu'il vienne me chercher au bar. Je vous préviens ... qu'on ne vienne pas me déranger, sauf si vous avez une bouteille avec vous.</fra>
		<pln>Jeśli ktoś potrzebuje, szukajcie mnie w barze, ale uprzedzam, bez flaszki rozmowy nie będzie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aem_drunk_4">
		<rus>Эх, день за днём одно и то же... всё водка, водка... Короче, я в баре.</rus>
		<eng>Eh, day to day, bottle after a bottle...Anyways, I'm in the Bar.</eng>
		<ukr>Ех, день за днем одне і те ж... все горілка, горілка... Коротше, я в барі.</ukr>
		<fra>Pfff, tous les jours c'est pareil... un coup de vodka par-ci, par-là, et un p'tit pour la route. Bref, je suis au Bar.</fra>
		<pln>Ech, dzień za dniem to samo... Tylko wódka, wódka... krótko mówiąc, jestem w barze.</pln>
	</string>
</string_table>
