<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="scaintist_docs_name">
		<rus>Документы</rus>
		<eng>Documents</eng>
		<ukr>Документи</ukr>
		<fra>Documents</fra>
		<pln>Dokumenty</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="scaintist_docs_desc">
		<rus>Судя по записям, учёные везли какой-то очень необычный артефакт.</rus>
		<eng>Accodring to the records, scientists were carrying a very unusual artifact.</eng>
		<ukr>Судячи із записів, вчені везли якийсь дуже незвичайний артефакт.</ukr>
		<fra>À en juger par les dossiers, les scientifiques ont emporté un artéfact très inhabituel.</fra>
		<pln>Sądząc po wpisach, uczeni wieźli jakiś bardzo niezwykły artefakt.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_krysyka_name">
		<rus>КПК Крысюка</rus>
		<eng>Krysyuk's PDA </eng>
		<ukr>КПК Щуряка</ukr>
		<fra>PDA Kryssiouk</fra>
		<pln>PDA Krysiuka</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_krysyka_desc">
		<rus>Крысюк много чего вынюхал и записал в свой КПК. Боров за него глотку порвёт.</rus>
		<eng>Krysyuk sniffed out a lot and recorded everything in his PDA. Hog can rip a throat out for it. </eng>
		<ukr>Щуряк багато чого винюхав і записав у свій КПК... Кабан за нього глотку порве...</ukr>
		<fra>Kryssiouk a détecté beaucoup de choses et les a écrites dans son PDA. Le Ragot veut récupérer les données et le massacrer.</fra>
		<pln>Krysiuk niejedno wyniuchał i zapisał to w swoim PDA. Borow przegryzł by za nie gardło.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_borov_secret_name">
		<rus>Тайник Борова</rus>
		<eng>Hog's stash</eng>
		<ukr>Схованка Кабана</ukr>
		<fra>La réserve du Ragot</fra>
		<pln>Schowek Borowa</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_borov_secret_descr">
		<rus>Боров сказал, тут есть чем поживиться.</rus>
		<eng>Hog said, there is some good stuff here. </eng>
		<ukr>Кабан сказав - тут є чим поживитися...</ukr>
		<fra>Ragot a dit, il y a quelques bonnes choses ici.</fra>
		<pln>Borow powiedział - jest się czym tu pożywić.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="vodka_rad">
		<rus>Палёная водка</rus>
		<eng>Tainted vodka</eng>
		<ukr>Палена горілка</ukr>
		<fra>Vodka contaminée</fra>
		<pln>Przepalanka</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="vodka_rad_descr">
		<rus>Был в Зоне один делец, пытался продавать дешёвую водку. Делец теперь на том свете - проклинает свою жажду наживы.</rus>
		<eng>There was one dealer in the Zone, he was trying to sell cheap vodka. Now the dealer is on the other side - he is cursing his demand for profit.</eng>
		<ukr>Був у зоні один ділок, намагався продавати дешеву горілку. Ділок тепер на тому світі - проклинає свою спрагу наживи...</ukr>
		<fra>Il essayait de vendre de la vodka bon marché. Il est maintenant le rideau de sa demande de profit..</fra>
		<pln>Był w Zonie jeden spryciarz, próbował sprzedawać podrobioną wódkę. Handlarz teraz na tamtym świecie - przeklina swoją chciwość.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="food_bread_rad">
		<rus>Радиоактивный батон</rus>
		<eng>Radioactive bread</eng>
		<ukr>Радіоактивний батон</ukr>
		<fra>Pain radioactif</fra>
		<pln>Radioaktywny chleb</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_food_bread_rad">
		<rus>Когда-то был нормальный хлеб, теперь радиоактивный хлеб... Если надоела жизнь - можно съесть.</rus>
		<eng>It used to be normal bread, now it's radioactive... If you're sick of this life, you can eat it.</eng>
		<ukr>Колись був нормальний хліб, тепер радіоактивний хліб... Якщо набридло життя - можна з'їсти...</ukr>
		<fra>Il était une fois un pain normal, maintenant un pain radioactif ... Si vous en avez marre de la vie, vous pouvez en manger.</fra>
		<pln>Kiedyś to był normalny chleb... Teraz to radioaktywny chleb... Jeśli masz dosyć życia - możesz zjeść.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорово, братела... Перетрём базар?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, bro... Can we talk?</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, братела... Перетремо базар?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, mon frère ... pouvons-nous parler?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, braciak... Zrobimy interes?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_1">
		<rus>И тебе не кашлять. О чём разговор?</rus>
		<eng>Hey yourself. What's the matter?</eng>
		<ukr>І тобі не кашляти... Про що розмова...</ukr>
		<fra>Hé toi-même.De quoi parlez-vous? Quel est le problème?</fra>
		<pln>Jasna sprawa... O czym ta mowa?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_2">
		<rus>Да так. Посидим, пузырёк раздавим...</rus>
		<eng>Nothing special. Just let's sit and refresh...</eng>
		<ukr>Та так.. посидимо, пляшку роздавимо...</ukr>
		<fra>Rien de spécial. Asseyons-nous et rafraîchissons-nous...</fra>
		<pln>Ano tak. Posiedzimy, flaszeczkę rozlejemy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_3">
		<rus>Ну наливай...</rus>
		<eng>Well, bring over...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну наливай...</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, apportez plus...</fra>
		<pln>To polewaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_41">
		<rus>Вздрогнем...</rus>
		<eng>Cheers...</eng>
		<ukr>Здригнемося...</ukr>
		<fra>Salut...</fra>
		<pln>To chlup...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_42">
		<rus>Вот ёпть, кончился нектар...</rus>
		<eng>Ah, damn, the nectar is over...</eng>
		<ukr>От йопть, скінчився нектар...</ukr>
		<fra>Ah, zut, le nectar est fini...</fra>
		<pln>Szlag, skończył się nektar...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_5">
		<rus>У-у-ух... Хорошо пошла... Сальцем бы занюхать...</rus>
		<eng>Whoo... It goes well... I'd like to bite some salo...</eng>
		<ukr>У-у-ух... Добре пішла... Сальцем би занюхати...</ukr>
		<fra>Ooh-euh ... Eh bien, je vais y aller ... Saltz sentirait...</fra>
		<pln>U-u-u-h... Dobrze poszło... Ogóreczka by...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_6">
		<rus>Слышь, кореш... Не слышал ни-э-чего интересного?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, buddy... Did not you he-eee-ar anything interesting?</eng>
		<ukr>Чуєш, кореш... Не чув ні-і-чого цікавого?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, mon pote ... avez-vous entendu quelque chose d'intéressant?</fra>
		<pln>Słuchaj, koleś... Nie słyszałeś aby czego ciekawego?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_71">
		<rus>Только тебе, братела, скажу... Недавно на трупе одном пэдэашку нашёл, там малява была про хабар спрятанный... Самому мне в лом топать, а раз ты свой кореш в доску, то можешь иметь...</rus>
		<eng>I'll tell only you, bro... Recently I've found a PDA on a corpse, there was a little bit about some hidden loot... I can't be bothered to go, and since you're like my brother, you can have...</eng>
		<ukr>Тільки тобі, братела скажу... Нещодавно на трупі одному педеашку знайшов, там малява була про хабар захований... Самому мені в лом топати, а раз ти свій кореш в дошку, то можеш мати...</ukr>
		<fra>Seulement à vous, Bratela, je dirai ... Récemment, sur l'un des cadavres, j'ai trouvé l'un d'entre eux, il y avait un swag sur le butin caché ... J'ai moi-même dû piétiner, et si vous étiez votre acolyte, vous auriez pu...</fra>
		<pln>Tylko tobie, braciak, powiem... Niedawno na trupie jednym PDA znalazłem, tam gryps był o towarze schowanym... Mnie tam nie po drodze, a że jesteś równy gość, to możesz mieć...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_73">
		<rus>Ну ты блин даёшь... корефан, чё тут интересного может быть, это же не Рио-де-Житомир... Тоска зелёная!</rus>
		<eng>You amaze me, mate... What can be interesting here? It's not Rio de Zhytomyr... Boredom to death!</eng>
		<ukr>Ну ти блін даєш... корефан, що тут цікавого може бути, це ж не Ріо-де-Житомир... Тоска зелена!</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, vous vous en foutez ... Korefan,Vous m'étonnez, mon pote ... Qu'est-ce qui peut être intéressant ici? Ce n'est pas Rio de Janeiro ... L'ennui à mourir!</fra>
		<pln>Co ty znowu pleciesz... Koleś, co tu może ciekawego być!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_81">
		<rus>Будет не фиг делать - слазию, зарисую...</rus>
		<eng>If I am bored, I will check it out...</eng>
		<ukr>Буде нєфіг робити - злазю, позирю...</ukr>
		<fra>Si je m'ennuie, je vais le vérifier...</fra>
		<pln>Nie będzie co robić - zajdę, popatrzę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ладно, будет чего - звони...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, if there is something, call me...</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, буде чого - дзвони...</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, s'il y a quelque chose, appelle-moi ...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, coś będzie - dzwoń...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_0">
		<rus>Как жизнь, корефан? Столкуемся?</rus>
		<eng>What's up, mate? Have a talk?</eng>
		<ukr>Як життя корефан? Порозуміємося?</ukr>
		<fra>Quoi de neuf, mec? Parler?</fra>
		<pln>Jak żyjesz koleżko?... Pogadamy?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да без базара... Падай рядом...</rus>
		<eng>No problem... Park yourself here...</eng>
		<ukr>Та без базару... Падай поруч...</ukr>
		<fra>Pas de problème ... Posons nous ici...</fra>
		<pln>Tylko bez gadki... Walnij się obok...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_2">
		<rus>В натуре кручила бы похавать...</rus>
		<eng>Word up, my stomach is churning...</eng>
		<ukr>В натурі крючила б похавати...</ukr>
		<fra>Je suis bouche bée...</fra>
		<pln>Prawdziwego koniaku by spróbować...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_3">
		<rus>Давай наливай, а крючила найдем, не межуйся...</rus>
		<eng>Come on, pour, we'll find something to eat, do not worry...</eng>
		<ukr>Давай наливай, а крючила знайдемо, не межуйся...</ukr>
		<fra>Allez, versez, versez, ne vous inquiétez pas...</fra>
		<pln>Polewaj, znajdzie się i koniak, nie martw się...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_41">
		<rus>Давай тогда, за пацанов...</rus>
		<eng>Let's drink the guys' health...</eng>
		<ukr>Давай тоді, за пацанів...</ukr>
		<fra>Buvons à la santé des gars...</fra>
		<pln>Za chłopaków...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_42">
		<rus>Не-е, мужик, если бы у меня было...</rus>
		<eng>No, man, if I had...</eng>
		<ukr>Ні-і, мужик, якби у мене було...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, mec, si j'avais...</fra>
		<pln>Nie-e, chłopie, jakbym miał...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_5">
		<rus>За пацанов, конкретно...</rus>
		<eng>Yeah, true...</eng>
		<ukr>За пацанів, конкретно...</ukr>
		<fra>Pour les garçons, en particulier...</fra>
		<pln>Za chłopaków, jeszcze raz...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_6">
		<rus>Мужик, просвисти чё-нить интересное... А?</rus>
		<eng>Man, tell me something interesting... Huh?</eng>
		<ukr>Мужик, просвисти що-небудь цікаве... А?</ukr>
		<fra>Homme, dis-moi quelque chose d'intéressant ... Hein?</fra>
		<pln>Gościu, wyśpiewaj coś ciekawego... No?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_71">
		<rus>Интересного? Слышал базар на сходняке, вроде как нычка есть не распотрошённая... Я не потащусь в такую даль - мне и здесь лохов хватает, если не в лом переть - запиши приметку...</rus>
		<eng>Interesting? I've heard something at a gathering, there is a sort of stash hidden... I won't go so far away - I've got enough loosers here, if you are not bothered to go, write down a note...</eng>
		<ukr>Цікаве? Чув базар на сходняку, ніби як ничка є нерозпотрошена... Я не потягну в таку далечінь - мені й тут лохів вистачає, якщо не в лом перти - запиши примітку...</ukr>
		<fra>Intéressant? J'ai vu quelque chose comme cette cachette cachée ... Elle n'est pas si loin...</fra>
		<pln>Ciekawego? Słyszałem gadkę, że niby jest skrytka niewypatroszona... Ja nie pójdę tak daleko - mnie i tu frajerów do golenia starczy - zapisz wskazówkę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_73">
		<rus>Соловья поймай, он те свиснет...</rus>
		<eng>Catch a nightingale, it will whistle...</eng>
		<ukr>Солов'я злови, він тобі свисне...</ukr>
		<fra>Attrapez un rossignol, il chantera...</fra>
		<pln>Słowika złap, on ci zaśpiewa...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_81">
		<rus>Не, мне тоже в лом, мимо буду переть - даже не нагнусь...</rus>
		<eng>No, I am bothered, too. If l pass by, I won't even bend...</eng>
		<ukr>Нє, мені теж в лом, як повз буду перти - навіть не нагнуся...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, ça me gêne aussi. Si je passe, je ne me plierai même pas...</fra>
		<pln>Nie, mnie tam też nie po drodze. Poza tym, nie chce mi się...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_82">
		<rus>Успокойся, утырок...</rus>
		<eng>Calm down, crumb twerp...</eng>
		<ukr>Заспокойся, утирок...</ukr>
		<fra>Calmez-vous, cachez-vous...</fra>
		<pln>Spokojnie, koleżko...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет паханам! О чём базарите?</rus>
		<eng>Hey shots callers! What's the rumpus?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт паханам! Про чо базарите?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour, travailleurs combattants! Quel est ce chahut?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć chłopaki, o czym gadacie?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_1">
		<rus>Привет, привет, терпила! Хоть Боров и велел тебя не трогать, но не нарывайся...</rus>
		<eng>Hey vic! Even though Hog ordered not to touch you, you'd better not to look for trouble...</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт, привіт. Терпила! Хоч Кабан і звелів тебе не чіпати, але не наривайся...</ukr>
		<fra>Salut, salut. J'ai souffert! Bien que le Ragot nous a dit de ne pas te toucher, mais ne t’inquiète pas...</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, cześć, łajzo. Chociaż Borow kazał cię nie ruszać, lepiej nie podskakuj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_2">
		<rus>Скучно блин, без водки... А в тюрьме сейчас ужин, макароны!</rus>
		<eng>It's boring without vodka... Now in prison they are having dinner, pasta!</eng>
		<ukr>Нудно блін, без горілки... А у в'язниці зараз вечеря, макарони!</ukr>
		<fra>C'est ennuyeux sans vodka ... Maintenant en prison, ils dînent, des pâtes!</fra>
		<pln>Nudno bez wódki... A w ciupie teraz kolacja, makaron!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_3">
		<rus>Не каркай, лучше наливай братанам...</rus>
		<eng>Don't be a worrywart! You'd better give the bros their drinks...</eng>
		<ukr>Не каркай, краще наливай братанам...</ukr>
		<fra>Ne soyez pas inquiet! Tu ferais mieux de leur donner leurs boissons...</fra>
		<pln>Nie kracz, lepiej polej chłopakom...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ладно, братаны. Шоб в сторону не вильнуло!</rus>
		<eng>All right, bros. Here we go!</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, братани. Шоб в сторону не вильнуло!</ukr>
		<fra>D'accord, frères. C'est parti!</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, braciaki. Na drugą nogę!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_42">
		<rus>Лады, щас с Боровом потолкую и налью.</rus>
		<eng>Alright, I will talk with Hog and pour.</eng>
		<ukr>Лади, щас з Кабаном потолкую і наллю.</ukr>
		<fra>D'accord, je vais parler au Ragot et verser.</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, tylko z Borowem pogadam i już leję.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_5">
		<rus>Мммм, уважаю! Так бы и начинал...</rus>
		<eng>Hmm, respect! You should have started with this...</eng>
		<ukr>Мммм, поважаю! Так би й починав...</ukr>
		<fra>Hmm, respect! Vous devriez avoir commencé avec ça...</fra>
		<pln>Mmmmm, powaga! Tak trzeba było od razu...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_6">
		<rus>Че нового слыхать? Не слышал ни-э-чего интересного?</rus>
		<eng>What's new? Did not you hear anything interesting?</eng>
		<ukr>Що нового слихать? Не чув ні-і-чого цікавого?</ukr>
		<fra>Quoi de neuf à entendre? Je n'ai rien entendu d'intéressant?</fra>
		<pln>Co nowego słychać? Nie było czegoś ciekawego?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_71">
		<rus>А чё нового... Вона вчера взяли мы с парнями трёх долговцев, они только на постах своих кренделями сидят, а тут сразу - "мужики, не надо"... "хабар могу показать"... Да какой там хабар, думают запудрить мозги и слинять по тихому, а потом всей кодлой навалиться... Гы.. А он - "совсем рядом нычка", ну не чмо а? А пошло оно все... Эта нычка его... Щас.. О! Вона где!.. Прикинь...</rus>
		<eng>New?... Yesterday we took three duty fighters, they appeared to be brave only on duty, as they moaned - "guys, do not..." "I can show you loot"... Oh yeah! They want to show us loot, they are going to blow smoke at us and blast off, and then come back with the whole gang... Ha... And after this he says that the stash is withing easy distance. Isn't he a douchebag? Screw it... This stash... Oh! Here is it!.. Look...</eng>
		<ukr>А що нового... Вона вчора взяли ми з хлопцями трьох долгівців, вони тільки на постах своїх кренделями сидять, а тут одразу - "мужики, не треба"... "хабар можу показати"... Та який там хабар, думають запудрити мізки і злиняти по тихому, а потім усією кодлою навалитися... Ги.. А він - "зовсім поруч хованка", ну не чмо а? А пішло воно все... Ця хованка його... Щас.. О! Вона де! Прикинь...</ukr>
		<fra>Et ce qui est nouveau ... Vaughn, nous avons emmené hier avec les types de trois débiteurs, ils sont assis sur leurs poteaux avec des bretzels, et ici à la fois - "les gars, ne faites pas ..." "Je peux vous montrer du butin" ... Oh oui! Et puis ça revient avec tout le gang, ils pensent se poudrer la cervelle et s’échapper sur le silence, puis tout le code va tomber sur ... Mince .. Et c’est un "très proche petit truc", bon, pas un imbécile? Et tout s'est passé ... cette cachette ... Oh! Voilà! .. Regardez ... maintenant ... Comptez...</fra>
		<pln>A co nowego... A no, wczoraj wieczorem wzięliśmy z chłopakami trzech z Powinności, oni tylko na swoich posterunkach tacy mocni, a tu od razu - "ludzie, nie trzeba"... "towar mogę od razu pokazać"... Jaki tam towar, kombinujemy jak oczy zamydlić i podkraść się po cichu, a potem całą kupą naskoczyć... Hehe. A on - "tu blisko jest skrytka", no i co? A poszedł że ty... I ta twoja skrytka...  Zaraz.. O! Tu jest!.. Zobacz...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_73">
		<rus>Нового? А чё тут нового, всё одно и то же!</rus>
		<eng>New? What can be new, everything is the same!</eng>
		<ukr>Нового? А чо тут нового, все одне і те ж!</ukr>
		<fra>Nouveau? Quoi de neuf, tout est pareil!</fra>
		<pln>Nowego? A co tu może być nowego, jedno i to samo!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_81">
		<rus>Ха, туда же полдня переть, точно - мозги втирали...</rus>
		<eng>Hah, it will take you half a day, bullshit...</eng>
		<ukr>Ха, туди ж півдня перти, точно - мізки втирали...</ukr>
		<fra>Hah, ça va te prendre une demi-journée, conneries...</fra>
		<pln>He, pół dnia trzeba by tam iść, dokładnie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_82">
		<rus>Покеда, будет поллитра - забегай...</rus>
		<eng>See you, if you have a half-liter bottle,  drop in...</eng>
		<ukr>Покеда, буде півлітра - забігай...</ukr>
		<fra>Rendez-vous si vous avez une bouteille d'un demi-litre, arrêtez-vous...</fra>
		<pln>Na razie, znajdziesz pół litra - zachodź...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_0">
		<rus>Ба! Кого я вижу! Сколько лет, сколько зим!</rus>
		<eng>Oh! Look who's here! Been a while!</eng>
		<ukr>Ба! Кого я бачу! Скільки років, скільки зим!</ukr>
		<fra>Oh! Regardez qui est ici! Ça fait longtemps!</fra>
		<pln>Ba! Kogo ja widzę! Kopę lat!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_1">
		<rus>Отвали, не видишь, устал я после вчерашнего...</rus>
		<eng>Fuck off, don't you see, I'm tired after yesterday...</eng>
		<ukr>Відвали, не бачиш, втомився я після вчорашнього...</ukr>
		<fra>Va te faire foutre, tu ne vois pas, je suis fatigué après hier...</fra>
		<pln>Spadaj, nie widzisz, zmęczony jestem po wczorajszym...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_2">
		<rus>Ну так давай, поправим здоровье...</rus>
		<eng>Well, it can be easily remedied...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну так давай, поправимо здоров'я...</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, allons améliorer notre santé,on peut facilement y remédier...</fra>
		<pln>No to dawaj, poprawimy zdrowie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_3">
		<rus>Да вчера все выжрали, голяк полный...</rus>
		<eng> Put away everything yesterday, nothing is left...</eng>
		<ukr>Та вчора все вижрали, голяк повний...</ukr>
		<fra>Hier, tout le monde a été dévoré,et je n'ai plus rien...</fra>
		<pln>Tylko że wczoraj wszystko wychlali...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_41">
		<rus>Для здоровья всегда припасаю микстурку... Поехали!</rus>
		<eng>I always have some medicine for health... Let's go!</eng>
		<ukr>Для здоров'я завжди припасаю мікстурку... Поїхали!</ukr>
		<fra>Pour la santé, commencez à économiser... Je garde toujours un médikit pour la santé!</fra>
		<pln>Dla zdrowia zawsze mam miksturkę... Jedziemy!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_42">
		<rus>Оп-па! И я пустой нонче...</rus>
		<eng>Oh! I also have nothing today...</eng>
		<ukr>Оп-па! І я порожній нинче...</ukr>
		<fra>Oh! Je n'ai rien non plus aujourd'hui...</fra>
		<pln>Op-pa! U mnie też pustki...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_5">
		<rus>У-у-ух... Благодетель...</rus>
		<eng>Hoo... That's nice...</eng>
		<ukr>У-у-ух... Благотетель...</ukr>
		<fra>Ooooh ... Bienfaiteur...</fra>
		<pln>U-u-u-h... Dobroczyńca...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_6">
		<rus>Чё говорят у вас? Есть ещё хабарные места?</rus>
		<eng>What do they say? Are are still loot places?</eng>
		<ukr>Чо говорять у вас? Є ще хабарні місця?</ukr>
		<fra>Que dites-vous? Y a-t-il d'autres endroits pour votre maison?</fra>
		<pln>Co u was mówią? Są jeszcze miejsca z towarem?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_71">
		<rus>А-то! Ты не звони сильно, я тут видел как Боровы шестёрки хабарок ныкали... Сам то не возьму - бо у нас с этим строго, не ровен час с пером в боку проснёшься, а ты пришёл - ушёл, никто и не хватиться. А когда будешь мимо проходить - заходи, ещё пару дел обмозгуем... Замётано?</rus>
		<eng>Sure! Do not open up, I saw Hog's doters hiding the loot... I won't take it, you know I'm accountable for that. Something might go wrong. But you have come and gone, nobody will notice. And when you pass by, come and see me, we'll think over a couple more ploys...Deal?</eng>
		<ukr>А то! Ти не звони сильно, я тут бачив як шістки Кабана хабарок никали... Сам то я не візьму - бо у нас з цим строго, не ровєн час з пером у боці просньошся, а ти пришол - ушол, ніхто й не хватітся. А кагда будеш мимо проходить - заході, ще пару справ обмозгуем... Замьотано?</ukr>
		<fra>Bien sûr! Vous n’appelez pas beaucoup, j’ai vu les braqueurs du Ragot cacher le butin... j’en suis responsable. Quelque chose pourrait mal tourner. Mais vous êtes venu et parti, personne ne le remarquera. Et quand vous passerez, venez me voir,nous vous promettons deux autres affaires ... OK?</fra>
		<pln>Aha! Tylko cicho o tym, widziałem jak ludzie Borowa towarek chowali... Sam nie wezmę - bo u nas z tym ostro, nie będziesz wiedział kiedy z kosą w boku się obudzisz, a ty, przyszedłes - poszedłeś, nikt się nie połapie. A jak będziesz tędy przechodził - zajrzyj, jeszcze parę rzeczy obmyślimy... Stoi?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_73">
		<rus>Все хабарные места Боров под себя подмял, нам крохи перепадают...</rus>
		<eng>Hog took all loot places, we see crumbs...</eng>
		<ukr>Всі хабарниє місця Кабан під себе подмял, нам крохи перепадають...</ukr>
		<fra>Ragot a pris tous les lieux de butin,il ne reste que des miettes...</fra>
		<pln>Wszystkie miejsca z towarem Borow dla siebie zagarnął, nam tylko ochłapy zostały...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_81">
		<rus>Замётано!</rus>
		<eng>Deal!</eng>
		<ukr>Заметано!</ukr>
		<fra>D'accord!</fra>
		<pln>Stoi!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ладно, стронулся я, бывай...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, I'm moving out, take care...</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, стронулся я, бувай...</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, je déménage, prends soin de toi...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, będę spadał, bywaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет, братишка... Как оно?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, bro... What's up?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт, братику... Як воно?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour frère ... comment ça va?Quoi de neuf?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, braciaszku... Jak tam?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да ничего вроде... Хотел чего или так просто?</rus>
		<eng>Not bad... Did you want something?</eng>
		<ukr>Та нічого ніби... Хотів чого або так просто?</ukr>
		<fra>Pas mal… Vouliez-vous quelque chose?</fra>
		<pln>A nic specjalnego... Chciałeś coś, czy tak tylko?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_2">
		<rus>Да так.. тихо здесь, дай думаю посидим, здоровье поправим...</rus>
		<eng>Not really.. it's quiet here, I thought we could sit and refresh...</eng>
		<ukr>Та так.. тихо тут, дай думаю посидимо, здоров'я поправимо...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, alors .. tranquillement ici, laissez-moi réfléchir, asseyons-nous, nous allons corriger notre santé...</fra>
		<pln>A tak.. cicho tu, pomyślałem posiedzimy, zdrowie poprawimy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_3">
		<rus>Здоровье - это хорошо, наливай что ли...</rus>
		<eng>It's a good idea, bring over...</eng>
		<ukr>Здоров'я - це добре, наливай чи що....</ukr>
		<fra>C’est une bonne idée...Versez quelque chose</fra>
		<pln>Zdrowie - a, to dobrze, nalej jednego...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ну давай по чуть-чуть...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, but a little bit...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай по чуть-чуть...</ukr>
		<fra>C’est une bonne idée...Ok, mais un peu...</fra>
		<pln>To dawaj po maluchu...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_42">
		<rus>Самому бы кто налил...</rus>
		<eng>I wish someone could pour me...</eng>
		<ukr>Самому б хто налив...</ukr>
		<fra>Je souhaite que quelqu'un puisse me verser...</fra>
		<pln>Sam bym się napił...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_5">
		<rus>Крепкая... Зараза... Сальцем бы занюхать...</rus>
		<eng>Damn...It's strong... I wish we had salo...</eng>
		<ukr>Міцна... Зараза... Сальцем би занюхати...</ukr>
		<fra>Putain ... C'est fort ... J'aurais aimé que nous en ayons plus...</fra>
		<pln>Mocna... Zaraza... Ogóreczka by...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_6">
		<rus>Мда... Хорошо по-ош-шла... Наверно и не знаешь ничего интересного?</rus>
		<eng>Yeah... It goes well... I guess you do not know anything interesting?</eng>
		<ukr>Мда... Добре пі-іш-шла... Напевно і не знаєш нічого цікавого?</ukr>
		<fra>Ouais ... Ça va bien ... Je suppose que vous ne savez rien d’intéressant?</fra>
		<pln>Ta-a... Dobrze weszła... Nie wiesz czegoś ciekawego?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_71">
		<rus>Недавно с Волком вытаскивали сталкера из аномалии, вернее то, что от него осталось... Да... При нем записка была с координатами. Мол спрятанный хабар там... Но Волк сказал - не соваться туда. Вот координаты - запиши, если стоящее дело - расскажи потом... Лады?</rus>
		<eng>Wolf and I have recently pulled Stalker out of the anomaly, or rather what was left of him... Yes... He had a note with coordinates. Like there is hidden loot there... But Wolf said not to butt in. Here are the coordinates - write down, if there is anything worthwhile, tell me, ok?</eng>
		<ukr>Нещодавно з Вовком витягали сталкера з аномалії, вірніше те, що від нього залишилося... Так... При ньому записка була з координатами. Мовляв захований хабар там... Але Вовк сказав - не сунутися туди. Ось координати - запиши, якщо варта справа - розкажи потім... Лади?</ukr>
		<fra>Récemment, un stalker avec le Loup a été retiré de l'anomalie, ou plutôt de ce qui lui restait ... Oui ... Avec lui, la note était avec les coordonnées. Ils disent que le butin caché là-bas ... Mais le Loup a dit - n'y allez pas. Voici les coordonnées - écrivez-le, si c'est une affaire digne d'intérêt - dites-le-moi plus tard ... OK?</fra>
		<pln>Niedawno z Wilkiem wyciągaliśmy stalkera z anomalii, a raczej to, co z niego zostało... Taa... Miał ze sobą notatkę z koordynatami. Pewnie towar tam miał schowany... Ale Wilk powiedział - żeby tam nie chodzić. Oto koordynaty - zapisz, jeśli było warto - opowiesz potem... Dobra?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_73">
		<rus>Не-е, я тут недавно, глубоко не ходил ещё... Подходи через недельку - может и узнаю чего...</rus>
		<eng>No, I'm new here, haven't gone deep yet... Come in a week, maybe I'll find out something...</eng>
		<ukr>Ні-і, я тут недавно, глибоко не ходив ще... Підходь через тиждень - може і дізнаюся чого...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, j'ai été ici récemment, je ne suis pas encore allé au fond ... Revenez dans une semaine - peut-être que je saurai quoi...</fra>
		<pln>Nie-e, ja tu jestem niedawno, tak głęboko jeszcze nie chodziłem... Przyjdź za tydzień - może czegoś się dowiem...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_81">
		<rus>Лады... Посмотрю...</rus>
		<eng>Good... I'll see...</eng>
		<ukr>Лади... Подивлюсь...</ukr>
		<fra>Bien ... je vais voir...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra... Popatrzę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ладно, ещё поговорим на досуге...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, let's talk in an idle moment...</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, ще поговоримо на дозвіллі...</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, parlons dans un moment d'inactivité ...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, jeszcze pogadamy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорово, как жизнь сталкерская?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, how's stalker's life?</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, як життя сталкерське?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, comment va la vie de Stalker?</fra>
		<pln>Czołem, jak tam życie stalkerskie?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_1">
		<rus>Здорово и тебе, Меченный... Так себе... Потихоньку...</rus>
		<eng>Hey, Marked One... So so... Plugging along...</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово і тобі, Мічений... Так собі.. Потихеньку...</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, le Marqué, alors ça va?.. Quoi de neuf?</fra>
		<pln>Czołem i tobie, Naznaczony... Tak sobie.. Pomalutku...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_2">
		<rus>Может по пять капель на грудь? Для поправки здоровья...</rus>
		<eng>What about knocking back a few drinks? For health improvement...</eng>
		<ukr>Може по п'ять крапель на груди? Для поправки здоров'я...</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi ne pas boire quelques verres? Pour améliorer la santé...</fra>
		<pln>Może by tak po kropelce? Dla poprawy zdrowia...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_3">
		<rus>Неплохо бы! Угости, раз такой добрый...</rus>
		<eng>Sounds good! Treat me, if you are so kind...</eng>
		<ukr>Непогано б! Пригости, раз такий добрий...</ukr>
		<fra>Ça sonne bien! Allez buvons un coup...</fra>
		<pln>Byłoby nieźle! Poczęstuj, jak już taki dobry jesteś...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ну дёрнули, по сто пятьдесят для храбрости...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, let's have some shots of courage...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну, підняли, по сто п'ятдесят для хоробрості...</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, prenons quelques coups de courage...</fra>
		<pln>No to już, po sto pięćdziesiąt dla odwagi...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_42">
		<rus>Щас, к Сидору смотаюсь только...</rus>
		<eng>Wait, I'll just visit Sidor...</eng>
		<ukr>Зара, до Сидора змотаюсь тільки...</ukr>
		<fra>Attendez, je vais juste rendre visite à Sidor...</fra>
		<pln>Już, tylko do Sidorowicza skoczę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_5">
		<rus>К-ха кха, вот ёпть... Из табуретки что ли гонят? Чуть обратно не пошла...</rus>
		<eng>Kaff-kaff, damn... What the hell was it made of? It almost went back...</eng>
		<ukr>К-ха кха, от йопть... З табуретки женуть, чи що? Мало назад не пішла...</ukr>
		<fra>Arff, putain ... De quoi était-il fait? Il est presque retourné...</fra>
		<pln>K-he khe, oż jego... Z nawozu to pędzą? O mało co się nie cofnęło...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_6">
		<rus>Здесь всё может быть... Расскажи чё-нить...</rus>
		<eng>Anything can be here... Tell me something...</eng>
		<ukr>Тут все може бути... Розкажи що-небудь...</ukr>
		<fra>Tout peut être ici ... Dis-moi quelque chose...</fra>
		<pln>Tutaj wszystko możliwe... Opowiedz coś...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_71">
		<rus>Недавно к Сидору приходили пара сталкеров... Я у Сидора в предбаннике спал.. Ну не совсем, конечно, спал, так, вполглаза... Они хотели снаряжение кое-какое у него выторговать, в кредит, так сказать... Говорили есть схрон богатый с хабаром, даже описали место... Но Сидор ничего не дал - вот ведь сквалыга, да? Думал сам смотаться, да все с духом не соберусь... Вот здесь это место - видишь? Если будет чего - не забудешь про меня?</rus>
		<eng>A couple of stalkers have come to Sidor recently... I slept in Sidor's small room. Well, I did not sleep actually, slept with one eye open... They wanted to bargain some equipment from him, on credit, so to speak... They said there is a huge stash with loot, they even described the place... But Sidor did not give anything. What a stingy person. I thought to go myself, but I can't get my courage... Look, here is the place. Don't forget about me, if there is something.</eng>
		<ukr>Нещодавно до Сидора приходили пара сталкерів... Я у Сидора в передбаннику спав.. Ну не зовсім, звичайно, спав, так, упівока... Вони хотіли спорядження деяке у нього виторгувати, в кредит, так би мовити... Говорили є схрон багатий з хабаром, навіть описали місце... Але Сидор нічого не дав - от же ж скнара, так? Думав сам змотатися, та все з духом не зберуся... Ось тут це місце - бачиш? Якщо буде щось - не забудеш про мене?</ukr>
		<fra>Récemment, un couple de Stalkers est venu chez Sidor ... J'ai dormi dans une salle d'attente à Sidor ... Eh bien, pas tout à fait bien sûr, j'ai dormi, alors que mes yeux étaient mi-vides ... Ils voulaient obtenir de l'équipement auprès de lui, à crédit, pour ainsi dire ... Ils ont dit qu'il y avait une caisse riche avec du butin, ils ont même décrit l'endroit ... Mais Sidor n'a rien donné -  quelle personne avare. Je pensais que je pouvais avoir mon courage ... Regardez, voici l'endroit. Ne m'oublie pas s'il y a quelque chose Je pensais y aller moi-même, mais je ne vais pas tout réunir ... </fra>
		<pln>Niedawno do Sidorowicza przyszło paru stalkerów... Ja tam w przedsionku spałem.. No, nie całkiem spałem, tak jednym okiem... Chcieli sprzęt jakiś tam u niego wytargować, na kredyt, że tak powiem... Mówili, że jest schowek bogaty z towarem, nawet miejsce opisali... Ale Sidor niczego nie dał - to ci kutwa, co? Myślałem żeby samemu się przejść, ale jakoś nie mogę się zebrać... To właśnie to miejsce - widzisz? Jak coś tam będzie - nie zapomnisz o mnie?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_73">
		<rus>Да чё рассказывать? Зона - она Зона и есть. Свалить бы отсюда...</rus>
		<eng>What to tell? Zone is Zone. I wish I could leave...</eng>
		<ukr>Та що розповідати.. Зона, вона Зона і є, звалити б звідси...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, que dire?La Zone - c'est la Zone.Et pour sortir d'ici...</fra>
		<pln>A co tu opowiadać. Zona to Zona i już, wynieść by się stąd...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_81">
		<rus>Если будет чего стоящее - не забуду...</rus>
		<eng>If there is something worthwhile, I will not forget...</eng>
		<ukr>Якщо буде щось варте - не забуду...</ukr>
		<fra>S'il y a quelque chose de valable, je n'oublierai pas...</fra>
		<pln>Jeśli będzie coś cennego - nie zapomnę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_82">
		<rus>Свалим, когда-нибудь...</rus>
		<eng>We'll leave, someday...</eng>
		<ukr>Звалимо, коли небудь...</ukr>
		<fra>Nous tomberons un jour ou l'autre...</fra>
		<pln>Może kiedyś zajdę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_0">
		<rus>Ты чего такой угрюмый? Может помощь требуется?</rus>
		<eng>Why are you so gloomy? Maybe you need some help?</eng>
		<ukr>Ти чого такий похмурий? Може допомога потрібна?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi es-tu si sombre? Peut-être avez-vous besoin d'aide?</fra>
		<pln>Coś taki ponury?... Może ci jakoś pomóc?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_1">
		<rus>А чего веселиться то? Тоскливо так, хоть в петлю...</rus>
		<eng>Is there a reason to have fun? It's depressing, I'm absolutely sick about it...</eng>
		<ukr>А чого веселитися то? Тоскно так, хоч в петлю...</ukr>
		<fra>Y a-t-il une raison de s'amuser? C'est déprimant, j'en ai absolument marre...</fra>
		<pln>A z czego tu się cieszyć? Smutno tak, że tylko się powiesić...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_2">
		<rus>Ну давай не пьянства ради, настроения для...</rus>
		<eng>Let's drink not for being drunk, but for setting the mood...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай не пияцтва ради, а настрою для....</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien,buvons pour préserver notre humeur, pour...</fra>
		<pln>No chodź, nie na pijaństwo, ale na pocieszenie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_3">
		<rus>А-а-а, Давай! Может полегчает...</rus>
		<eng>Ah, ok! Maybe I feel better...</eng>
		<ukr>А-а-а, Давай! Може полегшає...</ukr>
		<fra>Ah, d'accord! Peut-être que je me sentirais mieux...</fra>
		<pln>A-a-a, chodź! Może ulży trochę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_41">
		<rus>Так... Держи ровней... За НАДЕЖДУ!</rus>
		<eng>So... hold still... to the HOPE!</eng>
		<ukr>Так... Тримай рівніше... За НАДІЮ!</ukr>
		<fra>Alors ... restez calme ... et dans l'espoir!</fra>
		<pln>Tak... Trzymaj równo... Za NADZIEJĘ!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_42">
		<rus>Блин! НЕТУ! Помню точно - был пузырь! А НЕТУ!</rus>
		<eng>Damn! There is no! I remember for sure there was a bottle! But there is no!</eng>
		<ukr>Блін! НЕМАЄ! Пам'ятаю точно - була пляшка! А НЕМАЄ!</ukr>
		<fra>Zut! Il n'y a pas! Je me souviens bien qu'il y avait une bouteille! Mais il n'y a pas!</fra>
		<pln>Cholera! NIE MA! Pamiętam dobrze - była flaszka! A NIE MA!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_5">
		<rus>За неё, родимую... Спасибо тебе, не перевелись ещё настоящие мужики...</rus>
		<eng>To it, dear... Thanks to you, there are still real men...</eng>
		<ukr>За неї, рідну... Спасибі тобі, не перевелися ще справжні мужики...</ukr>
		<fra>Pour cela,merci ... Grâce à vous, il y a encore de vrais hommes...</fra>
		<pln>Za nią, rodzoną... Dziękuję ci, nie zginęły jeszcze prawdziwe chłopy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_6">
		<rus>Говорят - можно хабар найти недалеко, не слышал?</rus>
		<eng>They say, one can find loot nearby, did not you hear?</eng>
		<ukr>Кажуть - можна хабар знайти недалеко, не чув?</ukr>
		<fra>Ils disent - vous pouvez trouver un butin près, vous n'avez pas entendu?</fra>
		<pln>Mówią - że można znaleźć towar w okolicy, nie słyszałeś czego?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да, говорят есть нычка с хабаром, и даже не так далеко отсюда... Но кто ходил проверять - никто не вернулся. Давай покажу на карте - вот тут...</rus>
		<eng>Yes, they say there is a stash with loot, and even not so far from here... But those who went to check didn't come back. I can show it on the map - right here...</eng>
		<ukr>Так, кажуть є ничка з хабаром, і навіть не так далеко звідси... Але хто ходив перевіряти - ніхто не повернувся. Давай покажу на карті - ось тут...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, ils disent qu'il y a une cache avec un butin, et même pas si loin d'ici ... Mais qui est allé vérifier - personne n'est revenu. Montrons sur la carte - ici...</fra>
		<pln>Tak, mówią że jest skrytka z towarem, i nawet nie tak daleko stąd... Ale który poszedł sprawdzać - żaden nie wrócił. Daj, pokażę na mapie - o tu...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_73">
		<rus>Не-е, не слышал... Да я особо и не прислушиваюсь к трепачам...</rus>
		<eng>No, I did not hear... I do not listen to trash-talkers...</eng>
		<ukr>Ні-і, не чув... Та я особливо й не прислухаюся до базік...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, je n'ai pas entendu parler… Oui, je n'écoute pas vraiment les rumeurs...</fra>
		<pln>Nie-e, nie słyszałem... Ale ja raczej nie słucham plotek...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_81">
		<rus>Специально не полезу, но если поблизости буду - посмотрю...</rus>
		<eng>I won't go there intentionally, but if I'm around I'll see...</eng>
		<ukr>Спеціально не полізу, але якщо поблизу буду - подивлюся...</ukr>
		<fra>Je ne vais pas spécifiquement, mais si je suis dans les environs, je jetterai un coup d'œil...</fra>
		<pln>Specjalnie tam nie pójdę, ale jeśli będę w pobliżu - zajrzę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ну и правильно, меньше знаешь - крепче спишь...</rus>
		<eng>Well, right, curiosity killed the cat...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну і правильно, менше знаєш - краще спиш...</ukr>
		<fra>C'est vrai, moins vous en savez, vous dormez mieux...</fra>
		<pln>No i prawidłowo, mniej wiesz - lepiej śpisz...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорово, хлопец... Может сообразим?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, pal... What about splitting the bottle?</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, хлопець... Може щось придумаємо?</ukr>
		<fra>Bien, mon garçon ... Pouvons-nous résoudre ce problème?</fra>
		<pln>Czołem, kolego... Może pogadamy?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_1">
		<rus>Здорово... Об чём разговор...</rus>
		<eng>Hey... Sure thing...</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово... Про що розмова...</ukr>
		<fra>Bien ... De quoi parle-t-on...</fra>
		<pln>Czołem... A o czym...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_2">
		<rus>Посидим, языками потрепим под хорошую закуску...</rus>
		<eng>We'll sit, talk and snack...</eng>
		<ukr>Посидимо, язиками почешемо під гарну закуску...</ukr>
		<fra>Nous allons nous asseoir, parler et grignoter...</fra>
		<pln>Posiedzimy, językami potrzepiemy pod dobrą zakąskę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_3">
		<rus>Закусон с меня, давай, наливай, чего ждёшь?</rus>
		<eng>Snacks are on me, come on, pour, what are you waiting for?</eng>
		<ukr>Закусон з мене, давай, наливай, чого чекаєш?</ukr>
		<fra>Les collations sont ouvertes, allez, versez, versez...</fra>
		<pln>Zakąskę ja mam, a ty nalewaj, na co czekasz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_41">
		<rus>Вот она родимая, как слеза!</rus>
		<eng>Here it is, my precious, like a tear!</eng>
		<ukr>Ось вона рідна, як сльоза!</ukr>
		<fra>Le voici, mon précieux, comme une larme!</fra>
		<pln>Ech ta wódka, czysta jak łza!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_42">
		<rus>Закусон то есть... Её, родимой, нет...</rus>
		<eng>We have snacks... But there is no your precious...</eng>
		<ukr>Закусон то є... Її, рідної, нема...</ukr>
		<fra>Nous avons des collations ... Mais il n'y a pas de précieux...</fra>
		<pln>Zakąska to jest... Zakąszać nie ma czego...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_5">
		<rus>Хух, хороша! Аж до задницы пробрала... Гуд!</rus>
		<eng>Ooh, there is goes! It even reached my ass... Good!</eng>
		<ukr>Хух, хороша! Аж до дупи пробрало... Гуд!</ukr>
		<fra>Ooh, c'est parti! Il a même atteintet frappé ... Bien!</fra>
		<pln>Huh, doobra! Aż w plecy poszło... Uh!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_6">
		<rus>Их ферштеен... Чё слышно в Зоне?</rus>
		<eng>Ich verstehe... What's new in the Zone?</eng>
		<ukr>Іх ферштеєн... Що чутно в зоні?</ukr>
		<fra>Tant d'années ... Qu’entend-on dans la zone?</fra>
		<pln>Co tam w Zonie?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_71">
		<rus>Позавчера с солдатиками раздавили пару пузырей... Посидели... Они с Агропрома, частенько сюда бегают, Сидор их водочкой снабжает... Так они рассказали, что поймали зомбированного сталкера, ну сам понимаешь, тот мычит и за пушку хватается. Командир приказал живьём брать, этим яйцеголовым на большую землю отправить - для опытов, да... По мне лучше бы сразу пулю в висок и всё... Да, про что я? А-а ну вот, у этого зомби прямо на руке рисунок был, типа татуировки, но не настоящей, а так, вроде кто ножом вырезал... Карта как будто... Их командир сверился с приметами - и похоже недалеко от сюда схрон с хабаром... Примерно вот здесь...</rus>
		<eng>The day before yesterday we drank some bottles with soldiers... They often come here from Agroprom, Sidor supplies them with vodka... So they told that they caught a zombified stalker, well, you know, he mumbled and grabbed the gun. The commander ordered to take them alive and send to eggheads to the mainland for experiments... I think it would be better to immediately blow out their brains... So what was I talking about? Ah, well, this zombie had a picture on its arm, like a tattoo, but not real, like someone carved it with a knife... It looked like a map... Their commander checked the map and it seems there is a stash with loot not far from here... Somewhere here...</eng>
		<ukr>Позавчора з солдатиками розчавили пару пляшок... Посиділи... Вони з Агопрома, частенько сюди бігають, Сидор їх горілочкою постачає... Так вони розповіли, що спіймали зомбованого сталкера, ну сам розумієш, той мукає і за пушку хапається. Командир наказав живцем брати, цим яйцеголовим на велику землю відправити - для дослідів, так... Як на мене краще б відразу кулю в скроню і все... Так, про що я? А-а ну от, у цього зомбі прямо на руці малюнок був, типу татуювання, але не справжнього, а так, начебто хто ножем вирізав... Карта начебто.. Їх командир звірився з прикметами - і схоже недалеко звідсіля схрон з хабаром... Приблизно ось тут...</ukr>
		<fra>Avant-hier, ils ont bu quelques bouteilles avec les soldats ... Nous nous sommes assis ... ils sont d'Agroprom, ils courent souvent ici, Sidor leur fournit de la vodka ... Alors ils ont dit qu'ils avaient attrapé un traqueur de zombies, eh bien, vous savez, il mugit et se cramponnait . Le Commandant a ordonné de le prendre vivant, de l'envoyer sur le continent - pour des expériences, oui ... Il vaudrait mieux que je tire immédiatement une balle dans le temple et tout le reste ... Oui, de quoi est-ce que je parle? Ah, eh bien, ce zombie avait un dessin sur la main, semblable à un tatouage, mais pas réel, mais comme ça, il a découpé un couteau ... La carte semblait être ... Leur commandant a vérifié les signes - et cela ressemble à des caches pas très loin d'ici avec un butin ... à propos de ici ...</fra>
		<pln>Przedwczoraj z wojakami parę flaszek wysuszyliśmy... Posiedzieliśmy... Oni są z Agropromu, często tutaj bywają, Sidor ich w wódeczkę zaopatruje... Opowiadali, że złapali zzombifikowanego stalkera, ale sam rozumiesz, on tylko muczy i za giwerę łapie. Dowódca kazał żywcem brać, tym jajogłowym na "Wielką Ziemię" wysłać - dla doświadczeń, taa... Według mnie lepiej by od razu kula w łeb i koniec... Tak, o czym to ja?... A-a no tak, u tego zombie na ręku rysunek był, coś w rodzaju tatuażu, ale nie prawdziwego, a tak, jakby kto nożem wydziergał... Jakby mapa.. Ich dowódca mówi, że to wyglądało na koordynaty schowka... Mniej więcej gdzieś tutaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_73">
		<rus>Много чего слышно, про аномалии, про монстров, всего не перескажешь сразу, подходи ещё, поговорим...</rus>
		<eng>There are a lot of things about anomalies, monsters, it's impossible to tell everything at once, come later and we'll talk...</eng>
		<ukr>Багато чого чутно, про аномалії, про монстрів, все не перекажеш відразу, підходь ще, поговоримо...</ukr>
		<fra>Vous pouvez entendre beaucoup de choses sur les anomalies, sur les monstres, vous ne vous en souviendrez pas tout de suite, revenez, parlons-en...</fra>
		<pln>Czego to nie gadają, o anomaliach, o potworach, na raz wszystkiego nie opowiesz, przychodź jeszcze, pogadamy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_81">
		<rus>Да блин, лучше сразу... без мучений...</rus>
		<eng>Yes, it would be better at once... without suffering...</eng>
		<ukr>Так блін, краще відразу... без мук...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, ce serait mieux tout de suite ... sans souffrir...</fra>
		<pln>Prawda, cholera, lepiej od razu... bez męczarni...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_82">
		<rus>Подойду, поговорим...</rus>
		<eng>I'll come and talk...</eng>
		<ukr>Підійду, поговоримо...</ukr>
		<fra>iens, parlons-en...</fra>
		<pln>Przyjdę, pogadamy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорово, братан... Как тут у вас?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, bro... How are you here?</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, братан... Як тут у вас?</ukr>
		<fra>Bien, mon frère ... comment ça va avec toi?</fra>
		<pln>Czołem, bratku... Jak tu u was?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_1">
		<rus>Мутанты иногда валят... А так вроде нормуль всё...</rus>
		<eng>Mutants beat sometimes... Not bad, in general...</eng>
		<ukr>Мутанти іноді валять... А так начебто нормуль все...</ukr>
		<fra>Des mutants sont parfois abattus ... C’est donc tout à fait normal...</fra>
		<pln>Mutanty czasem się kręcą... A tak w sumie to normalnie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_2">
		<rus>Давай за знакомство? Или начальство не велит?</rus>
		<eng>How about a drink to our meeting? Or the heads don't let you?</eng>
		<ukr>Давай за знайомство? Чи начальство не велить?</ukr>
		<fra>Que diriez-vous d'un verre à notre réunion?Faisons connaissance avec vous? Ou les autorités commandent?</fra>
		<pln>Możemy za znajomość?... A może dowództwo nie pozwala?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_3">
		<rus>Да какое начальство... Прапор наш - старый служивый, понимает, что в Зоне без этого нельзя. Так что не межуйся - наливай.</rus>
		<eng>What kind of heads are you talking about?... Our Prapor, an old soldier, understands that it is impossible without it in the Zone. So do not worry, pour.</eng>
		<ukr>Та яке начальство... Прапор наш - старий служивий, розуміє, що в Зоні без цього не можна. Так що не межуйся - наливай.</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, quels patrons ... Notre enseigne - le vieux soldat, comprend que dans la zone, il est impossible sans lui. Donc, ne pas entre - verser.</fra>
		<pln>Jakie tam dowództwo... Nasz Prapor - stary wojak, rozumie, że w Zonie bez tego ani rusz. Czyli nie krępuj się - nalewaj.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ну! За хороших людей!</rus>
		<eng>Well, to good people!</eng>
		<ukr>Ну! За хороших людей!</ukr>
		<fra>Bien! Pour les bonnes personnes!</fra>
		<pln>No! Za dobrych ludzi!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_42">
		<rus>Налил бы, да последнюю поллитру пришлось потратить на здоровье...</rus>
		<eng>I would pour, but I had to use the last bottle for my health...</eng>
		<ukr>Налив б, та останню півлітру довелося витратити на здоров'я...</ukr>
		<fra>Je le remplirais, mais le dernier demi-litre devait être consacré à la santé...</fra>
		<pln>Nalałbyś, bo ostatnią połówkę trzeba było stracić na odkażanie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_5">
		<rus>За нас то есть! Закусывай, вот колбаса...</rus>
		<eng>It means to us! Have a snack, here's sausage...</eng>
		<ukr>За нас тобто! Закушуй, ось ковбаса...</ukr>
		<fra>Cela signifie pour nous! Prenez une collation, voici la saucisse...</fra>
		<pln>Za nas to jest! Zakąszaj, tu jest kiełbasa...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_6">
		<rus>Спасибо... Что слышно здесь? Может какие новости?</rus>
		<eng>Thank you... What's new here? Maybe there are some news?</eng>
		<ukr>Спасибі.. Що чути тут? Може які новини?</ukr>
		<fra>Merci ... Qu'est-ce qui est entendu ici? Peut-être des nouvelles?</fra>
		<pln>Dziękuję.. Co słychać? Jakieś nowości?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_71">
		<rus>Особенных новостей нет... Но, про Макса Любера слышал? Поймали его с корефаном бандюки из Тёмной Долины... Пуля - друган Любера, по следу пошёл... А перед этим сказал что корефан Макса карту успел сбросить, на которой место обозначено с хабаром заныканым... Вот! Пуля просил сгонять кому-нибудь туда, но Прапор не разрешил - мол и так бойцов на посту мало осталось... В общем, вот это место, забери, чтобы бандитам не досталось...</rus>
		<eng>Nothing special... But did you hear about Max Lyuber? He and his bro were caught by bandits from Dark Valley... Bullet, Lyuber's friend followed tracks... And before that he said that Max's bro had sent the map, on which the place with the stash was marked... Here! Bullet wanted someone to go there, but Prapor did not allow as there are very few soldiers left at watch... So here is this place, take it for bandits not to get it...</eng>
		<ukr>Особливих новин немає.. Але, про Макса Любера чув? Спіймали його з корефаном бандюки з темної долини... Куля - друган Любера, по сліду пішов... А перед цим сказав що корефан Макса карту встиг скинути, на якій місце позначене з хабаром заниканим... Ось! Куля просив зганяти кому небудь туди, але Прапор відмовив - мовляв і так бійців на посту мало залишилося... Загалом, ось це місце, забери, щоб бандитам не дісталося...</ukr>
		<fra>Il n'y a pas de nouvelles en particulier ... Mais avez-vous entendu parler de Max Liouber? Bandits de la Vallée obscure l'a attrapé avec Corefan ... Balle était un ami de Liouber, il a suivi la piste ... Et avant cela, il a dit que Corefan Max avait eu le temps de se débarrasser de l'endroit marqué avec une cache indiquée ... Ici! Balle a demandé de conduire quelqu'un là-bas, mais Prapor ne l’a pas autorisé - ils disent qu’il ne reste que peu de soldats sur le poste ... En général, prenez cet endroit, afin que les bandits ne reçoivent pas...</fra>
		<pln>Szczególnych nowości nie ma.. Ale, o Maksie Luberze słyszałeś? Złapali go z towarzyszem bandyci z Doliny Mroku... Nabój - przyjaciel Lubera, poszedł za nimi... A przed tym powiedział, że towarzysz Maksa zdążył upuścić mapę, na której zaznaczone jest miejsce z schowanym towarem... No! Nabój prosił, żeby ktoś tam poszedł, ale Prapor nie pozwolił - i tak mało zostało ludzi na posterunku... Jakby co, to tu jest to miejsce, zabierz, żeby bandytom się nie dostało...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_73">
		<rus>Вроде не слышал ничего особенного, так, по мелочи...</rus>
		<eng>I did not hear anything special, just little things...</eng>
		<ukr>Начебто не чув нічого особливого, так, дрібниці...</ukr>
		<fra>Je n'ai rien entendu de spécial, juste de petites choses...</fra>
		<pln>Jakoś nie słyszałem niczego specjalnego, takie tam...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_81">
		<rus>Ладно, заберу...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, I'll take it...</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, заберу...</ukr>
		<fra>D'accord, je vais le prendre...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, wezmę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ну покеда пока, ещё увидимся...</rus>
		<eng>Then bye, see you...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну покеда поки, ще побачимося...</ukr>
		<fra>Alors au revoir, à bientôt...</fra>
		<pln>No to na razie, jeszcze się zobaczymy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_0">
		<rus>Приветствую, служивый!</rus>
		<eng>Hello, soldier!</eng>
		<ukr>Вітаю, служивий!</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour soldat!</fra>
		<pln>Pozdrowienia, żołnierzu!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_1">
		<rus>И тебе туда же... Ты откуда такой нарисовался?</rus>
		<eng>Hey... Where did you come from?</eng>
		<ukr>І тобі туди ж... Ти звідки такий намалювався?</ukr>
		<fra>Et pour vous là-bas ... Où avez-vous eu cela?</fra>
		<pln>I ciebie tutaj... A skąd żeś się tu wziął?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_2">
		<rus>Да так, потихоньку топчу Зону... Ты как насчёт ста грамм?</rus>
		<eng>So far, so good, hanging about in the Zone... What about 100 grams?</eng>
		<ukr>Та так, потихеньку топчу Зону... Ти як щодо ста грам?</ukr>
		<fra>Oh, alors, piétinez lentement la zone ... Que diriez-vous d'une centaine de grammes?</fra>
		<pln>A tak, po cichutku drepczę po Zonie... Co powiesz na sto gram?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_3">
		<rus>Что за вопрос! Двести грамм ещё никому не повредили...</rus>
		<eng>Why! 200 grams have not hurt anyone yet...</eng>
		<ukr>Що за питання! Двісті грам ще нікому не зашкодили...</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi! 200 grammes n'ont encore blessé personne...</fra>
		<pln>Też pytanie! Dwieście gram jeszcze nikomu nie zaszkodziło...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_41">
		<rus>Держи двести пятьдесят и без закуски...</rus>
		<eng>Take 250 and without snacks...</eng>
		<ukr>Тримай двісті п'ятдесят і без закуски...</ukr>
		<fra>Prenez 250 et sans collations...</fra>
		<pln>Trzymaj dwieście pięćdziesiąt i bez zakąski...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_42">
		<rus>Я щас арты Бармену свалю и вернусь...</rus>
		<eng>===Wait, I'll go to Barkeep to exchange some artifacts and come back...</eng>
		<ukr>Я зара арти Бармену звалю і повернуся...</ukr>
		<fra>===Attendez, je vais y retourner... Je vais avoir l’art du Barman maintenant et je reviens...</fra>
		<pln>Ja tylko arty Barmanowi podrzucę i wracam...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_5">
		<rus>Ха, нормуль пошла... На кой закусывать такой нектар...</rus>
		<eng>Ha, it goes well... Why should I eat something after this nectar...</eng>
		<ukr>Ха, нормуль пішла... Навіщо закушувати такий нектар...</ukr>
		<fra>Ha, ça va bien ... Pourquoi devrais-je manger quelque chose après ce nectar...</fra>
		<pln>Ha, prawidłowo poszła... Nie ma co zakąszać takiego nektaru...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_6">
		<rus>Это точно, добро на г... переводить только... Расскажи чё-нить...</rus>
		<eng>That's right, why should we waste it... Tell me something...</eng>
		<ukr>Це точно, добро на г... переводити тільки... Розкажи що-небудь...</ukr>
		<fra>Bien sûr, bienvenue dans votre ... traduction uniquement ... Dites-moi quel est le fil de discussion...</fra>
		<pln>Co racja, to racja... szkoda smak psuć... Opowiedz coś...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_71">
		<rus>На днях Бес тут гостил, хороший мужик, хоть и одиночка... Без обид, ладно? Мы ему немного с патронами помогли, поговорили о том, о сём... У него ничего ценного не было, так он рассказал о найденном схроне. Хабара правда там не было, но судя по приметам там часто кто то прячет добро. Если есть желание - разведай, чья она...</rus>
		<eng>Fiend stayed here the other day, a good man, though a loner... No offense meant, but we helped him with ammo a little, had a small talk... He had nothing valuable, but he told us about the found stash. There was no loot there, but according to some signs someone often hides goods there. If you want, scout out whose it is...</eng>
		<ukr>Днями Біс тут гостював, хороший мужик, хоч і одинак... Без образ, добре? Ми йому трохи з патронами допомогли, поговорили про те про се... У нього нічого цінного не було, так він розповів про знайдений схрон. Хабара правда там не було, але судячи за прикметами там часто хтось ховає добро. Якщо є бажання - розвідай, чий він...</ukr>
		<fra>L’autre jour, Démon était ici, un homme bon, même s’il était solitaire ... Pas d’offense, d'accord? Nous l'avons un peu aidé avec les cartouches, avons parlé de ça, de ça… Il n'avait rien de précieux, alors il a parlé des caches trouvées. Swag n'était vraiment pas là, mais à en juger par les signes, quelqu'un cache souvent quelque chose de bon. S'il y a un désir, savoir à qui il appartient ...</fra>
		<pln>Na dniach gościł tu Bies, równy gość, chociaż samotnik... Bez obrazy, dobra?... Trochę mu z amunicją pomogliśmy, pogadaliśmy o tym o tamtym... Niczego cennego nie miał, ale opowiedział o znalezionym schowku. Towaru wprawdzie tam nie było, ale sądząc po wszystkim, tam ktoś często jakieś dobro chowa. Jeśli masz chęć - zajrzyj, co tam się dzieje...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_73">
		<rus>Да чё рассказывать.. Зона, она Зона и есть, если бы не мы - давно бы зараза по всему миру расползлась...</rus>
		<eng>I don't know what to tell.. Zone is Zone, without us the infection would have spread all over the world long ago...</eng>
		<ukr>Та що розповідати.. Зона, вона Зона і є, якби не ми - давно б зараза по всьому світу розповзлася...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, que dire… Zone, c’est la Zone, sinon pour nous, l’infection se serait répandue dans le monde entier il y a bien longtemps...</fra>
		<pln>I co tu opowiadać.. Zona, to Zona i tyle,  gdyby nie my - dawno by zaraza po całym świecie się rozlazła...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_81">
		<rus>Попробую разведать...</rus>
		<eng>I'll try to find out...</eng>
		<ukr>Спробую розвідати...</ukr>
		<fra>Je vais essayer de repérer...</fra>
		<pln>Spróbuję zajrzeć...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ну бывай, спаситель мира...</rus>
		<eng>Good luck, world-saver...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну бувай, спаситель світу...</ukr>
		<fra>Bien sûr...Bonne chance le Sauveur du monde...</fra>
		<pln>No to bywaj, zbawco świata...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет мужик, что-то лицо твоё знакомо, мы раньше не встречались?</rus>
		<eng>Hey man, your face looks familiar, haven't we met before?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт мужик, щось обличчя твоє знайоме, ми раніше не зустрічалися?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour mec, votre visage vous est-il familier? Avons-nous déjà rencontré?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, twoja twarz jest jakby znajoma, czy myśmy się wcześniej nie spotkali?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_1">
		<rus>А кто его знает, я только тех, с кем дружен помню...</rus>
		<eng>Who knows, I remember only those who I often meet...</eng>
		<ukr>А хто його знає, я тільки тих, з ким дружив пам'ятаю...</ukr>
		<fra>Et qui sait, je ne me souviens que de ceux que je rencontre souvent...Je ne me souviens que de mes amis!</fra>
		<pln>A kto to może wiedzieć, ja tylko tych pamiętam, z którymi się przyjaźnię...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_2">
		<rus>Ну давай, не пьянства окаянного ради, дружбы для...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, not for getting drunk but to our friendship...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай, не пияцтва окаянного заради, а дружби для...</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, pas pour ivre mais pour notre amitié...</fra>
		<pln>No to dawaj, nie dla pijaństwa przeklętego, ale dla przyjaźni...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_3">
		<rus>Ну вот, вроде вспоминаю... Давай, наливай!</rus>
		<eng>Well, it's coming back to me... Come on, pour!</eng>
		<ukr>Ну от, начебто згадую... Давай, наливай!</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, en quelque sorte, souvenez-vous ... Allez, versez!</fra>
		<pln>Aha, jakbym sobie przypominał... No to polewaj!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_41">
		<rus>Так... Держи ровней... За Дружбу!</rus>
		<eng>So... Hold still... To Friendship!</eng>
		<ukr>Так... Тримай рівніше... За Дружбу!</ukr>
		<fra>Alors ... Tenez-vous tranquille et gardez votre niveau... à l'amitié!</fra>
		<pln>Tak... Trzymaj równiej... Za Przyjaźń!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_42">
		<rus>Блин! НЕТУ! Помню точно - был пузырь! А НЕТУ!</rus>
		<eng>Damn! There is no! I remember for sure there was a bottle! But there is no!</eng>
		<ukr>Блін! НЕМАЄ! Пам'ятаю точно - була пляшка! А НЕМАЄ!</ukr>
		<fra>Zut! Il n'y a pas! Je me souviens bien qu'il y avait une bouteille! Mais il n'y a pas!</fra>
		<pln>Diabli! NIE MA! Pamiętam dobrze - była flaszka! A NIE MA!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_5">
		<rus>За надёжных друзей! С которыми даже в Зоне не пропадёшь!</rus>
		<eng>To reliable friends! With whom you'll be all right even in the Zone!</eng>
		<ukr>За надійних друзів! З якими навіть в Зоні не пропадеш!</ukr>
		<fra>Pour des amis fiables! Avec qui même dans la zone tu ne seras pas perdu!</fra>
		<pln>Za dobrych przyjaciół! Z którymi nawet w Zonie nie przepadniesz!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_6">
		<rus>Говорят - можно хабар найти недалеко, не слышал?</rus>
		<eng>They say one can find a stash not far from here, did you hear?</eng>
		<ukr>Кажуть - можна хабар знайти недалеко, не чув?</ukr>
		<fra>Ils disent - vous pouvez trouver un butin près, vous n'avez pas entendu?</fra>
		<pln>Nie słyszałeś, czy można tu jakiś towar znaleźć w pobliżu?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_71">
		<rus>Никому не говорил, но тебе, как другу скажу. Есть наводка на нычку одну... Случайно узнал про неё... Может там и нет ничего, а может хабара дофигища. Если ты настоящий друг, то поделишься я думаю?</rus>
		<eng>I did not tell anyone, but you're my friend, so I'll tell you. There is a tip-off about the stash... I accidentally learned about it... Maybe there's nothing or a lot of loot there. If you are a real friend, then you will share, right?</eng>
		<ukr>Нікому не говорив, але тобі, як другові скажу. Є наводка на ничку одну... Випадково дізнався про неї... Може там і немає нічого, а може хабара дофігіща. Якщо ти справжній друг, то поділишся я думаю?</ukr>
		<fra>Je n'ai rien dit à personne, mais je vais vous le dire en tant qu'ami. Il y a une astuce sur une petite chose ... J'ai découvert par hasard à son sujet ... Peut-être n'y a-t-il rien, ou peut-être une cache du Devoir. Si vous êtes un véritable ami, vais-je le partager?</fra>
		<pln>Nikomu nie mówiłem, ale tobie, jak przyjacielowi, powiem. Jest wskazówka na jedną skrytkę... Przypadkiem się o niej dowiedziałem... Może tam nie ma niczego, a może towaru od metra. Jeśli jesteś prawdziwym przyjacielem, to się podzielisz, nie?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_73">
		<rus>Не-е, не слышал... Собрали все что поблизости было, а что там дальше - только Стрелок знает...</rus>
		<eng>No, I did not hear... We collected everything that was nearby, I guess only Strelok knows about it...</eng>
		<ukr>Ні-і, не чув... Зібрали все що поблизу було, а що там далі - тільки Стрілець знає...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, je n'ai pas entendu dire ... Ils ont rassemblé tout ce qui se trouvait à proximité et la prochaine étape est que j'ai pensé au fait que Strelok le sache...</fra>
		<pln>Nie-e, nie słyszałem... W pobliżu wszystko wyzbierane, a co tam dalej - tylko Striełok wie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_81">
		<rus>Об чём разговор! Для друга ничего не жалко...</rus>
		<eng>Sure! Nothing is too good for my friend...</eng>
		<ukr>Про що розмова! Для друга нічого не шкода...</ukr>
		<fra>Bien sûr! Rien n'est trop beau pour mon ami...</fra>
		<pln>Co ty mówisz! Dla przyjaciela niczego nie żal...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_82">
		<rus>Стрелок? Ну, ну... Есть у меня к нему вопрос, другой...</rus>
		<eng>Strelok? Well, well... I have a question for him...</eng>
		<ukr>Стрілець? Ну, ну... Є у мене до нього питання, два...</ukr>
		<fra>Strelok? Eh bien, bien ... j'ai une question pour lui...</fra>
		<pln>Striełok? No, no... Mam do niego parę pytań...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет, поговорим, не против?</rus>
		<eng>Hi, can we talk?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт, поговоримо, не проти?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour, pouvons-nous parler?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, pogadajmy, dobra?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_1">
		<rus>Присаживайся... О чём разговор...</rus>
		<eng>Sit down... What's the matter...</eng>
		<ukr>Сідай... Про що розмова...</ukr>
		<fra>Asseyez-vous ... Quelle est la conversation...</fra>
		<pln>Siadaj... O czym chcesz pogadać...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_2">
		<rus>Может для смазки по пять капель?</rus>
		<eng>What about a drink?</eng>
		<ukr>Може для змащення по п'ять крапель?</ukr>
		<fra>Qu'en est-il d'un verre?</fra>
		<pln>Może dla zdrowia po kilka kropelek?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_3">
		<rus>Закусон с меня, давай, наливай, чего ждёшь?</rus>
		<eng>Snacks are on me, come on, pour, what are you waiting for?</eng>
		<ukr>Закусон з мене, давай, наливай, чого чекаєш?</ukr>
		<fra>Les collations sont ouvertes, allez, versez, versez...</fra>
		<pln>Zakąskę mam... dobra, lej, na co czekasz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_41">
		<rus>Держи стаканы ровней, а то краёв не увижу...</rus>
		<eng>Hold the glasses still, otherwise it will overflow...</eng>
		<ukr>Тримай стакани рівніше, а то країв не побачу...</ukr>
		<fra>Tenez les lunettes à un niveau, sinon je ne verrai pas les bords...</fra>
		<pln>Trzymaj szklanki równiej, bo brzegów nie widzę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_42">
		<rus>Закусон то есть... Её, родимой, нет...</rus>
		<eng>We have snacks... But we don't have our precious...</eng>
		<ukr>Закусон то є... Її, рідної, нема...</ukr>
		<fra>Nous avons des collations ... mais nous n’avons pas notre précieux...</fra>
		<pln>Zakąska jest... Tylko wódeczki nie ma...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_5">
		<rus>Жжёшь... О-о-о! Смазало как маслом...</rus>
		<eng>Ooh! It's burning like fire...</eng>
		<ukr>Жжош... О-о-о! Змастило як маслом...</ukr>
		<fra>Ooh! Il brûle comme un feu...</fra>
		<pln>O-żesz... Po-o-szło! Balsam...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_6">
		<rus>Не тоскливо тут целыми днями сидеть?</rus>
		<eng>Aren't you bored to sit here all day?</eng>
		<ukr>Чи не тоскно тут цілими днями сидіти?</ukr>
		<fra>N’est-il pas déprimant de rester ici toute la journée?</fra>
		<pln>Nie smutno tu całymi dniami siedzieć?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да нет, чего тосковать то? Закуску Бармен подкатывает, типа платит за охрану... Одиночки часто проходят, последними сведениями делятся... Опять же пострелять есть по чему... \nХохма - братки последнее время оборзели, подставы устраивают... Так вот - лежит один, раненным сталкером прикидывается, шлёт СОС по всем частотам. А тут пара бюреров на него нарвались... Этот "раненый" как только услышал их вопли, ноги в руки и понёсся не разбирая дороги... Влетел прямо к нам и с разбега в подпорку навеса - хрясь! Шум, треск, вонь - этот любитель лёгкого хабара обделался по самые уши... Потом все трясся и обещал всех озолотить, мол хабар спрятал и отметку на карту поставил... Чудак ей богу... У нас никто задницей рисковать не будет за какой-то там хабар. Мы заслон! Защищаем мир от нечисти... Если интересно - вот здесь эта его отметка...</rus>
		<eng>Not at all. Barkeep gives some snacks as payment for security... Loners often come and share news... There is something to shoot at... \nHoot - bros haven't been out of line recently, set up... For example, one was lying pretending to be a wounded stalker and sending SOS on all frequencies. And then a couple of burers saw him... As soon as this "wounded" heard their screams, he broke into a run... flew directly into our place and butted up against a pole - Bang! Noise, crack, pong - this lover of easy loot shitted his pants... Then he was shaking and promised to make everyone rich, as he hid some loot and made a mark on the map... Weirdo... Nobody will risk their butts for something like that. We are a covering force! We protect the world from evil spirits... If you are interested, here is this mark...</eng>
		<ukr>Та ні, чого тужити то? Закуску Бармен підкочує, типу платить за охорону... Одиночки часто проходять, останніми відомостями діляться... Знову ж таки постріляти є по чому...\nХохма - братки останнім часом оборзіли, підстави влаштовують... Так ось - лежить один, пораненим сталкером прикидається, шле СОС по всіх частотах. А тут пара бюрерів на нього нарвалася... Цей "поранений" як тільки почув їх крики, ноги в руки і понісся не розбираючи дороги... Влетів прямо до нас і з розбігу в підпору навісу - хрясь! Шум, тріск, сморід - цей любитель легких хабарів обробився по самі вуха... Потім все трясся і обіцяв усіх озолотити, мовляв хабар сховав і відмітку на карту поставив... Дивак їй богу... У нас ніхто дупою ризикувати не буде за якийсь там хабар. Ми заслін! Захищаємо світ від нечисті... Якщо цікаво - ось тут ця його відмітка...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, à quoi aspirer? Le Barman prend une collation, c'est comme payer la sécurité ... Les solitaires passent souvent, ils partagent les dernières informations ... Encore une fois, il y a quelque chose pour lequel il faut tirer ... \ nHomme - Les frères se sont enlisés, ils se préparent ... Maintenant, il y en a un, blessé Stalker prétend envoyer SOS à toutes les fréquences. Et puis quelques burers l'ont rencontré ... Ce "blessé" dès qu'il a entendu leurs cris, les jambes en main, et s'est précipité sans casser la route ... Il a volé directement vers nous et de la course au support de la canopée - Bruit, craquements, puanteur - cet amoureux d’un léger butin le faisait jusqu’à ses oreilles ... Puis il a tout secoué et a promis de remonter le moral à tout le monde, en disant que le butin le cachait et portait une marque sur la carte ... L’excentrique à son dieu ... Nous ne risquons pas notre âne une prétendue cache. Nous sommes une barrière! Nous protégeons le monde des mauvais esprits ... Si cela est intéressant,voilà où c'est, c’est sa marque...</fra>
		<pln>A nie, czym znowu się smucić? Zakąskę Barman zapewnia, znaczy płaci za ochronę... Samotnicy często przechodzą, najnowsze wieści przynoszą... Postrzelać też jest do czego... \nHumor też jest - braciaki ostatnio dojrzeli, nowe pomysły ugruntowują... No na przykład, leży jeden, rannego stalkera udaje, wysyła SOS na wszystkich kanałach. A tu para burerów na niego trafiła... Ten "ranny" jak tylko usłyszał ich zawodzenie, nogi za pas i grzeje, nie wybiera drogi... Wypadł prosto na nas i z rozpędu w słupek daszka - trach! Wrzask, trzask, smród - bo ten amator łatwych zdobyczy obsrał się po pas... Potem ciągle się trząsł i obiecywał wszystkich ozłocić, bo niby towar schował i znacznik na mapie zrobił... Cudak, że hej... U nas nikt tyłka ryzykować nie będzie za jakiś tam towar. My jesteśmy zaporą! Chronimy świat od paskudztwa... Jeśliś ciekaw - tu jest ten jego znacznik na mapie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_73">
		<rus>Тоскливо конечно, но зато чувствуешь себя при деле - Мир от нечисти защищаем!</rus>
		<eng>It's boring, of course, but you have a sense of purpose - we protect the world from evil!</eng>
		<ukr>Тоскливо звичайно, але зате відчуваєш себе при справі - Світ від нечисті захищаємо!</ukr>
		<fra>Malheureusement, bien sûr, mais vous vous sentez en affaires: défendre le monde des esprits diaboliques!</fra>
		<pln>Pewnie  że smutno, ale za to masz poczucie misji - Świat przed paskudztwem bronimy!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_81">
		<rus>Да, повеселил... Гляну при случае, хотя думаю - лажа это...</rus>
		<eng>Yeah, that's funny... I'll check on occasion, although I think it is crap...</eng>
		<ukr>Так, повеселив... Гляну при нагоді, хоча думаю - лажа це...</ukr>
		<fra>Ouais, c'est marrant ... Je vais vérifier à l'occasion, même si je pense que c'est pas terrible comme truc...</fra>
		<pln>No, uśmiałem się... Zajrzę przy okazji, chociaż myślę - że to bajki...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ну тогда не буду отвлекать героя...</rus>
		<eng>Then I will not distract the hero...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну тоді не буду відволікати героя...</ukr>
		<fra>Alors je ne vais pas distraire le héros...</fra>
		<pln>No, to już nie będę przeszkadzać bohaterowi...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет, братишка... Как жизнь?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, brother... How's life?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт, братику... Як життя?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour mon frère ... comment vas-tu?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, bratku... Jak żyjesz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_1">
		<rus>Бандиты задрали, блин! Никаких нервов не хватит! Лезут и лезут!</rus>
		<eng>Bandits got under my skin, damn it! My nerves can't take much more of this! They are constantly annoying me!</eng>
		<ukr>Бандити задрали, блін! Ніяких нервів не вистачить! Лізуть і лізуть!</ukr>
		<fra>Les bandits ont ma peau, bon sang! Mes nerfs ne peuvent pas supporter beaucoup plus de ça! Ils m'agacent constamment!</fra>
		<pln>Bandyci napierają, cholera! Już nerwów brakuje! Lezą i lezą!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_2">
		<rus>Сбрось пар... Давай расслабимся немного...</rus>
		<eng>Take it easy... Let's relax a bit...</eng>
		<ukr>Скинь пар... Давай розслабимося трохи...</ukr>
		<fra>Prenez votre temps ... détendons-nous un peu...</fra>
		<pln>Odpuść trochę... Zróbmy sobie chwilę relaksu...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_3">
		<rus>Да я не кипячусь, просто давно нормальной выпивки не было... Наливай, раз предложил...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, I just haven't had a normal drink for a long time... Pour, if you offered...</eng>
		<ukr>Та я не кип'ячу, просто давно нормальної випивки не було... Наливай, раз запропонував...</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, je bois un verre depuis longtemps ... Versez, si vous offriez...</fra>
		<pln>Ja się nie denerwuję, po prostu dawno normalnej wypitki nie było... Nalewaj, skoro proponujesz...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_41">
		<rus>Давай за завтрашний день, чтобы увидеть его!</rus>
		<eng>Let's drink to tomorrow, for us to see it!</eng>
		<ukr>Давай за завтрашній день, щоб побачити його!</ukr>
		<fra>Venez demain pour le voir!Buvons à demain!</fra>
		<pln>Za jutrzejszy dzień, żebyśmy go doczekali!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_42">
		<rus>Сейчас у самого пусто, хабаром притарюсь - возьму у барыг...</rus>
		<eng>I have nothing now, I'll take some from wheeler-dealers...</eng>
		<ukr>Зараз у самого порожньо, хабаром затарюсь - візьму у бариг...</ukr>
		<fra>Je n'ai rien maintenant - je vais prendre dans la réserve...</fra>
		<pln>Teraz u mnie pusto, jak towaru załapię - wezmę u handlarza...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_5">
		<rus>Давай! За смерть от старости!</rus>
		<eng>Ok! To the death in old age!</eng>
		<ukr>Давай! За смерть від старості!</ukr>
		<fra>Allez! Pour la mort de la vieillesse!</fra>
		<pln>Dawaj! Za śmierć ze starości!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_6">
		<rus>Во-от... Отпустило малёх... Что говорят?</rus>
		<eng>Well... Now it's better... What do they say?</eng>
		<ukr>О-о-ось... Відпустило трохи... Що говорять?</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien ... Maintenant, c'est mieux ... Que disent-ils?</fra>
		<pln>Uf-f... Odpuściło trochę... Co powiadają?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_71">
		<rus>Все стараются при себе держать свои мысли, ЗОНА брат... Но я как то слышал, что пара ребят уходя от военных бросила свой хабар... Собирался сам поживиться, да думаю не доберусь туда... Так что, если хочешь - пользуйся, иначе пропадёт совсем - тех ребят на днях бандиты положили в очередном набеге... А жаль, хорошие были сталкеры, свои в доску...</rus>
		<eng>Everyone tries to keep their thoughts to themselves, it's the ZONE bro... But I heard that a couple of guys leaving the military threw their loot... I was going to take it myself, but I think I won't reach... So if you want, use, otherwise it will disappear - those guys have been recently captured by bandits... It's a pity they were good stalkers, blood brothers...</eng>
		<ukr>Усі намагаються при собі тримати свої думки, ЗОНА брат... Але я якось чув, що пара хлопців йдучи від військових кинула свій хабар... Збирався сам поживитися, та думаю не доберуся туди... Так що, якщо хочеш - користуйся, інакше пропаде зовсім - тих хлопців днями бандити поклали в черговому набігу... А жаль, хороші були сталкери, свої в дошку...</ukr>
		<fra>Tout le monde essaie de garder leurs pensées avec eux, frère de ZONE ... Mais de toute façon, j’ai entendu dire que quelques gars qui quittaient l’Armée avaient laissé leur butin ... Il allait en tirer profit, mais je pense que je n’y arriverai pas ... Alors, si si vous voulez - utilisez-le, sinon il disparaîtra complètement - ces gars-là ont récemment été mis dans le prochain raid ... Et dommage que les Stalkers soient bons, ils étaient sur le tableau ...</fra>
		<pln>Wszyscy swoje myśli starają się trzymać przy sobie, ZONA bracie... Ale ja słyszałem, że para chłopaków, uciekając przed żołnierzami, wyrzuciła swój towar... Chciałem sam skorzystać, ale myślę, że nie dotrę na czas... Tak więc, jeśli chcesz, częstuj się, inaczej całkiem przepadnie - tych chłopaków na dniach bandyci załatwili podczas kolejnego najazdu... A żal, dobrzy byli stalkerzy, swoje chłopy z jajami...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_73">
		<rus>Все стараются при себе держать свои мысли, ЗОНА брат... Даже друзья стараются не загадывать на завтра.. Чтоб не сглазить...</rus>
		<eng>Everyone tries to keep their thoughts to themselves, it's the ZONE bro... Even friends try not look ahead. Not to jinx it...</eng>
		<ukr>Усі намагаються при собі тримати свої думки, ЗОНА брат... Навіть друзі намагаються не загадувати на завтра.. Щоб не наврочити...</ukr>
		<fra>Tout le monde essaie de garder ses pensées avec eux, frère de la Zone ... Même des amis essayent de ne pas faire de projets pour demain .. Afin de ne pas le gêner...</fra>
		<pln>Wszyscy swoje myśli starają się trzymać przy sobie, ZONA bracie... Nawet przyjaciele starają się nie robić planów na jutro.. Żeby nie zapeszyć...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_81">
		<rus>Да.. Много хороших людей уходит...</rus>
		<eng>Yes .. Many good people go...</eng>
		<ukr>Да.. Багато хороших людей йде...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui. Beaucoup de bonnes personnes s'en vont...</fra>
		<pln>Tak.. Wielu dobrych ludzi odchodzi...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_82">
		<rus>Это точно! Ладно, друг - до завтра...</rus>
		<eng>Exactly! Ok, pal - see you tomorrow...</eng>
		<ukr>Це точно! Гаразд, друже - до завтра...</ukr>
		<fra>Exactement! Ok, mon ami, à demain...</fra>
		<pln>To prawda! No cóż, przyjacielu - do jutra...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_0">
		<rus>Что тут у вас за стрельба была?</rus>
		<eng>What kind of shooting did you have here?</eng>
		<ukr>Що тут у вас за стрілянина була?</ukr>
		<fra>Qu'avez-vous eu pour tirer?</fra>
		<pln>Co tu u was za strzelanina była?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_1">
		<rus>Стреляем, на страх врагам и себе...</rus>
		<eng>Shoot at our own risk...</eng>
		<ukr>Стріляємо, на страх ворогам і собі...</ukr>
		<fra>Tirer à nos risques et périls...</fra>
		<pln>Strzelamy, na postrach wrogom i sobie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_2">
		<rus>Давай для храбрости по двести пятьдесят?</rus>
		<eng>Let's take a shot of courage?</eng>
		<ukr>Давай для хоробрості по двісті п'ятдесят?</ukr>
		<fra>Prenons un coup de courage?</fra>
		<pln>Co powiesz na dwieście pięćdziesiąt na odwagę?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_3">
		<rus>А наливай!</rus>
		<eng>Pour!</eng>
		<ukr>А наливай!</ukr>
		<fra>Et versez!</fra>
		<pln>A nalewaj!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_41">
		<rus>Держи двести пятьдесят! Чтоб не крайние!</rus>
		<eng>Take 250 to be sure!</eng>
		<ukr>Тримай двісті п'ятдесят! Щоб не крайні!</ukr>
		<fra>Prenez 250 pour être sûr!Ce n'est pas extrême!</fra>
		<pln>Trzymaj szklankę! Żeby nie ostatnią!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_42">
		<rus>Подожди чуток, проверю что тут твориться...</rus>
		<eng>Wait a bit, I'll check what's going on here...</eng>
		<ukr>Почекай трохи, перевірю що тут твориться...</ukr>
		<fra>Attendez un peu, vérifiez ce qui se passe ici...</fra>
		<pln>Poczekaj chwilę, zobaczę co się tutaj dzieje...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_5">
		<rus>Фу-у! Ну и гадость, но крепкая...</rus>
		<eng>Oh, yuck...it's so strong...</eng>
		<ukr>Фу-у! Ну і гидота, але міцна....</ukr>
		<fra>Oh, beurk ... c'est tellement fort...</fra>
		<pln>Hu-u! No i mocna, gadzina...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_6">
		<rus>Хех, а ты хотел лимонад, что ли? О чем интересном слышно?</rus>
		<eng>Heh, did you want lemonade? Anything interesting?</eng>
		<ukr>Хех, а ти хотів лимонад, чи що? Що цікавого чути?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, et vous vouliez de la limonade, ou quoi? Qu'est-ce qui est intéressant entendu?</fra>
		<pln>Heh, a ty myślałeś że co, lemoniada? Słyszałeś coś ciekawego?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_71">
		<rus>Бес со своими ребятами положили десяток мародёров возле болота, я потом туда наведался... Трупы, конечно, зверьё основательно перепотрошили, зрелище ещё то... Смотрю в этом месиве блестит что то, палкой вытащил небольшую бутылочку, совсем миниатюрную, сувенирная наверно - грамм на пятьдесят. Мда... Видимо этот упырь проглотил её, когда жаренным запахло... В этой бутылочке листок бумаги был, с картой и отметкой о спрятанном хабаре... Вот эта карта, попробуй доберись, я не смог...</rus>
		<eng>Fiend with his guys killed a dozen looters near the swamp, then I went there... Of course, monsters destroyed the corpses thoroughly, it was horrifying... I saw something glittering in the mash, I pulled out a small even tiny bottle of 50 grams with a stick, it must have been a souvenir. Hmm... Apparently this ghoul drank it when he smelled trouble... In this bottle there was a piece of paper, with a map and a mark of the hidden loot... Here is this map, try to get it, I could not...</eng>
		<ukr>Біс зі своїми хлопцями поклали десяток мародерів біля болота, я потім туди навідався... Трупи, звичайно, звірина грунтовно перепотрошила, видовище ще те... Дивлюся в цьому місиві блищить щось, палицею витягнув невелику пляшку, зовсім мініатюрну, сувенірна напевно - грам на п'ятдесят. Мда.. Мабуть цей упир проковтнув її, коли смаженим запахло... У цій пляшечці листок паперу був, з картою і відміткою про захований хабар... Ось ця карта, спробуй доберись, я не зміг...</ukr>
		<fra>Démon et ses gars ont placé une douzaine de maraudeurs près du marais, puis j'y suis allé ... Les cadavres bien sûr, la bête a été complètement reformulée, le spectacle était toujours ... J'ai regardé dans ce bazar qui brillait de quelque chose, avec un bâton qui a sorti une petite bouteille, assez miniature, probablement un souvenir - cinquante grammes. Hmm ... Apparemment, cette goule l'a avalé quand l'odeur de frites ... Dans cette bouteille se trouvait un morceau de papier, avec une carte et une marque sur un butin caché ... Voici cette carte, essayez de l'obtenir, je ne pouvais pas...</fra>
		<pln>Bies ze swoimi chłopakami rozwalili z dziesiątkę maruderów przy bagnach, a potem tutaj przybyli... Trupami oczywiście zwierzęta się zajęły, niezły widok... Patrzę, w tym gulaszu coś się błyszczy, kijem wyciągnąłem niedużą buteleczkę, taką malutką, pewnie pamiątkowa - z pięćdziesiąt gram. Taa.. W tej buteleczce był kawałek papieru, z mapą i notatką o schowanym towarze... To jest ta mapa, spróbuj się dostać, ja nie dałem rady...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_73">
		<rus>Да все как обычно, тот в аномалии сгинул, другого подстрелили, а третий вообще пропал без следа... Вот такие у нас "интересные" новости...</rus>
		<eng>Everything is usual, one died in the anomaly, another was shot, and the third one disappeared without a trace... Here are our "interesting" news...</eng>
		<ukr>Та все як завжди, той у аномалії згинув, іншого підстрелили, а третій взагалі пропав без сліду... Ось такі у нас "цікаві" новини...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, tout est comme d'habitude, il a disparu dans l'anomalie, un autre a été abattu et le troisième a disparu sans laisser de trace ... Nous avons ici la nouvelle "intéressante"...</fra>
		<pln>Wszystko jak zwykle, ten w anomalii zginął, drugiego zastrzelili, a trzeci w ogóle przepadł bez śladu... Takie to u nas "ciekawe" nowości...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_81">
		<rus>Если смогу добраться, половина - твоя...</rus>
		<eng>If I can get there, half is yours...</eng>
		<ukr>Якщо зможу дістатися, половина - твоя...</ukr>
		<fra>Si je peux y arriver, la moitié est à vous...</fra>
		<pln>Jeśli dam radę dojść, połowa  - twoja...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ладно, не раскисай... До встречи.</rus>
		<eng>Ok, cheer up... See you.</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, не розкисати... До зустрічі.</ukr>
		<fra>D'accord, ne boitez pas ... A bientôt.</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, nie rozklejaj się... Do zobaczenia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет, не возражаешь перекинуться парой слов?</rus>
		<eng>Hi, do you mind having a quick word?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт, не заперечуєш перекинутися парою слів?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour, ça vous dérange un mot?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, nie masz nic przeciwko zamianie kilku słów?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_1">
		<rus>А че языками то трепать? Если бы по делу...</rus>
		<eng>What sense in chewing the rug? Let's stick to the case...</eng>
		<ukr>А чого ото базікати ? Якби по ділу...</ukr>
		<fra>Qu'est-ce que tricher le tapis? Restons dans le cas...</fra>
		<pln>A co tu gadać po próżnicy? Chyba że o czymś konkretnym...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_2">
		<rus>Может вспрыснем знакомство? Чем не дело?</rus>
		<eng>What about having a drink to the meeting? Isn't it the case?</eng>
		<ukr>Може перекинемо за знайомство? Чим не діло?</ukr>
		<fra>Peut-être une nouvelle connaissance? Qu'est-ce qui n'est pas le cas?</fra>
		<pln>Może oblejemy znajomość? Masz coś przeciwko?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_3">
		<rus>Нечем мне вспрыскивать... Если есть, то доставай, а не мели попусту...</rus>
		<eng>There is nothing to drink... If there is, then take it out, and do not waste time...</eng>
		<ukr>Нема чим мені перекидати... Якщо є, то діставай, а не мели попусту...</ukr>
		<fra>Il n'y a rien que je puisse pulvériser ... S'il y en a une, sortez-la, mais ne gaspillez pas stupidement...</fra>
		<pln>Nie ma czym oblewać... Jeśli masz, to wyciągaj, nie zawracaj głowy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_41">
		<rus>Есть, есть! Давай за родство душ!</rus>
		<eng>Yes, there is! Let's drink to affinity of souls!</eng>
		<ukr>Є, є! Давай за спорідненість душ!</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, il y en a un! Buvons à l'affinité des âmes!</fra>
		<pln>Jest, jest! Za pokrewieństwo dusz!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_42">
		<rus>Извини, приятель, у меня тоже кончилась...</rus>
		<eng>Sorry, pal, I'm out of it, too...</eng>
		<ukr>Вибач, приятель, у мене теж скінчилася...</ukr>
		<fra>Désolé, mon pote, je ne suis plus à la hauteur...</fra>
		<pln>Wybacz, przyjacielu, mnie też się skończyło...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_5">
		<rus>Говоришь много, пить, как и жить - нужно тихо...</rus>
		<eng>You talk a lot, it's better to live and drink quietly...</eng>
		<ukr>Говориш багато, пити, як і жити - потрібно тихо...</ukr>
		<fra>Vous parlez beaucoup, mieux vaut vivre et boire tranquillement...</fra>
		<pln>Dużo mówisz, pić, jak i żyć - trzeba cicho...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_6">
		<rus>Философ, блин! Ну просвети меня, как жить нужно...</rus>
		<eng>Damn, you are a philosopher! Well, tell me how to live...</eng>
		<ukr>Філософ, блін! Ну просвіти мене, як жити потрібно...</ukr>
		<fra>Bon sang, vous êtes un philosophe! Eh bien, dites-moi comment vivre...</fra>
		<pln>Filozof, cholera! No, oświeć mnie, jak trzeba żyć...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_71">
		<rus>Живёт каждый по своему, и научиться чужой жизни невозможно... Вот Счастливчик Лёвка, слыхал наверное? Все хвалился какой он везучий, как бабы его любят, что все монстры его обходят... Не жил одним днем, все прятал хабарок, нычки устраивал... Не выпить с ним, не развеяться нормально, берёг арты, не сдавал здешним барыгам, думал на Большой земле все сдать и жить как сыр в масле... И где он теперь? Даже клочка волос не осталось - весь в холодце растворился. А нычки теперь другие удачники ищут... А я так думаю - не будет счастья с того хабара, и не нужен он тем, кто как я, живёт только одним днем...</rus>
		<eng>Everyone lives in their own way, and it's impossible to learn another's life... For example, Lyovka the Lucky, have you heard of him? He was constantly boasting how lucky he was, how women loved him, that all the monsters bypassed him... He did not live for the moment, he kept hiding and looting... It was impossible to drink with him, to get relaxed normally, he kept artifacts, didn't give them to local dealers, thought he would sell everything in the mainland and start living in a clover... And where is he now? Even there is no hair - vanished. Now other lucky people are looking for the loot...I think this loot won't bring them happiness, and those who live for the moment like me do not need it...</eng>
		<ukr>Живе кожен по своєму, і навчитися чужого життя неможливо... Ось Щасливчик Льовка, чув напевно? Все хвалився який він везучий, як баби його люблять, що всі монстри його обходять... Не жив одним днем, все ховав хабарок, хованки влаштовував... Ні випити з ним, ні развіятися нормально, беріг арти, не здавав тутешнім баригам, думав на Великій землі все здати і жити як сир у маслі... І де він тепер? Навіть клаптика волосся не залишилося - весь у холодці розчинився. А хованки тепер інші щасливчики шукають... А я так думаю - не буде щастя з того хабара, і не потрібен він тим, хто як я, живе тільки одним днем...</ukr>
		<fra>Chacun vit à sa manière et il est impossible d’apprendre la vie de quelqu'un d’autre... C’est Lyovka le Vergeot, l’avez-vous entendu? Tout le monde se vantait de sa chance, de son amour pour les femmes, de tous les monstres qui l’entouraient .. Il n’a pas vécu un jour, il a tout caché, les caches sont arrangées... Ne pas boire avec lui, ne pas se détendre normalement, le Shore Art ne lâche pas Je pensais tout passer sur la Grande Terre et vivre comme du fromage au beurre... Et où est-il maintenant? Même un lambeau de cheveux a été laissé - tout dissous dans une morsure froide. Et maintenant, les autres réussites sont à la recherche de pseudos... Et je pense que oui, il n'y aura pas de bonheur dans ce butin, et il n'est pas nécessaire pour ceux qui, comme moi, ne vivent qu'un jour...</fra>
		<pln>Każdy żyje po swojemu, i cudzego życia nie można się nauczyć... Taki Farciarz Lewka, pewnie słyszałeś? Ciągle chwalił się jakie on ma szczęście, jak baby go lubią, jak wszystkie potwory go omijają... Nie żył z dnia na dzień, ciągle towar chował, skrytki zakładał... Ni z nim wypić, ni zabawić się normalnie, dusił arty, nie oddawał tutejszym handlarzom, zamierzał na "Wielkiej Ziemi" wszystko sprzedać i żyć jak pączek w maśle... I gdzie on teraz? Nawet pęczka włosów nie zostało - cały w galarecie się rozpuścił. A skrytek teraz inni farciarze szukają... A ja tak myślę - ten towar szczęścia nie da i nie potrzebny on tym, którzy jak ja, żyją tylko dniem dzisiejszym...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_73">
		<rus>А зачем тебя просвещать... Если есть жизненный путь - то и будешь им идти, а нет - то никак его и не получишь...</rus>
		<eng>Why should I tell you how to live... If there is a life journey, then you will wend this way, if there is no, you won't get it...</eng>
		<ukr>А навіщо тебе просвіщати... Якщо є життєвий шлях - то і будеш ним іти, а ні - то ніяк його і не отримаєш...</ukr>
		<fra>Et pourquoi devriez-vous illuminer ... S'il y a un mode de vie, vous irez, mais non, vous ne l'obtiendrez pas...</fra>
		<pln>A po co mam ciebie oświecać... Jeśli masz drogę życiową - to i będziesz nią iść, a jeśli nie - to i tak jej nie znajdziesz...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_81">
		<rus>Может ты и прав, но я так думаю - о завтрашнем дне заботиться нужно...</rus>
		<eng>Maybe you're right, but I think it's necessary to think about tomorrow...</eng>
		<ukr>Може ти і правий, але я так думаю - про завтрашній день піклуватися потрібно...</ukr>
		<fra>Peut-être avez-vous raison, mais je pense que oui - vous devez prendre soin de demain...</fra>
		<pln>Może i masz rację, ale ja tak myślę - o jutrzejszym dniu myśleć trzeba...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_82">
		<rus>Судьба значит... А я верю в человека...</rus>
		<eng>It's fate... I personally believe in a man...</eng>
		<ukr>Доля значить... А я вірю в людину...</ukr>
		<fra>Le destin signifie ... Et je crois en l'homme...</fra>
		<pln>Znaczy los... A ja wierzę w człowieka...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_0">
		<rus>Как оно, приятель?</rus>
		<eng>How are things, buddy?</eng>
		<ukr>Як воно, приятель?</ukr>
		<fra>Comment ça va, mon pote?</fra>
		<pln>Jak tam, przyjacielu?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да помаленьку, немного тоскливо правда...</rus>
		<eng>So so, sometimes it's sad...</eng>
		<ukr>Та помаленьку, трохи тоскно правда...</ukr>
		<fra>Alors oui,bof parfois c'est triste à mourir...</fra>
		<pln>Pomalutku, trochę smutno, po prawdzie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_2">
		<rus>Давай для настроения? По чуть-чуть?</rus>
		<eng>Let's drink a little bit to set the mood!</eng>
		<ukr>Давай для настрою? По чуть-чуть?</ukr>
		<fra>Buvons un peu pour nous mettre dans l'ambiance?</fra>
		<pln>Może tak dla nastroju? Po maluchu?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_3">
		<rus>С тебя пузырь, с меня все остальное...</rus>
		<eng>A bottle is on you, all the rest is on me...</eng>
		<ukr>З тебе пляшка, з мене все інше...</ukr>
		<fra>Une bouteille d'eau pour vous,et tout le reste est pour moi :)...</fra>
		<pln>Stawiasz flaszkę, ja daję resztę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_41">
		<rus>Согласен! Давай стаканы...</rus>
		<eng>Agree! Give glasses...</eng>
		<ukr>Згоден! Давай стакани...</ukr>
		<fra>Je suis d'accord! Allez buvons...</fra>
		<pln>Zgoda! Dawaj szklanki...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_42">
		<rus>Остальное и у меня есть, пузыря нету...</rus>
		<eng>I also have the rest, there is no bottle...</eng>
		<ukr>Все інше і у мене є, пляшки нема...</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai aussi le reste, il n'y a pas de bouteille...</fra>
		<pln>Reszta to i u mnie jest, flaszki nie ma...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_5">
		<rus>Хороша, чертовка! Все нутро прожгла!</rus>
		<eng>Goddam, it's good! It's burned out my gut!</eng>
		<ukr>Хороша, бісова! Все нутро пропалила!</ukr>
		<fra>Bon Dieu, c'est bon! Il a brûlé mes tripes!</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, diablica! Nieźle pali!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_6">
		<rus>Расскажи что-нибудь поинтереснее...</rus>
		<eng>Tell me something more interesting...</eng>
		<ukr>Розкажи що-небудь, поцікавіше...</ukr>
		<fra>Dis-moi quelque chose de plus intéressant...</fra>
		<pln>Opowiedz coś ciekawego...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_71">
		<rus>Поинтереснее? Хм... Что бы соврать то... А! Ладно, расскажу как есть... Юрика знаешь? Малёк совсем, попытался за хабаром наравне с опытными сталкерами ломануться... Голова у него на выпивку совсем слабая, на пробку наступит - а несёт его как от ведра... Вчера сидел тут с нами, языком мел, как помелом... Разошёлся, типа он всем старикам нос утрёт, потому как знает, где хабар заныкан. Мы его на смех подняли, так он ерепениться начал - тыкать всем свой КПК с отметкой на месте нычки. Не поверил никто, конечно - откуда у сопли с Кордона такая инфа может быть... Типа вот здесь какой то хабар... Ты бы поверил?</rus>
		<eng>More interesting? Hmm... What should I lie... Ah! Ok, I'll tell you how it is... Do you know Yurik? He's very little, but tried to get loot along with experienced stalkers... He gets drunk quite easily, even when he drinks little, he smells like he's drunk a bucket... Yesterday he sat here with us and talked a lot... As a result he said he would get the edge over the experienced, as he knew where loot was. We began to laugh at him, which made him stubborn. He began to show his PDA with the mark of the loot place. Of course, nobody believed him, how could that kid from Cordon get the information... Like here is some loot... Would you believe it?</eng>
		<ukr>Поцікавіше? Хм... Що ж би це збрехати... А! Гаразд, розповім як є... Юрка знаєш? Мальок зовсім, спробував за хабаром нарівні з досвідченими сталкерами ломанутися... Голова у нього на випивку зовсім слабка, на пробку наступить - а несе його як від відра... Вчора сидів тут з нами, язиком плів, як помелом... Розійшовся, типу він усім старим ніс втре, томущо знає де хабар заниканий. Ми його на сміх підняли, так він комизитись почав - тикати всім свій КПК з відміткою на місці хованки. Не повірив ніхто, звичайно - звідки у соплі з Кордону така інфра може бути... Типу ось тут якийсь хабар... Ти б повірив?</ukr>
		<fra>Plus intéressant? Hmm ... Que mentirais-tu ... Ah! D'accord, je vais vous dire comment manger ... Yuri sait? La frite du tout, a essayé de traîner avec les harceleurs expérimentés avec le butin ... Sa tête était très faible pour boire, il viendrait au bouchon - et il le portait comme un seau ... comme s’il essuierait son nez pour toutes les personnes âgées, car il sait où se trouve le butin. Nous l’avons fait rire, alors il a commencé à jouer: piquer tout le monde avec son PDA avec une marque à la place de la cache.Bien sûr, personne ne croyait - d'où vient la morve de Cordon? Cet infa peut être ... Comme quoi, qu'est-ce qu'un butin ici ... le croiriez-vou?</fra>
		<pln>Ciekawego? Hm... Co by ci tu powiedzieć... A! Dobra, to ci opowiem... Znasz Jurika? Żółtodziób całkowity, spróbował jak doświadczony stalker za towarem się wypuścić... Słabą ma głowę do wypitki, po jednej szklance - jakby wiadro wypił... Wczoraj siedział tu z nami, jęzor jak łopata... Przechwalał się, że on wszystkim starym nosa utrze, bo wie gdzie towar jest schowany. Jak go zaczęliśmy wyśmiewać, to się zjeżył - zaczął każdemu, czy chciał czy nie, podtykać swój PDA z zaznaczonym schowkiem. Oczywiście nikt nie uwierzył - skąd smark z Kordonu może mieć taką informację... Że gdzieś tu jest taki towar... Ty byś uwierzył?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_73">
		<rus>Че то язык у меня заплетается, завтра что-нибудь расскажу.</rus>
		<eng>I got tongue-tied, I'll tell you something tomorrow.</eng>
		<ukr>Щось язик у мене заплітається, завтра що-небудь розповім..</ukr>
		<fra>Je me suis énervé, je vais vous dire quelque chose demain.</fra>
		<pln>Jakoś dzisiaj mi się język plącze, jutro coś opowiem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_81">
		<rus>Не, не поверил бы... Юрик ещё тот свистун...</rus>
		<eng>No, I would not believe... Yurik is a storyteller...</eng>
		<ukr>Ні, не повірив би... Юрко ще той свистун...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, je n'y croirais pas ... Yurik est un conteur...</fra>
		<pln>Nie, nie uwierzyłbym... Jurik to jeszcze szczeniak...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_82">
		<rus>Тогда до завтра, приятель...</rus>
		<eng>Then see you tomorrow, pal...</eng>
		<ukr>Тоді до завтра, приятель...</ukr>
		<fra>Alors à demain, mon pote...</fra>
		<pln>No to do jutra, przyjacielu...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет, как тут у вас?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, how is it going?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт, як тут у вас?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour, comment vas-tu?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, jak tu u was?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_1">
		<rus>У нас весело, хочешь иди в Бар, хочешь - с долговцами перетирай или делай ставки на Арене. Много слухов ходит - Бар же почти в центре Зоны находится...</rus>
		<eng>We are having fun, if you want, you can go to the Bar, or talk round with Duty fighters or bet on the Arena. There are a lot of rumors, as the Bar is almost in the center of the Zone...</eng>
		<ukr>У нас весело, хочеш йди в Бар, хочеш - з долганами перетирай або роби ставки на арені. Багато чуток ходить - Бар ж майже в центрі Зони знаходиться...</ukr>
		<fra>Nous nous amusons beaucoup, vous voulez aller au barreau, vous voulez vous battre avec les débiteurs ou parier sur l’arène. Il y a beaucoup de rumeurs - le bar est presque au centre de la zone...</fra>
		<pln>U nas wesoło, chcesz - idziesz do Baru, chcesz - z powinnościowcami gadasz albo obstawiasz na Arenie. mówią, że Bar leży prawie w centrum Zony...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_2">
		<rus>Может накатим по стопарю? За знакомство...</rus>
		<eng>What about a shot glasss? To the acquaintance...</eng>
		<ukr>Може накатимо по стопарю? За знайомство...</ukr>
		<fra>Peut-être que nous allons arrêter par arrêt? Pour faire connaissance...</fra>
		<pln>Może trochę procentów? Za znajomość...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_3">
		<rus>Тоже неплохо... Давай наливай, я тебя после на арену свожу - пощекочем нервишки...</rus>
		<eng>Not bad... Pour, then I'll take you to the arena to rattle nerves...</eng>
		<ukr>Теж непогано... Давай наливай, я тебе після на арену зводжу - полоскочимо нервишки...</ukr>
		<fra>Dommage ... Allez viens, je vais t'emmener à l'arène - chatouillons nos nerfs...</fra>
		<pln>Też nieźle... Polej, a potem cię na Arenę zaprowadzę - nerwy potrenujemy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_41">
		<rus>Давай, за бодрость духа!</rus>
		<eng>Let's do it, to the high spirits!</eng>
		<ukr>Давай, за бадьорість духу!</ukr>
		<fra>Faisons-le, pour la haute humeur!</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, za hart ducha!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_42">
		<rus>За пузырём в "100 Рентген" сбегаю и назад... Жди!</rus>
		<eng>I'll run to "100 R" for a bottle... Be right back!</eng>
		<ukr>За пляшкою в "100 Рентген" збігаю і назад... Чекай!</ukr>
		<fra>Pour une bouteille au "100 Roentgen", je vais courir en arrière ... Attendez!</fra>
		<pln>Skoczę po flaszkę do "100 Rentgenów" i zaraz wracam... Czekaj!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_5">
		<rus>Ну давай...</rus>
		<eng>Ok...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай...</ukr>
		<fra>Allez...Ok.</fra>
		<pln>No dobra...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_6">
		<rus>А какие слухи ходят, чего интересного говорят?</rus>
		<eng>What kind of rumors? What interesting do they say?</eng>
		<ukr>А які чутки ходять, що цікавого говорять?</ukr>
		<fra>Quel genre de rumeurs? Qu'est-ce qu'ils disent d'intéressant?</fra>
		<pln>A jakie słuchy chodzą, co ludzie ciekawego mówią?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да много чего... Вроде есть телепорт прямо к МОНОЛИТу, правда мест называют не меньше десятка. Появилась новая разновидность монстров - электричеством бьются, вообще атас... Долговцы со свободовцами всё не поделят Зону, то и дело слышно - то эти тех завалили, то те этих, а чё делить-то? Зоны на всех хватит... Недавно поймали свободовца и вели перевоспитывать к себе с подвал - психиатры тоже мне... Так тот свободовец кинул хрень какую то в кусты, я потом слазил, нашёл КПК его, а в нем координаты тайничка. Вот. Давай вместе посмотрим - что там? Вот здесь вроде он находится...</rus>
		<eng>Many things... Like there is a teleport directly to the MONOLITH, but nobody know where is it exactly. A new variety of monsters has appeared that give an electric shock, watch out!... Duty and Freedom fighters can't share Zone, now and then they say these are taken out, then those are killed, but what do they share? Zone is enough for everyone... Recently, the Freedom soldier was caught, they decided to put him to the basement and re-educate...some psychiatrists... So that fighter threw something to bushes, then I checked and found his PDA, and there were coordinates of the stash in it. Here it is. Let's see together what's there? It seems to be here...</eng>
		<ukr>Та багато чого... Начебто є телепорт прямо до Моноліту, правда місць називають не менше десятка. З'явився новий різновид монстрів - електрикою б'ються, взагалі атас... Долг все з волівцями не поділять Зону, увесь час чути - то ці тих завалили, то ті цих, а що ділити то? Зони на всіх вистачить... Нещодавно зловили волівця і вели перевиховувати до себе в підвал - психіатри теж мені... Так той волівець кинув хрінь якусь в кущі, я потім злазив, знайшов КПК його, а в ньому координати схованок. Ось. Давай разом подивимося - що там? Ось тут начебто він перебуває...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, beaucoup de choses ... Il semble qu'il y ait un téléport directement vers MONOLITH, bien qu'il y ait au moins une douzaine d'endroits. Un nouveau type de monstres est apparu - ils se battent avec l'électricité, généralement les atas ... Devoir ne partage pas la zone avec Liberté, de temps en temps, vous pouvez l'entendre - alors ceux-ci se sont remplis, puis ceux-ci, mais qu'en est-il du partage? Il y aura assez de zones pour tout le monde ... Récemment, un gars de la Liberté a été attrapé et ils étaient rééduqués du sous-sol - des psychiatres aussi pour moi ... Pour que les Liberté aient jeté de la merde dans les buissons, j'ai ensuite slazit, trouvé son PDA et les coordonnées du secret. La voici Voyons ensemble qu'est-ce qu'il y a? Ici, il semble qu'il soit...</fra>
		<pln>Różne takie... Że niby jest teleport prosto do MONOLITu, ale miejsc podają nie mniej niż dziesięć. Pojawił się nowy rodzaj mutantów - prądem uderzają... Powinność z Wolnością nadal nie mogą się w Zonie pomieścić, ciagle słychać - a to ci tamtych, a to tamci tych postrzelali, i po co to? Zony dla wszystkich starczy... Niedawno złapali wolnościowca i prowadzili go do piwnicy, żeby go reedukować - też mi psychiatrzy... Widziałem jak ten wolnościowiec po drodze coś wrzucił w krzaki, podszedłem potem i znalazłem jego PDA, a w nim koordynaty schowka. Chodź, zobaczymy razem co tam jest? Wydaje się, że to jest gdzieś tutaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_73">
		<rus>Приходи вечерком в Бар, соберутся наши, пообщаемся... Много полезного услышать можно, только не забывай выпивку выставлять...</rus>
		<eng>Come to the Bar tonight, our people will gather, we will talk... You can learn a lot of useful things, just do not forget to get some drinks...</eng>
		<ukr>Приходь вечерком в Бар, зберуться наші, поспілкуємося... Багато корисного почути можна, тільки не забувай випивку виставляти...</ukr>
		<fra>Venez au bar le soir, rassemblez les nôtres, discutez ... Vous pouvez entendre beaucoup de choses utiles, mais n'oubliez pas de prendre un verre...</fra>
		<pln>Przyjdź wieczorem do Baru, nasi się zbiorą, pogadamy... Dużo ciekawych rzeczy można usłyszeć, tylko nie zapominaj kolejek stawiać...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_81">
		<rus>Далековато, я пока в другую сторону иду...</rus>
		<eng>It's far, I'm going to the other side...</eng>
		<ukr>Далеченько, я поки в іншу сторону йду...</ukr>
		<fra>C'est loin, je vais de l'autre côté...</fra>
		<pln>Dość daleko, ja akurat w przeciwną stronę idę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ладно, приду...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, I'll come...</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, прийду...</ukr>
		<fra>D'accord, je viendrai...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, przyjdę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорово, старина. Как жизнь?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, old cap. How's your life?</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, старина. Як життя?</ukr>
		<fra>Grand, mon vieux. Comment ça va?</fra>
		<pln>Czołem, stary. Jak żyjesz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_1">
		<rus>Ключом бьёт... По голове... Чё надо?</rus>
		<eng>It could be much better... What do you want?</eng>
		<ukr>Ключем б'є... По голові... Що треба?</ukr>
		<fra>Cela pourrait être beaucoup mieux ... Que voulez-vous?</fra>
		<pln>Kiepsko... Co chciałeś?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_2">
		<rus>Ты чё сердитый такой? Давай накатим для настроения?</rus>
		<eng>Why are you so angry? Let's drink to set the mood!</eng>
		<ukr>Ти чого сердитий такий? Давай накатимо для настрою?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi es-tu si en colère? Buvons pour mettre de l'ambiance?</fra>
		<pln>Coś ty taki wkurzony? Chodź, łykniemy dla poprawy nastroju?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_3">
		<rus>Достало уже всё! Выкатывай...</rus>
		<eng>I'm fed up with everything! Take it out...</eng>
		<ukr>Дістало вже все! Викочуй...</ukr>
		<fra>J'en ai marre de tout! Sortez-le...</fra>
		<pln>Wszystkiego mam już dość! Wyciągaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ладно! Наплюй на все... Поехали!</rus>
		<eng>Ok! Take it easy... Come on!</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд! Наплюй на все... Поїхали!</ukr>
		<fra> ok! Allez-y doucement ... Allez!</fra>
		<pln>Dobra! Pluń na to wszystko... Jazda!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_42">
		<rus>Я лучше отвалю...</rus>
		<eng>I'd better go...</eng>
		<ukr>Я краще відвалю...</ukr>
		<fra>Je ferais mieux d'y aller...</fra>
		<pln>Lepiej sobie pójdę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_5">
		<rus>Ну давай... Хоть водку не разучились делать ещё...</rus>
		<eng>Ok... At least they still can make good vodka...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай... Хоч горілку не розучилися робити ще...</ukr>
		<fra>Allez ... Bien qu'ils n'aient pas oublié comment faire de la vodka...</fra>
		<pln>No jazda... Przynajmniej wódki jeszcze nie oduczyli się robić...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_6">
		<rus>Да чистая, как слеза комсомолки... А что достало-то?</rus>
		<eng>Yes, it's clean like a tear... And what are you fed up with?</eng>
		<ukr>Так, чиста як сльоза комсомолки... А що ж дістало?</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, c'est comme ... Et de quoi en avez-vous marre?</fra>
		<pln>Czysta, jak łza komsomołki... A co ci tak dopiekło?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да козлы кругом одни... Делаешь добро людям, а они говнищем мажут... Нашёл я нычку одну, думал с одним козлом вместе добраться, что бы было кому спину прикрыть... Так эта зараза свалила по тихому - даже ещё и рюкзак мой распотрошить успела... Тьфу... Люди... Козлы! Может сумеешь его опередить? Вот здесь этот тайник...</rus>
		<eng>Jerks are everywhere... You do people good and they screw over...I found one loot here and wanted to go there together with one jerk for us to cover each other's backs... But this bastard ran away and even emptied my backpack... Ugh... People... Jerks! Can you reach it faster than he? Here is the stash...</eng>
		<ukr>Та козли кругом одні... Робиш добро людям, а вони лайном мажуть... Знайшов я ничку одну, думав з одним козлом разом дістатися, що б було кому спину прикрити... Так ця зараза звалила по тихому - та ще й рюкзак мій розпотрошити встигла... Тьху... Люди... Козли! Може зумієш його випередити? Ось тут ця схованка...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, les chèvres sont toutes seules ... Vous faites du bien aux gens, mais ils ont mis le minable ... J'ai trouvé un petit, j'ai pensé avec une chèvre à se réunir, qu'est-ce que quelqu'un aurait à couvrir ... Cette infection est donc tombée dans le calme - même J'ai aussi réussi à vider mon sac à dos ... Ugh ... Les gens ... Les chèvres! Peut-être que vous pouvez le battre? Voici cette cache...</fra>
		<pln>Same durnie wokoło... Robisz ludziom dobrze, a oni cię gównem obrzucą... Znalazłem jedną skrytkę, chciałem z jednym dupkiem pójść, żeby było komu pleców pilnować... A ten skurwiel zwiał po cichu - nawet jeszcze i mój plecak wypatroszyć zdążył... Tfu... Ludzie... Świnie! Może uda ci się go wyprzedzić? O, tu jest ten schowek...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_73">
		<rus>Чудаков на букву М хватает, верить никому нельзя... Так и норовят подлянку сделать...</rus>
		<eng>There are too many jerks with no cojones , you can't trust anyone... Everyone tries to do dirt...</eng>
		<ukr>Чудаків на букву М вистачає, вірити нікому не можна... Так і норовлять підлянку зробити...</ukr>
		<fra>Assez avec la lettre M, ça suffit, vous ne pouvez en croire personne ... Alors ils s’efforcent de faire un tour...</fra>
		<pln>Dziwaków nie brakuje, nikomu wierzyć nie można... Tylko patrzą, żeby jakieś świństwo zrobić...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_81">
		<rus>Попробую, если получиться - постараюсь вернуть тебе веру в людей.</rus>
		<eng>I'll go for it, maybe I can do. I'll try to make you trust people again.</eng>
		<ukr>Спробую, якщо вийде - постараюся повернути тобі віру в людей.</ukr>
		<fra>Je vais y aller, peut-être que je peux faire. Vous ferez de nouveau confiance aux gens.</fra>
		<pln>Spróbuję, jeśli się uda - postaram się przywrócić ci wiarę w ludzi.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_82">
		<rus>Злой ты, уйду я от тебя...</rus>
		<eng>You are mad, I'll leave you...</eng>
		<ukr>Злий ти, піду я від тебе...</ukr>
		<fra>Vous êtes en colère, je vous laisse...</fra>
		<pln>Zły jesteś, idę sobie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет братан, мы раньше не встречались?</rus>
		<eng>Hey bro, have not we met before?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт братан, ми раніше не зустрічалися?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour mon frère, est-ce que nous nous sommes déjà rencontrés?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć braciak, czy myśmy się kiedyś nie spotkali?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да и твоя физия мелькала вроде, как тебя?</rus>
		<eng>I guess I saw your face too, what's your name?</eng>
		<ukr>Та й твоя фізія мелькала ніби, як тебе?</ukr>
		<fra>Je suppose que j'ai aussi vu votre visage, comment vous appelez-vous?</fra>
		<pln>I twoja gęba jakby nie obca, jak cię wołają?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_2">
		<rus>Меченным меня зови, все так называют...</rus>
		<eng>Call me Marked One, they call me like that...</eng>
		<ukr>Міченим мене клич, всі так називають...</ukr>
		<fra>Appelle-moi le Marqué, ils m'appellent comme ça...</fra>
		<pln>Nazywaj mnie Naznaczony, wszyscy tak na mnie mówią...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_3">
		<rus>Ладно, Меченный так Меченый, ну давай за знакомство? Есть с собой?</rus>
		<eng>Ok, Marked One, well, let's have a drink to the acquaintance? Do you have any?</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, Мічений так Мічений, ну давай за знайомство? Є з собою?</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, le Marqué, eh bien, faisons connaissance? Avez-vous un peu de bonne boisson?</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, Naznaczony to Naznaczony, może by tak za znajomość? Masz coś z sobą?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_41">
		<rus>А то! Вот! Крепкая, как мат монаха...</rus>
		<eng>Sure! Here is it! It's very strong...</eng>
		<ukr>А то! Ось! Міцна, як мат ченця...</ukr>
		<fra>Et ça! Ici! Fort, comme un tapis de moine...</fra>
		<pln>Aha! Jasne! Mocna, jak należy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_42">
		<rus>Нет, нету... Пришлось отдать за патроны весь запас...</rus>
		<eng>No... I had to give everything for ammo...</eng>
		<ukr>Ні, немає... Довелося віддати за патрони весь запас...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, non ... J'ai dû abandonner toute ma réserve de munitions...</fra>
		<pln>Nie, nie mam... Trzeba było cały zapas za amunicję oddać...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_5">
		<rus>Ха! Правда! Крепкая! Ну что брат Меченный, вот и двумя хорошими людьми больше в Зоне стало...</rus>
		<eng>Ha! True! Strong! Well, Marked One, this is how more two good people appeared in the Zone...</eng>
		<ukr>Ха! Правда! Міцна! Ну що брат Мічений, от і двома хорошими людьми більше в Зоні стало...</ukr>
		<fra>Ha! Vraiment! Fort! Eh bien, frère le Marqué, deux autres braves gens de la Zone sont apparues dans la Zone...</fra>
		<pln>Ha! Prawda! Mocna! No cóż, bracie Naznaczony, i w ten sposób przybyło w Zonie dwóch dobrych ludzi...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_6">
		<rus>Говорят - можно хабар найти недалеко, не слышал?</rus>
		<eng>They say one can find some loot nearby, did you hear?</eng>
		<ukr>Кажуть - можна хабар знайти недалеко, не чув?</ukr>
		<fra>Ils disent que vous pouvez trouver à proximité, vous entendez?</fra>
		<pln>Nie słyszałeś, czy można gdzieś w okolicy towar znaleźć?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_71">
		<rus>Ну, раз ты хороший человек, а хорошие люди должны помогать друг другу, расскажу тебе как на духу, Меченный... Зомбаки последнее время что то очень часто стали забредать прямо сюда, и вот ведь загадка - все подходы к базе долговцами перекрыты, даже мышь не пролезет, а эти все равно появляются... Бормочут чего-то, руки тянут... Жуть! Вчера ночью культурно так себе отдыхаю - Бармен, скотина, больше в долг не наливает, ну не жлоб, а? Ну так вот, закемарил я - чувствую вонью несёт и тяжесть навалилась - открываю глаза - вот он голубчик, трупак ходячий. Я оцепенел весь, не рукой не ногой двинуть не могу... Не со страху, конечно, а так, от неожиданности... А дохлик гнусаво так говорит чего-то, прислушался - цифры вроде, снова и снова одно и тоже. Я глаза закрыл, открываю - нет никого... Только вонь осталась... А цифры так в голове и звучат, после глянул - вроде на координаты похожи. Только далеко отсюда... Вот такая брат петрушка...</rus>
		<eng>Well, since you're a good person, and good people should help each other, I'll tell you, Marked One... These days zombies often come here, and that's a mystery - all the ways to the base are blocked by Duty soldiers, even a mouse can't get through that, but these ones still appear... They mutter something with their long arms... Spooky! Yesterday night, I was having a rest, Barkeep does not give me drinks on credit anymore, mean dog, isn't he? Well, I fell asleep, then I smelt something stinky, I opened my eyes and saw a walking corpse. I was numb, I couldn't move... Of course, not because of fear but surprise... The zombie was saying something, I guess, numbers, the same thing again and again. I closed my eyes then opened and there was nobody... Only the pong remained... But those numbers were still in my head, then I checked, they appeared to coordinated. But it's far... That's the way the cookie crumbles...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну, раз ти хороша людина, а хороші люди повинні допомагати один одному, розповім тобі як на духу, Мічений... Зомбаки останнім часом щось дуже часто стали забрідати прямо сюди, і от же ж загадка - всі підходи до бази долгівцями перекриті, навіть миша не пролізе, а ці все одно з'являються... Бурмочуть чогось, руки тягнуть... Жах! Вчора вночі культурно так собі відпочиваю - Бармен, скотина, більше в борг не наливає, ну не жлоб, а? Ну так от, закімарив я - відчуваю смородом несе і тягар навалився - відкриваю очі - ось він голубчик, трупак ходячий. Я заціпенів весь, що ні рукою ні ногою рушити не можу... Не зі страху, звичайно, а так, від несподіванки... А дохлік гугняво так говорить чогось, прислухався - цифри начебто, знову і знову одне і теж. Я очі закрив, відкриваю - нема нікого... Тільки сморід залишився... А цифри так в голові і звучать, після глянув - начебто на координати схожі. Тільки далеко звідси... Ось така брат петрушка...</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, puisque vous êtes une bonne personne et que les bonnes personnes doivent s'entraider, je vais vous dire en ce qui concerne l'esprit, le Marqué... Zombies ont récemment commencé à errer très souvent ici même, et le mystère est que toutes les approches de la base sont à long terme bloquée, même la souris ne rampe pas, mais elles apparaissent toujours ... Elles marmonnent quelque chose, leurs mains se tirent ... Horreur! Hier soir, culturellement, alors je me repose - le Barman brute n’est plus endetté, eh bien, pas un imbécile, hein? Eh bien, alors, je zakemaril - je sens la puanteur de porter et de poids - j'ouvre les yeux - le voilà, mon cher cadavre en marche. J'étais complètement engourdi, je ne pouvais pas bouger mon pied avec mon pied ... Pas de peur, bien sûr, mais à cause de la surprise ... Mais le dohlik dit nasalement quelque chose, écouté - des chiffres comme, encore et encore la même chose. Je fermai les yeux, je l'ouvris - il n'y avait personne ... Seule la puanteur subsistait ... Et les chiffres sonnent comme ça dans ma tête, après que j'ai regardé - on dirait que les coordonnées sont similaires. Seulement loin d’ici ... Voici un tel frère persil...</fra>
		<pln>No cóż, ponieważ dobry z ciebie człowiek, a dobrzy ludzie powinni sobie pomagać, powiem ci uczciwie, Naznaczony... Zombiaki ostatnimi czasy coś bardzo często zaczęły przyłazić prosto tutaj, i to jest zagadka - wszystkie podejścia do bazy są strzeżone przez powinnościowców, nawet mysz się nie prześlizgnie, a oni i tak wyłażą... Mamroczą coś tam, ręce wyciągają... Straszne! Wczoraj w nocy kulturalnie sobie odpoczywam - Barman łajdak na kredyt więcej nie chce nalać, no czy to nie żłób, co? I tak jakoś zadrzemałem, nagle czuję - smród jakiś i taki ciężar. Otwieram oczy - a tu on, gołąbeczek, chodzący trup. Zdrętwiałem cały, ani ręką ani nogą nie ruszyć... Nie ze strachu, oczywiście, a tak, z zaskoczenia... A zgniłek niemrawo coś tam gada, przysłuchuję się - jakby liczby, w kółko te same. Zamknąłem oczy, otwieram - nie ma nikogo... Tylko smród został... A liczby w głowie dźwięczą, potem pomyślałem - jakby jakieś koordynaty. Tylko daleko stąd... Taka to, bracie, sprawa...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_73">
		<rus>Весь хабар, который был в лёгких местах, подчистую выгребли... Нужно к центру Зоны пробиваться - говорят - там клондайк...</rus>
		<eng>They took all the loot in easy places... It is necessary to go to the center of the Zone - they say there is treasure trove...</eng>
		<ukr>Весь хабар, який був в легеких місцях, дочиста вигребли... Потрібно до центру Зони пробиватися - кажуть - там клондайк....</ukr>
		<fra>Tous les butins qui se trouvaient dans les endroits faciles ont été nettoyés proprement ... Nous devons nous rendre au centre de la Zone - ils disent - il y a un Klondike...</fra>
		<pln>Cały towar, który był w łatwych miejscach, wyczyścili do żywego... Trzeba do centrum Zony wędrować - mówią - tam klondike...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_81">
		<rus>Видать водка палёная была, где брал?</rus>
		<eng>Vodka must have been tainted, where did you take it?</eng>
		<ukr>Видно горілка палена була, де брав?</ukr>
		<fra>On dirait que la vodka était tombée, où l'avez-vous obtenue?</fra>
		<pln>Widać wódka chrzczona była, skąd brałeś?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_82">
		<rus>Клондайк, говоришь? Ну-ну...</rus>
		<eng>Treasure trove? Indeed...</eng>
		<ukr>Клондайк, кажеш? Ну-ну...</ukr>
		<fra>Klondike, vous dites? Bien, bien...</fra>
		<pln>Klondike, mówisz? No-no...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_0">
		<rus>Что так невесел, друг?</rus>
		<eng>Why are you so sad, friend?</eng>
		<ukr>Що такий невеселий, друже?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi es-tu si triste, mon ami?</fra>
		<pln>Coś taki zasępiony, przyjacielu?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да так, думаю - валить из Зоны надо... С каждым днем все хуже и хуже. Монстры все опаснее и злее, погода дерьмовая, аномалии не поймёшь где - а самое страшное - люди звереют...</rus>
		<eng>I think I should leave the Zone... Every day it gets worse and worse. Monsters get more dangerous and evil, the weather sucks, you can not understand where anomalies are - and the most terrible thing is that people become like brutes...</eng>
		<ukr>Та так, думаю - валити із Зони треба... З кожним днем все гірше і гірше. Монстри все небезпечніші і зліші, погода гівняна, аномалії не розумієш де - а найстрашніше - люди звіріють...</ukr>
		<fra>Oh, je pense - il est nécessaire de sortir de la zone ... Cela empire de jour en jour. Les monstres sont plus dangereux et plus méchants, par temps de merde, les anomalies ne peuvent pas être comprises là où - et le pire, les gens sont en train de devenir des bêtes...</fra>
		<pln>A tak, myślę - pora z Zony się wynosić... Z każdym dniem coraz gorzej i gorzej. Mutanty coraz niebezpieczniejsze i bardziej złe, pogoda do dupy, anomalie gdzie się nawet nie spodziewasz, a najstraszniejsze - ludzie się zezwierzęcają...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_2">
		<rus>Ладно, забей! Давай лучше накатим...</rus>
		<eng>Come on, forget! Let's have a drink...</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, забий! Давай краще накатимо...</ukr>
		<fra>Allez, oublie! Buvons un verre...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, zapomnij! Już lepiej coś wypić...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_3">
		<rus>Ну давай, а есть что?</rus>
		<eng>Ok, but do you have?</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай, а є що?</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, mais est-ce que vous avez?</fra>
		<pln>Pewnie, a jest co?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_41">
		<rus>Не было бы - не предлагал бы...</rus>
		<eng>If I didn't have, I would not offer...</eng>
		<ukr>Не було б - не пропонував би...</ukr>
		<fra>Si je ne l’avais pas eu, je ne pourrais pas offrir...</fra>
		<pln>Jak by nie było - nic bym nie mówił...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_42">
		<rus>Вот дьявол! Была же ещё бутылка! Спёрли!</rus>
		<eng>Damn it! There was a bottle! They stole it!</eng>
		<ukr>До біса! Була ж ще пляшка! Сперли!</ukr>
		<fra>Bon sang! Il y avait une bouteille! Ils l'ont volé!</fra>
		<pln>Co za diabeł! Miałem jeszcze butelkę! Ukradli!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_5">
		<rus>Эх-р-р-м, не Шардонэ конечно, но тоже ничего!</rus>
		<eng>Ohh, it's not Chardonnay, of course, but also good!</eng>
		<ukr>Ех-р-р-м, не Шардоне звичайно, але теж нічого!</ukr>
		<fra>Ohh, ce n'est pas du Chardonnay, bien sûr, mais presque aussi bon!</fra>
		<pln>Eh-h-m, nie Chardonnay, ale też niczego sobie!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_6">
		<rus>А что за хабаром не идёшь?</rus>
		<eng>Why don't you go for loot?</eng>
		<ukr>А що за хабаром не йдеш?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi n’allez-vous pas chercher du butin?</fra>
		<pln>A czemu za towarem nie idziesz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да долгая история... Не спешишь?.. Мы с Серёгой Безухим друзьями были, все время вместе в глубокие рейды ходили... Иной раз до самого Мозговыжигателя добирались, видели этих фантомов и не только... \nПлесни ещё чуток... Да-а, Серёга... Ухо у него отстрелили ещё в Чечне, оттуда и кличка такая. Сколько раз мы друг другу спины прикрывали... В последней ходке на псевдогиганта нарвались, тварь не особо опасная - если, конечно, на неё не переть сдуру. А тут так получилось, что хлопнула эта тварь своей ручищей по земле, Серёгу отбросило, ну наверно не больше полуметра, прямо в холодец, всем телом... Лицо, руки... Короче всё.. Мясо как кисель стекало с черепа... А он в сознании был... Плесни, душа горит... Бросил я его там... И душу свою тоже там оставил... Тайничок мы оставили, не буду я его забирать, не хочу... Если найдёшь, помяни Серёгу...</rus>
		<eng>It's a long story... Aren't you in a hurry? .. We were friends with One-eared Sergei, we always carried out deep raids... Once we reached the Brain burner, saw phantoms and not only... \nPour little bit more... Well, Sergei... His ear was shot off in Chechnya, that's how he got his nickname. We covered each other's backs so many times... Last time we ran up against Pseudogiant, the creature is not so dangerous, unless you attack it. The creature smacked its hand down on the ground, Sergei was knocked out probably no more than half a meter in the air, that's the way he smashed. His body, face, arms...everything .. Meat was flowing down the skull like jelly.. And he was conscious... Pour, my heart bleeds... I left him there...And my heart is there, too... We left loot in that place... I will not take it, I do not want... If you find, drink to Sergei's memory...</eng>
		<ukr>Та довга історія... Не поспішаєш? Ми з Сергієм Безвухим друзями були, весь час разом в глибокі рейди ходили... Інший раз до самого мізковипалювача добиралися, бачили цих фантомів і не тільки...\nПлесни ще чуток... Да-а, Сергій... Вухо у нього відстрілили ще в Чечні, звідти і кличка така. Скільки разів ми один одному спину прикривали... В останній ходці на Псевдогіганта нарвалися, створіння не особливо небезпечне - якщо, звичайно, на нього не перти здуру. А тут так вийшло, що хлопнула ця тварюка своєю ручицьою по землі, Сергія відкинуло, ну напевно не більше півметра, прямо в холодець, всім тілом... Обличчя, руки... Коротше все.. М'ясо як кисіль стікало з черепа... А він у свідомості був... Плесни, душа горить... Кинув я його там... І душу свою теж там залишив... схованку ми залишили, не буду я її забирати, не хочу... Якщо знайдеш, пом'яни Сергія...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, une longue histoire ... Vous avez du temps pour écouter? ... Nous étions amis avec Seryoga Bezukhi, nous allions ensemble à des raids en profondeur ... Parfois, nous nous rendions jusqu'au vent du cerveau, voyions ces fantômes et pas seulement ... \nUn peu… Oui, Seryoga… Son oreille a été blessée par balle en Tchétchénie, d'où son surnom. Combien de fois avons-nous couvert le dos de chacun ... Lors de la dernière promenade, nous avons rencontré un Pseudo-géant, la créature n’est pas particulièrement dangereuse - à moins, bien sûr, que ce ne soit pas stupide de la jouer. Et voilà que cette créature se frappa les mains au sol, Seryoga fut jeté, eh bien, probablement pas plus d’un demi-mètre, droit dans le dos, avec tout le corps ... Visage, mains ... Bref tout ... De la viande comme celle de kissel drainée du crâne .. Et il était conscient ... Spill, l'âme brûle ... Je l'ai jetée là-bas ... Et j'ai laissé mon âme là aussi ... Nous avons laissé le secret, je ne le prendrai pas, je ne veux pas ... Si vous le trouvez, Rappelez-vous Seryoga...</fra>
		<pln>To długa historia... Masz czas?.. My z Sieriożą Bezuchym przyjaźniliśmy się, zawsze razem na głębokie wypady chodziliśmy... Któregoś razu do samego "Mózgozwęglacza" dotarliśmy, widzieliśmy te fantomy i nie tylko... \nChlapnij jeszcze trochę... Tak-a, Sierioża... Ucho mu odstrzelili jeszcze w Czeczenii, stąd i ksywka taka. Ileż to razy nawzajem się ratowaliśmy... W ostatnim wypadzie natknęliśmy się na pseudogiganta, stwór niezbyt groźny - oczywiście, jeśli nie leźć na niego bez głowy. A tutaj tak wyszło, że walnął ten stwór swoim łapskiem w ziemię, Sieriożę odrzuciło, nawet nie więcej niż pół metra, ale prosto w galaretę, całym ciałem... Twarz, ręce... No, wszystko.. Ciało jak kisiel spływało z czaszki... A on przytomny był... Polej, dusza boli... Zostawiłem go tam... I duszę swoją też tam zostawiłem... Schowek tam mieliśmy, nie będę do niego chodził... Jeśli znajdziesz, wspomnij Sieriożę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_73">
		<rus>Не могу я... Сломала меня Зона... Ещё день два и пойду выбираться...</rus>
		<eng>I can't... Zone has broken me... Two more days and I'll go out...</eng>
		<ukr>Не можу я... Зламала мене Зона... Ще день два і піду вибиратися...</ukr>
		<fra>Je ne peux pas ... Zone m'a cassé ... Encore deux jours et je sors...</fra>
		<pln>Nie mogę... Złamała mnie Zona... Jeszcze dzień-dwa i wynoszę się stąd...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_81">
		<rus>Помяну...</rus>
		<eng>I'll do...</eng>
		<ukr>Пом'яну...</ukr>
		<fra>N'oubliez pas...</fra>
		<pln>Wspomnę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_82">
		<rus>Правильно... Наверное...</rus>
		<eng>That's right... Probably...</eng>
		<ukr>Правильно... Напевно...</ukr>
		<fra>C'est vrai ... Probablement...</fra>
		<pln>Prawda... Pewnie tak...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здравствуй, поговорим?</rus>
		<eng>Hello, can we talk?</eng>
		<ukr>Здрастуй, поговоримо?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour, pouvons-nous parler?</fra>
		<pln>Witaj, pogadamy?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_1">
		<rus>Здравствуй, почему нет? Ты я смотрю не из этих говнюков...</rus>
		<eng>Hello, why not? I guess you are not one of those bastards...</eng>
		<ukr>Здрастуй, чому ні? Ти я дивлюся не з цих гівнюків...</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour, pourquoi pas? Vous, je ne regarde pas en dehors de ces abrutis...</fra>
		<pln>Witaj, czemu nie? Widzę, że ty nie z tych gówniarzy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_2">
		<rus>Нет, не из них... Давай по сто грамм?</rus>
		<eng>No, I am not... What about 100 grams?</eng>
		<ukr>Ні, не з них... Давай по сто грам?</ukr>
		<fra>Non, je ne suis pas ... Qu'en est-il de 100 grammes?</fra>
		<pln>Nie, nie z nich... Co powiesz na sto gram?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_3">
		<rus>А что... Неплохо... Наливай...</rus>
		<eng>Hm... Not bad... Pour...</eng>
		<ukr>А що... Непогано... Наливай...</ukr>
		<fra>Hum ... Pas mal ... Pour...</fra>
		<pln>A co... Nie odmówię... Nalewaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ну давай за знакомство...</rus>
		<eng>Well, let's drink to the acquaintance...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай за знайомство...</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, buvons à la connaissance...</fra>
		<pln>No to za znajomość...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_42">
		<rus>Эх, кончилась родимая...</rus>
		<eng>Oh, it's over...</eng>
		<ukr>Ех, скінчилася рідненька...</ukr>
		<fra>Oh, c'est fini...</fra>
		<pln>Eh, skończyła się...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_5">
		<rus>За знакомство... Хух, и где ты ее взял... Гадость голимая...</rus>
		<eng>To the acquaintance... Huh, where did you take it... It's awful...</eng>
		<ukr>За знайомство... Хух, і де ти її взяв... Гидота галіма...</ukr>
		<fra>À la connaissance ... Hein, où l'avez-vous prise ... C'est affreux...</fra>
		<pln>Za znajomość... Huu, a skąd żeś ty ją wziął... Pakudne draństwo...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_6">
		<rus>Да уж, не Смирнофф! Что слышно в Зоне?</rus>
		<eng>Yeah, it's not Smirnoff! What's new in Zone?</eng>
		<ukr>Ага, не Смірнофф! Що чути в Зоні?</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, ce n'est pas Smirnoff! Quoi de neuf dans Zone?</fra>
		<pln>Wiadomo, że nie Smirnoff! Co słychać w Zonie?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_71">
		<rus>Ну, слышно кое-что... Вроде есть тайники богатые, остались от сталкеров погибших... Есть тайные схроны клановых группировок, но никто не говорил что нашёл такой... Мне совершенно случайно попался КПК в котором отмечено место тайника, могу поделиться с тобой... Сам я наверно не дойду уже...</rus>
		<eng>Well, I heard something... It seems there are huge stashes left from the dead stalkers... There are stashes of clan groups, but nobody said that they found them... I accidentally got a PDA in which the loot place is marked, I can share with you... I guess I won't go there...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну, чути дещо... Начебто є схованки багаті, залишилися від сталкерів загиблих... Є таємні схрони кланових угруповань, але ніхто не говорив що знайшов такий... Мені зовсім випадково попався КПК в якому зазначено місце схованки, можу поділитися з тобою... Сам я напевно не дійду вже...</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, vous pouvez entendre quelque chose ... Il semble qu'il existe de riches caches, laissées par les harceleurs des victimes ... Il existe des caches secrètes de groupes de clans, mais personne n'a dit qu'il en avait trouvé ... J'ai accidentellement eu un PDA dans lequel le lieu de la cache a été marqué , Je peux partager avec vous ... Je ne vais probablement pas y arriver déjà...</fra>
		<pln>No, słychać to i owo... Że niby są schowki bogate, pozostałe po stalkerach co zginęli... Są tajne schrony ugrupowań klanowych, ale nikt nie mówił, żeby taki znalazł... Mnie zupełnie przypadkiem trafiło się PDA, w którym zaznaczono lokalizację schowka, mogę się z tobą podzielić... Sam już na pewno nie pójdę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_73">
		<rus>Приходи вечерком в Бар, соберутся наши, пообщаемся... Много полезного услышать можно, только не забывай выпивку выставлять...</rus>
		<eng>Come to the Bar tonight, our people will gather, we will talk... You can learn a lot of useful things, just do not forget to take some drinks...</eng>
		<ukr>Приходь ввечері в Бар, зберуться наші, поспілкуємося... Багато корисного почути можна, тільки не забувай випивку виставляти...</ukr>
		<fra>Venez au bar le soir, rassemblez les nôtres, discutez ... Vous pouvez entendre beaucoup de choses utiles, mais n'oubliez pas de prendre un verre...</fra>
		<pln>Przyjdź wieczorem do Baru, nasi się zbiorą, pogadamy... Dużo pożytecznych rzeczy można usłyszeć, byle nie zapominać kolejek stawiać...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_81">
		<rus>Спасибо, буду в тех краях - проверю...</rus>
		<eng>Thanks, if I am in that area, I will check...</eng>
		<ukr>Спасибі, буду в тих краях - перевірю...</ukr>
		<fra>Merci, si je suis dans cette zone, je vérifierai...</fra>
		<pln>Dziękuję, będę w tych stronach - zajrzę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ладно, приду...</rus>
		<eng>Ok, I'll come...</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, прийду...</ukr>
		<fra>D'accord, je viendrai...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, przyjdę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорово, старина. Как жизнь?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, old cap. How's your life?</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, старина. Як життя?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, vieille casquette. Comment va ta vie?</fra>
		<pln>Czołem, stary. Jak leci?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_1">
		<rus>Ключом бьёт... По голове... Чё надо?</rus>
		<eng>It could be much better... What do you want?</eng>
		<ukr>Ключем б'є... По голові... Що треба?</ukr>
		<fra>Cela pourrait être beaucoup mieux ... Que voulez-vous?</fra>
		<pln>Jak po grudzie... Czego chciałeś?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_2">
		<rus>Ты че сердитый такой7 Давай накатим для настроения?</rus>
		<eng>Why are you so angry? Let's drink to set the mood!</eng>
		<ukr>Ти чого сердитий такий? Давай накатимо для настрою?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi es-tu si en colère? Buvons pour créer l'ambiance?</fra>
		<pln>Coś ty taki wkurzony? Chodź, łykniemy dla poprawy nastroju?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_3">
		<rus>Достало уже всё! Выкатывай...</rus>
		<eng>I'm fed up with everything! Take it out...</eng>
		<ukr>Дістало вже все! Викочуй...</ukr>
		<fra>J'en ai marre de tout! Sortez-la...</fra>
		<pln>Wszystkiego mam już dość! Wyciągaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ладно! Наплюй на все... Поехали!</rus>
		<eng>Ok! Take it easy... Come on!</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд! Наплюй на все... Поїхали!</ukr>
		<fra>Ok! Allez-y doucement ... Allez!</fra>
		<pln>Dobra! Pluń na to wszystko... Jazda!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_42">
		<rus>Я лучше отвалю...</rus>
		<eng>I'd better go...</eng>
		<ukr>Я краще відвалю...</ukr>
		<fra>Je ferais mieux d'y aller...</fra>
		<pln>Lepiej sobie pójdę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_5">
		<rus>Ну давай... Хоть водку не разучились делать ещё...</rus>
		<eng>Ok... At least they still can make good vodka...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай... Хоч горілку не розучилися робити ще...</ukr>
		<fra>Allez ... Bien qu'ils n'aient pas oublié comment faire de la vodka...</fra>
		<pln>No jazda... Przynajmniej wódki jeszcze nie oduczyli się robić...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_6">
		<rus>Да чистая, как слеза комсомолки... А что достало-то?</rus>
		<eng>Yes, it's clean like a tear... And what are you fed up with?</eng>
		<ukr>Так, чиста, як сльоза комсомолки... А що дістало те?</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, c'est comme ... Et de quoi en avez-vous marre?</fra>
		<pln>Czysta, jak łza komsomołki... A co ci tak dopiekło?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да козлы кругом одни... Делаешь добро людям, а они говнищем мажут... Нашёл я нычку одну, думал с одним козлом вместе добраться, что бы было кому спину прикрыть... Так эта зараза свалила по тихому - даже ещё и рюкзак мой распотрошить успела... Тьфу... Люди... Козлы! Может сумеешь его опередить? Вот здесь этот тайник...</rus>
		<eng>Jerks are everywhere... You do people good and they screw over...I found one loot here and wanted to go there together with one jerk for us to cover each other's backs... But this bastard ran away and even emptied my backpack... Ugh... People... Jerks! Can you reach it faster than he? Here is the stash...</eng>
		<ukr>Та козли кругом одні... Робиш добро людям, а вони лайном мажуть... Знайшов я ничку одну, думав з одним козлом разом дістатися, що б було кому спину прикрити... Так ця зараза звалила по тихому - та ще й рюкзак мій розпотрошити встигла... Тьху... Люди... Козли! Може зумієш його випередити? Ось тут ця схованка...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, les chèvres sont toutes seules ... Vous faites du bien aux gens, mais ils ont mis le minable ... J'ai trouvé un petit, j'ai pensé avec une chèvre à se réunir, qu'est-ce que quelqu'un aurait à couvrir ... Cette infection est donc tombée dans le calme - même J'ai aussi réussi à vider mon sac à dos ... Ugh ... Les gens ... Les chèvres! Peut-être que vous pouvez le battre? Voici cette cache...</fra>
		<pln>Same durnie wokoło... Robisz ludziom dobrze, a oni cię gównem obrzucą... Znalazłem jedną skrytkę, chciałem z jednym dupkiem pójść, żeby było komu pleców pilnować... A ten skurwiel zwiał po cichu - nawet jeszcze i mój plecak wypatroszyć zdążył... Tfu... Ludzie... Świnie! Może uda ci się go wyprzedzić? O, tu jest ten schowek...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_73">
		<rus>Чудаков на букву М хватает, верить никому нельзя... Так и норовят подлянку сделать...</rus>
		<eng>There are too many jerks with no cojones , you can't trust anyone... Everyone tries to do dirt...</eng>
		<ukr>Чудаків на букву М вистачає, вірити нікому не можна... Так і норовлять подлянку зробити...</ukr>
		<fra>Assez avec la lettre M, ça suffit, vous ne pouvez en croire personne ... Alors ils s’efforcent de faire un tour...</fra>
		<pln>Sukinsynów nie brakuje, nikomu wierzyć nie można... Tylko patrzą, żeby jakieś świństwo zrobić...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_81">
		<rus>Попробую, если получиться - постараюсь вернуть тебе веру в людей.</rus>
		<eng>I'll go for it, maybe I can do. I'll try to make you trust people again.</eng>
		<ukr>Спробую, якщо вийде - постараюся повернути тобі віру в людей.</ukr>
		<fra>Je vais y aller, peut-être que je peux faire. Vous ferez de nouveau confiance aux gens.</fra>
		<pln>Spróbuję, jeśli się uda - postaram się przywrócić ci wiarę w ludzi.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_82">
		<rus>Злой ты, уйду я от тебя...</rus>
		<eng>You are mad, I'll leave you...</eng>
		<ukr>Злий ти, піду я від тебе...</ukr>
		<fra>Vous êtes en colère, je vous laisse...</fra>
		<pln>Zły jesteś, idę sobie...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет братан, мы раньше не встречались?</rus>
		<eng>Hey bro, have not we met before?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт братан, ми раніше не зустрічалися?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour mon frère, est-ce que nous nous sommes déjà rencontrés?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć braciak, czy myśmy się kiedyś nie spotkali?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да и твоя физия мелькала вроде, как тебя?</rus>
		<eng>I guess I saw your face too, what's your name?</eng>
		<ukr>Та й твоя фізія мелькала ніби, як тебе?</ukr>
		<fra>Je suppose que j'ai aussi vu votre visage, comment vous appelez-vous?</fra>
		<pln>I twoja gęba jakby nie obca, jak cię wołają?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_2">
		<rus>Меченым меня зови, все так называют...</rus>
		<eng>Call me Marked One, they call me like that...</eng>
		<ukr>Міченим мене клич, всі так називають...</ukr>
		<fra>Appelle-moi le Marqué, ils m'appellent comme ça...</fra>
		<pln>Nazywaj mnie Naznaczony, wszyscy tak na mnie mówią...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_3">
		<rus>Ладно, Меченый так Меченый, ну давай за знакомство? Есть с собой?</rus>
		<eng>Ok, Marked One, well, let's have a drink to the acquaintance? Do you have any?</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, Мічений так Мічений, ну давай за знайомство? Є з собою?</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, le Marqué, eh bien, allons boire un verre à la connaissance? Avez-vous une bouteille ?</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, Naznaczony to Naznaczony, może by tak za znajomość? Masz coś z sobą?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_41">
		<rus>А то! Вот! Крепкая, как мат монаха...</rus>
		<eng>Sure! Here is it! It's very strong...</eng>
		<ukr>А то! Ось! Міцна, як мат ченця...</ukr>
		<fra>Bien sûr! La voici! Et c'est très fort ...</fra>
		<pln>Aha! Jasne! Mocna, jak należy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_42">
		<rus>Нет, нету... Пришлось отдать за патроны весь запас...</rus>
		<eng>No... I had to give everything for cartridges...</eng>
		<ukr>Ні, немає... Довелося віддати за патрони весь запас...</ukr>
		<fra>Non, non ... j'ai dû abandonner toute la réserve de munitions...</fra>
		<pln>Nie, nie mam... Trzeba było cały zapas za amunicję oddać...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_5">
		<rus>Ха! Правда! Крепкая! Ну что брат Меченый, вот и двумя хорошими людьми больше в Зоне стало...</rus>
		<eng>Ha! True! Strong! Well, Marked One, this is how more two good people appeared in the Zone...</eng>
		<ukr>Ха! Правда! Міцна! Ну що брат Мічений, от і двома хорошими людьми більше в Зоні стало...</ukr>
		<fra>Ha! Vrai! Fort! Eh bien, frère le Marqué, il y a deux personnes de plus qui viennent d'apparaître dans la Zone...</fra>
		<pln>Ha! Prawda! Mocna! No cóż, bracie Naznaczony, i w ten sposób przybyło w Zonie dwóch dobrych ludzi...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_6">
		<rus>Говорят - можно хабар найти недалеко, не слышал?</rus>
		<eng>They say one can find some loot nearby, did you hear?</eng>
		<ukr>Кажуть - можна хабар знайти недалеко, не чув?</ukr>
		<fra>Ils disent que vous pouvez trouver à proximité, vous entendez?</fra>
		<pln>Nie słyszałeś, czy można gdzieś w okolicy towar znaleźć?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_71">
		<rus>Недавно забрёл я на Янтарь, посмотреть что там яйцеголовые окопались... Далеко не забирался, ибо мозг не казённый... Видел там этих бедолаг - сталкеров зомбированных. Стреляют правда как ворошиловские стрелки! Как так удаётся? Мозг же не работает? Нет? Один из них при смерти лежал, попытался я его обыскать - так - Мама моя родная! Из него как брызнет гадость какая-то, чуть коньки не отбросил, отравился... В общем, у него карта была с отметкой о схроне... Но я туда не рискну идти, а с тобой могу поделиться...</rus>
		<eng>Lately I went to Yantar to see what eggheads were doing there... I did not go far, as was afraid for my brains...I saw those poor fellows, zombified stalkers. But they are still sharpshooters! How is it possible? I thought their brains are not working. One of them was dying, I tried to search him. Holy crap, some awful spray came out of him, I almost passed out, poisoned... In general, he had a map with the mark of the loot place... But I will not risk going there, but I can share it with you...</eng>
		<ukr>Нещодавно забрів я на Янтар, подивитися що там яйцеголові окопалися... Далеко не забирався, бо мозок не казенний... Бачив там цих бідолах - сталкерів зомбованих. Стріляють правда як ворошиловські стрілки! Як так вдається? Мозок же ж не працює? Ні? Один з них при смерті лежав, спробував я його обшукати - так - Мама моя рідна! З нього як бризне гидота якась, мало ковзани не відкинув, отруївся... Загалом, у нього карта була з відміткою про схрон... Але я туди не ризикну йти, а з тобою можу поділитися...</ukr>
		<fra>Je me suis récemment promené à Yantar pour voir ce que les têtes de fouet étaient enfouis là-bas ... Je ne suis pas allé loin, car le cerveau n'était pas officiel ... J'y ai vu ces pauvres camarades - des harceleurs de zombies. Tirez sur la vérité comme des flèches Voroshilov! Comment est-ce possible? Le cerveau ne fonctionne pas? Non? L'un d'eux était étendu mort, j'ai essayé de le fouiller - alors - ma chère mère! Une sorte de merde jaillit de lui, presque jeté les patins, empoisonné ... En général, il avait une carte avec une marque de caches ... Mais je ne risquerais pas d'y aller, mais je peux partager avec vous...</fra>
		<pln>Niedawno zawędrowałem na Jantar, popatrzeć co tam jajogłowi robią... Daleko nie chodziłem, bo mózgu na wymianę nie mam... Widziałem tam tych biedaków - zombifikowanych stalkerów. Ale strzelają jak strzelcy wyborowi! Jak to możliwe? Przecież mózg nie pracuje? Nie? Jeden już uspokojony leżał, chciałem go obszukać - a tu - Mamusiu moja kochana! Jak z niego nie bryźnie  jakieś świństwo, mało nie zwróciłem, zemdliło mnie... Ale miał mapę z informacją o schowku... Ja nie zaryzykuję tam iść, ale z tobą mogę się podzielić...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_73">
		<rus>Весь хабар, который был в лёгких местах, подчистую выгребли... Нужно к центру Зоны пробиваться - говорят - там клондайк...</rus>
		<eng>They took all the loot in easy places... It is necessary to go to the center of the Zone - they say there is treasure trove...</eng>
		<ukr>Весь хабар, який був в легких місцях, дочиста вигребли... Потрібно до центру Зони пробиватися - кажуть - там клондайк....</ukr>
		<fra>Tous les butins qui se trouvaient dans les endroits faciles ont été nettoyés proprement ... Nous devons nous rendre au centre de la zone - ils disent - il y a un Klondike...</fra>
		<pln>Cały towar, który był w łatwych miejscach, wyczyścili do żywego... Trzeba do centrum Zony wędrować - mówią - tam klondike...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_81">
		<rus>Ладно, я рискну!</rus>
		<eng>Ok, I'll take a chance!</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, я ризикну!</ukr>
		<fra>Ok, je vais tenter ma chance!</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, ja zaryzykuję!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_82">
		<rus>Клондайк, говоришь? Ну-ну...</rus>
		<eng>Treasure trove? Indeed...</eng>
		<ukr>Клондайк, кажеш? Ну-ну...</ukr>
		<fra>Klondike, vous dites?Le trésor d'artéfacts? Bien, bien...</fra>
		<pln>Klondike, mówisz? No-no...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_0">
		<rus>Что так невесел, друг?</rus>
		<eng>Why are you so sad, friend?</eng>
		<ukr>Що такий невеселий, друже?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi es-tu si triste, mon ami?</fra>
		<pln>Coś taki zasępiony, przyjacielu?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да так, думаю - валить из Зоны надо... С каждым днем все хуже и хуже. Монстры все опаснее и злее, погода дерьмовая, аномалии не поймёшь где - а самое страшное - люди звереют...</rus>
		<eng>I think I should leave the Zone... Every day it gets worse and worse. Monsters get more dangerous and evil, the weather sucks, you can not understand where anomalies are - and the most terrible thing is that people become like brutes...</eng>
		<ukr>Та так, думаю - валити із Зони треба... З кожним днем все гірше і гірше. Монстри все небезпечніші і зліші, погода гівняна, аномалії не розумієш де - а найстрашніше - люди звіріють...</ukr>
		<fra>Oh, je pense - il est nécessaire de sortir de la zone ... Cela empire de jour en jour. Les monstres sont plus dangereux et plus méchants, par temps de merde, les anomalies ne peuvent pas être comprises là où - et le pire, les gens sont en train de devenir des bêtes...</fra>
		<pln>A tak, myślę - pora z Zony się wynosić... Z każdym dniem coraz gorzej i gorzej. Mutanty coraz niebezpieczniejsze i bardziej złe, pogoda do dupy, anomalie gdzie się nawet nie spodziewasz, a najstraszniejsze - ludzie się zezwierzęcają...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_2">
		<rus>Ладно, забей! Давай лучше накатим...</rus>
		<eng>Come on, forget about that! Let's have a drink...</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд, забий! Давай краще накатимо...</ukr>
		<fra>Allez, oublie ça! Buvons un verre...</fra>
		<pln>Dobra, zapomnij! Już lepiej coś wypić...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_3">
		<rus>Ну давай, а есть что?</rus>
		<eng>Ok, do you have?</eng>
		<ukr>Ну давай, а є що?</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, allez, mais en avez vous?</fra>
		<pln>Pewnie, a jest co?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_41">
		<rus>Не было б - не предлагал бы...</rus>
		<eng>If I didn't have, I would not offer...</eng>
		<ukr>Не було б - не пропонував би...</ukr>
		<fra>Si je n'en  avait pas de b - ne serait pas offrir...</fra>
		<pln>Jak by nie było - nic bym nie mówił...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_42">
		<rus>Вот дьявол! Была же ещё бутылка! Спёрли!</rus>
		<eng>Damn it! There was a bottle! They stole it!</eng>
		<ukr>До біса! Була ж ще пляшка! Сперли!</ukr>
		<fra>Bon sang! Il y avait une bouteille! Ils l'ont volé!</fra>
		<pln>Co za diabeł! Miałem jeszcze butelkę! Ukradli!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_5">
		<rus>Эх-р-р-м, не Шардонэ, конечно, но тоже ничего!</rus>
		<eng>Ohh, it's not Chardonnay, of course, but also good</eng>
		<ukr>Ех-р-р-м, не Шардоне, звичайно, але теж нічого!</ukr>
		<fra>Ohh, ce n'est pas du Chardonnay, bien sûr, mais c'est presque aussi bon!</fra>
		<pln>Eh-h-m, nie Chardonnay, ale też niczego sobie!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_6">
		<rus>А что за хабаром не идёшь?</rus>
		<eng>Why don't you go for loot?</eng>
		<ukr>А що за хабаром не йдеш?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi n’allez-vous pas chercher du butin?</fra>
		<pln>A czemu za towarem nie idziesz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да долгая история... Не спешишь?.. Мы с Серёгой Безухим друзьями были, все время вместе в глубокие рейды ходили... Иной раз до самого Мозговыжигателя добирались, видели этих фантомов и не только... \nПлесни ещё чуток... Да-а, Серёга... Ухо у него отстрелили ещё в Чечне, оттуда и кличка такая. Сколько раз мы друг другу спины прикрывали... В последней ходке на псевдогиганта нарвались, тварь не особо опасная - если конечно на неё не переть сдуру. А тут так получилось, что хлопнула эта тварь своей ручищей по земле, Серёгу отбросило, ну наверно не больше полуметра, прямо в холодец, всем телом... Лицо, руки... Короче всё.. Мясо как кисель стекало с черепа... А он в сознании был... Плесни, душа горит... Бросил я его там... И душу свою тоже там оставил... Тайничок мы оставили, не буду я его забирать, не хочу... Если найдёшь, помяни Серёгу...</rus>
		<eng>It's a long story... Aren't you in a hurry? .. We were friends with One-eared Sergei, we always carried out deep raids... Once we reached the Brain burner, saw phantoms and not only... \nPour little bit more... Well, Sergei... His ear was shot off in Chechnya, that's how he got his nickname. We covered each other's backs so many times... Last time we ran up against Pseudogiant, the creature is not so dangerous, unless you attack it. The creature smacked its hand down on the ground, Sergei was knocked out probably no more than half a meter in the air, that's the way he smashed. His body, face, arms...everything .. Meat was flowing down the skull like jelly.. And he was conscious... Pour, my heart bleeds... I left him there...And my heart is there, too... We left loot in that place... I will not take it, I do not want... If you find, drink to Sergei's memory...</eng>
		<ukr>Та довга історія... Не поспішаєш? Ми з Сергієм Безвухим друзями були, весь час разом в глибокі рейди ходили... Інший раз до самого мізковипалювача добиралися, бачили цих фантомів і не тільки...\nПлесни ще чуток... Да-а, Сергій... Вухо у нього відстрілили ще в Чечні, звідти і кличка така. Скільки разів ми один одному спину прикривали... В останній ходці на Псевдогіганта нарвалися, створіння не особливо небезпечне - якщо звичайно на нього не перти здуру. А тут так вийшло, що хлопнула ця тварюка своєю ручицьою по землі, Сергія відкинуло, ну напевно не більше півметра, прямо в холодець, всім тілом... Обличчя, руки... Коротше все.. М'ясо як кисіль стікало з черепа... А він у свідомості був... Плесни, душа горить... Кинув я його там... І душу свою теж там залишив... схованку ми залишили, не буду я її забирати, не хочу... Якщо знайдеш, пом'яни Сергія...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, une longue histoire ... Ne vous pressez pas? ... Nous étions amis avec Seryoga Bezukhi, nous allions ensemble à des raids en profondeur ... Parfois, nous nous rendions jusqu'au vent du cerveau, voyions ces fantômes et pas seulement ... \nUn peu… Oui, Seryoga… Son oreille a été blessée par balle en Tchétchénie, d'où son surnom. Combien de fois avons-nous couvert le dos de chacun ... Lors de la dernière promenade, nous avons rencontré un Pseudo-géant, la créature n’est pas particulièrement dangereuse - à moins, bien sûr, que ce ne soit pas stupide de la jouer. Et voilà que cette créature se frappa les mains au sol, Seryoga fut jeté, eh bien, probablement pas plus d’un demi-mètre, droit dans le dos, avec tout le corps ... Visage, mains ... Bref tout ... De la viande comme celle de kissel drainée du crâne .. Et il était conscient ... Spill, l'âme brûle ... Je l'ai jetée là-bas ... Et j'ai laissé mon âme là aussi ... Nous avons laissé le secret, je ne le prendrai pas, je ne veux pas ... Si vous le trouvez, Rappelez-vous Seryoga...</fra>
		<pln>To długa historia... Masz czas?.. My z Sieriożą Bezuchym przyjaźniliśmy się, zawsze razem na głębokie wypady chodziliśmy... Któregoś razu do samego "Mózgozwęglacza" dotarliśmy, widzieliśmy te fantomy i nie tylko... \nChlapnij jeszcze trochę... Tak-a, Sierioża... Ucho mu odstrzelili jeszcze w Czeczenii, stąd i ksywka taka. Ileż to razy nawzajem się ratowaliśmy... W ostatnim wypadzie natknęliśmy się na pseudogiganta, stwór niezbyt groźny - oczywiście, jeśli nie leźć na niego bez głowy. A tutaj tak wyszło, że walnął ten stwór swoim łapskiem w ziemię, Sieriożę odrzuciło, nawet nie więcej niż pół metra, ale prosto w galaretę, całym ciałem... Twarz, ręce... No, wszystko.. Ciało jak kisiel spływało z czaszki... A on przytomny był... Polej, dusza boli... Zostawiłem go tam... I duszę swoją też tam zostawiłem... Schowek tam mieliśmy, nie będę do niego chodził... Jeśli znajdziesz, wspomnij Sieriożę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_73">
		<rus>Не могу я... Сломала меня Зона... Ещё день два и пойду выбираться...</rus>
		<eng>I can't... the Zone has broken me... Two more days and I'll go out...</eng>
		<ukr>Не можу я... Зламала мене Зона... Ще день два і піду вибиратися...</ukr>
		<fra>Je ne peux pas ... La zone m'a cassé ... Encore deux jours et allez-vous en sortir...</fra>
		<pln>Nie mogę ja... Złamała mnie Zona... Jeszcze dzień, dwa i wynoszę się stąd...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_81">
		<rus>Помяну...</rus>
		<eng>I'll do...</eng>
		<ukr>Пом'яну...</ukr>
		<fra>Je ferai...</fra>
		<pln>Wspomnę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_82">
		<rus>Правильно... Наверное...</rus>
		<eng>That's right... Probably...</eng>
		<ukr>Правильно... Напевно...</ukr>
		<fra>C'est vrai ... Probablement...</fra>
		<pln>Prawda... Pewnie tak...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорово, братишка? Как оно?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, bro? How are you?</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, братику? Як воно?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, mec? Comment ça va?</fra>
		<pln>Czołem, bracie? Jak leci?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да вот, решил проверить истину, что непьющий дольше проживёт. Попробовал не пить неделю - мне показалось - прожил год...</rus>
		<eng>Well, I decided to check the truth that a nondrinker lives longer. I tried not to drink for a week, it seemed to me it lasted a year...</eng>
		<ukr>Та от, вирішив перевірити істину, що неп'ющий довше проживе. Попробував не пити тиждень - мені здалося - прожив рік...</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi, j’ai décidé de vérifier que le non-buveur vivra plus longtemps. J'ai essayé de ne pas boire pendant une semaine - il me semblait que je vivais un an...</fra>
		<pln>Więc, zdecydowałem się sprawdzić teorię, że niepijący dłużej żyją. Spróbowałem nie pić przez tydzień - wydało mi się - że rok minął ...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_2">
		<rus>Так может, выпьем? Не ради пьянки окаянной, а дабы не отвыкнуть?</rus>
		<eng>So maybe we should have a drink. Not for getting drunk, but in order not to get rusty?</eng>
		<ukr>Так може, вип'ємо? Не ради п'янки окаянної, а щоб не відвикнути?</ukr>
		<fra>Alors peut-être devrions-nous prendre un verre. Pas pour se saouler, mais pas pour se rouiller?</fra>
		<pln>To może wypijemy? Żadne pijaństwo, tak tylko, żeby się nie odzwyczaić?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_3">
		<rus>Какой вопрос?! А есть?</rus>
		<eng>Sure! You got some?</eng>
		<ukr>Яке питання?! А є?</ukr>
		<fra>Quelle est la question?! En avez-vous?</fra>
		<pln>Co za pytanie?! A masz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_41">
		<rus>Для такого случая всегда есть!</rus>
		<eng>I always got some for such a case!</eng>
		<ukr>Для такого випадку завжди є!</ukr>
		<fra>J'en ai toujours pour le cas ou!</fra>
		<pln>Na taką okazję zawsze jest!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_42">
		<rus>В том-то и дело, что нету.</rus>
		<eng>That's the problem, I don't.</eng>
		<ukr>У тому то й справа, що нема.</ukr>
		<fra>C'est le problème, je n'en ai pas du tout.</fra>
		<pln>W tym problem, że nie ma.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_5">
		<rus>Эх, провалилась, не заметил.</rus>
		<eng>Oh, I even did not notice.</eng>
		<ukr>Еех, провалилася, не помітив...</ukr>
		<fra>Oh, je n'ai même pas remarqué.</fra>
		<pln>Ech, wypadła, nie zauważyłem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_6">
		<rus>Ты слыхал - сталкер какой-то на днях в Бар пришёл. Говорят, нычку авторитетного наёмника обчистил. Радостный был, всем рассказывал, как он подобрал КПК этого наёмника где-то здесь, на Складах. На следующие сутки он куда-то пропал, и до сих пор его никто не видел, видать наёмники убрали. Вот так вот.</rus>
		<eng>Did you hear that a stalker came to the Bar some time ago. They say he robbed a high-powered contractor's stash. He was happy, telling everyone how he found that guy's PDA somewhere here, around Warehouses. The next day, he disappeared, and nobody has seen him, the contractors must have mopped. This is it.</eng>
		<ukr>Ти чув - сталкер какойто днями в Бар прийшов... Кажуть ничку авторитетного найманця обчистив. Радісний був, всім розповідав як він підібрав PDA цього найманця десь сдесь, на складах... На наступну добу він кудато пропав, і до цих пір його ніхто не бачив, видать найманці прибрали... Ось так ось</ukr>
		<fra>Vous avez entendu - un stalker est venu au bar l’autre jour. Ils disent qu'ils ont nettoyé le pseudo d'un mercenaire de bonne réputation. Il était joyeux, il a raconté à tout le monde comment il avait récupéré le PDA de ce mercenaire quelque part dans les entrepôts. Le lendemain, il a disparu quelque part, et toujours personne ne l'a vu, les mercenaires ont été vus. C'est comme ça.</fra>
		<pln>Ty słyszałeś - jeden stalker na dniach do Baru przyszedł... Mówią, że wyczyścił skrytkę jakiegoś ważnego najemnika. Uradowany był, wszystkim opowiadał jak zdobył PDA tego najemnika gdzieś tutaj, na Magazynach... Na drugi dzień gdzieś przepadł, i do tej pory nikt go nie widział, widocznie najemnicy go wzięli... Ano tak.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да фигня это всё! Мы этих наёмников шугаем как тараканов. Мы вот рейд на базу Долга устраивали, война была - ужас, но пробиться таки не смогли - грянул Выброс. Да мощный такой, мозги прямо закипели. Запнулся о труп долговца - мелькнул КПК, ну я его схватил. Пришлось спасаться на Дикой Территории. Засели в каком-то гараже, переждали Выброс... Вернулись на базу, я этот КПК исследовал и увидел метку на карте, вот тут. Проверить времени не было, так что вот, держи...</rus>
		<eng>Bullshit! We always share off these contractors. We carried out a raid on Duty's base, the war was horrible, but we could not get through - there was a blowout. So powerful, even my brains began to boil. I stumbled on a duty fighter's corpse, saw a PDA and grabbed it. We had to seek survival in the Wild Territory. We hid in a garage, waited out a blowout... Then we returned to the base, I checked this PDA and saw the mark on the map, right here. There was no time to check, so take it...</eng>
		<ukr>Та фігня це все... Ми цих найманців щугаєм як тарганів... Ми ось рейд на базу боргу влаштовували, війна була - жах, але пробитися таки не змогли - грянув викид, та мощьний такий... мізки прямо закипіли, запнувся об труп Долгівця - майнув КПК, ну я його схопив... Довелося рятуватися на Дикій Території... Засіли в какомто гаражі, перечекали викид... Повернулися на базу, я цей КПК досліджував і побачив мітку на карті вот тут, перевірити часу небуло, так що ось, тримай...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, les ordures c'est tout! Nous tuons ces mercenaires comme des cafards. Nous organisions un raid sur la base de la Devoir, la guerre était horrible, mais nous ne pouvions pas passer - la rafale a frappé. Oui, si puissant, le cerveau bouillonne directement. Il est tombé sur le cadavre du Devoir - le PCC a flashé, eh bien, je l'ai attrapé. Devait fuir dans le territoire sauvage. Nous nous sommes assis dans un garage, avons attendu l'éjection ... Nous sommes retournés à la base, j'ai enquêté sur ce PDA et j'ai vu la marque sur la carte, juste ici. Il n'y avait pas le temps de vérifier, alors voici, attendez...</fra>
		<pln>To wszystko nic... My tych najemników tłuczemy jak karaluchy... Zorganizowaliśmy atak na bazę Powinności, wojna była - że strach, ale przebić się nie daliśmy rady - przyszła emisja, i to wyjątkowo silna... mózg wprost zakipiał, potknąłem się o trupa powinnościowca - błysnął PDA, a ja go cap... Trzeba było uciekać na Dzicz... Schowaliśmy się w jakimś garażu, żeby emisję przeczekać... Jak wróciliśmy na bazę, ja to PDA dokładnie przejrzałem i znalazłem znaczek na mapie, o tu. Na sprawdzanie czasu nie było, tak że masz, trzymaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_73">
		<rus>Да чёрт с ним! Не фиг было выпендриваться, может бы и дольше прожил. Что-то меня на сон потянуло... Приходи ещё! Поболтаем о том, о сём.</rus>
		<eng>Hell yeah! He shouldn't have shown off, maybe he could live longer. I began to feel sleepy... Come again later and we will talk.</eng>
		<ukr>Та біс з ним. Нефіг було випендрюватися, може б і довше прожив. Чото мене на сон потягнуло... Приходь ще! Поболтаєм про те про се....</ukr>
		<fra>Bon sang! Pas figues ont été exhibés, aurait pu vivre plus longtemps. Quelque chose m'a fait dormir ... Reviens! Parlons de ceci et de cela.</fra>
		<pln>A pies go tańcował. Trzymałby język za zębami, może by i pożył dłużej. Coś mi się na sen zbiera... Przyjdź jeszcze! Pogadamy o tym i o tamtym.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_81">
		<rus>Мда, проверю как-нибудь, спасибо. До скорого.</rus>
		<eng>Hmm, I'll check it sometime, thanks. See you later.</eng>
		<ukr>Мда, перевірю як небудь, спасибі. До скорого...</ukr>
		<fra>Humm, je vais le vérifier de temps en temps, merci. A plus tard.</fra>
		<pln>Taa, sprawdzę przy okazji, dziękuję. Do zobaczenia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_1_dialog_82">
		<rus>Подойду конечно, о чём речь?</rus>
		<eng>Of course, I will come.</eng>
		<ukr>Підійду звичайно, про що мова?</ukr>
		<fra>Allez, bien sûr, de quoi parle-t-on?</fra>
		<pln>Przyjdę na pewno, co za pytanie?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорово, Макс! Как жизнь?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, Max! What's up?</eng>
		<ukr>Здарово, Макс! Як жизня?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, Max! Quoi de neuf?</fra>
		<pln>Zdrówko, Maks! Jak leci?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да как-то стрёмно, ряды пополнять никто не хочет... Может запишешься в наши ряды? Станет жить спокойнее...</rus>
		<eng>Not so good, nobody wants to enter the force... Maybe you'll join us? Your life will become quieter...</eng>
		<ukr>Та якось стрьомно, ряди поповнювати ніхто не хоче... Може запишешся в наші ряди? Стане жити спокійніше...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, en quelque sorte, idiot, personne ne veut remplir les rangs ... Peut-être pourriez-vous rejoindre nos rangs? Cela rendra la vie plus calme...</fra>
		<pln>A tak głupio, w szeregi wstępować nikt nie chce... Może wstąpisz do nas? Zaczniesz żyć spokojniej...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_2">
		<rus>Ну я как раз об этом думаю... Может бутылочку пропустим за знакомство?</rus>
		<eng>Well, I'm just thinking about it... Maybe we should drink to our acquaintance?</eng>
		<ukr>Ну я якраз про це думаю... Може пляшечку пропустимо за знайомство?</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, j’y réfléchis ... Pouvons-nous sauter une bouteille pour une connaissance?</fra>
		<pln>Aha, akurat o tym myślę... Może flaszeczkę rozpijemy za znajomość?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_3">
		<rus>Эх, побольше бы таких щедрых людей как ты... вот у меня как раз для такого дела пол кило колбаски сохранилось... Доставай эликсир!</rus>
		<eng>Oh, I wish there were more generous people like you... I have half a kilo of sausage for such situation... Take the elixir out!</eng>
		<ukr>Еех побільше б таких щедрих людей як ти... от у мене як раз для такої справи пів кіло ковбаски збереглося... Діставай еліксир!</ukr>
		<fra>Euh, il y aurait plus de gens aussi généreux que vous ... Ici, il ne me reste qu'un demi-kilo de saucisses ... Prenez l'élixir!</fra>
		<pln>Ehh, przydałoby się więcej takich szczodrych jak ty... a ja mam akurat na taką okazję pół kilo kiełbaski schowane... Wyciągaj eliksir!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_41">
		<rus>Во-от, настоящая! "Столичная"! Держи гранённый!</rus>
		<eng>Here is it, real! "Stolichnaya"! Hold the glass!</eng>
		<ukr>Ось, справжня! "Столична"! Тримай гранчак!</ukr>
		<fra>Voilà, c'est vrai! "Stolichnaya"! Tenez le verre!</fra>
		<pln>Jest, prawdziwa Ukraińska... "Kozacy". Trzymaj szklanki!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_42">
		<rus>Я ка-ак раз собирался к Шурупу, шас, если у него осталось, стрельну...</rus>
		<eng>I was going to Screw, if he has, I will take...</eng>
		<ukr>Я я-я-краз збирався до Шурупа, шас, якщо у нього залишилося, стрільну...</ukr>
		<fra>J'allais à Shurup, s'il l'a fait, je prendrai...</fra>
		<pln>Ja ee... akurat wybierałem się do Wkręta, momencik, jeśli u niego zostało, przyniosę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_5">
		<rus>Бррр... Печень моя не рада будет... Зачёт тебе в личное дело!</rus>
		<eng>Ugh... My liver will not be happy... It hit the spot!</eng>
		<ukr>Бррр... Печінка моя не рада буде... Залік тобі в особову справу!</ukr>
		<fra>Brrr ... Mon foie ne sera pas heureux ... Partez pour vous dans une affaire personnelle!</fra>
		<pln>Brrr... Wątroba nie podziękuje... Daje zdrowo!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_6">
		<rus>Ну что, Макс? И-ик... Что тут у-у вас происходит вообще?</rus>
		<eng>Well, Max, wha-a-at's going o-oh on here?</eng>
		<ukr>Ну що, Макс? І-ік... Що тут у-у вас відбувається взагалі?</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, Max, qu'est-ce qui se passe oh oh ici?</fra>
		<pln>No jak tam, Maks? E-epp... Co się tu u was w ogóle dzieje?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да вот, недавно Лукаш попросил сбегать на Барьер... Говорил, беда у них там какая-то... Ну я прихватил во-от этих вот обезьян, которые за костром сидят, видишь? Ну и на Барьер... А так - массированная атака зомби! Штук пятьдесят, наверное... Потеряли только снайпера, хотя я думал все поляжем. Ну а зомбированные - живучие гады, поэтому добивать хочешь-не хочешь, а нужно... Подхожу я значит к одному, а тот бормочет числа какие-то, несколько раз повторил, ну я "помог" бедняге. Когда вернулся - меня осенило, что цифры - это координаты, только вот координаты чего? Вот тут...</rus>
		<eng>Lately Lukash asked to run to the Barrier... He said that they had some kind of trouble there... So I took these monkeys who are sitting behind the fire, do you see? Well, the Barrier... there was a massive attack of zombies there! I guess there were fifty of them... We lost only a sniper, although I thought we would all be killed. Zombies are hard to kill, so even if you don't want, you have to beat them completely... I came up to one, he was muttering some numbers, he repeated them several times, well, I "helped" the poor fellow. When I returned, I realized that the numbers were coordinates, but the coordinates of what? Right here...</eng>
		<ukr>Та от, нещодавно Лукаш попросив збігати на Бар'єр... Говорив біда у них там якась... Ну я прихопив о-ось цих от мавп, які за багаттям сидять, бачиш? Ну і на Бар'єр... А там - масована атака зомбі! Штук п'ятдесят, напевно... Втратили тільки снайпера, хоча я думав всі поляжемо. Ну а зоммбованні - живучі гади, тому добивати хочеш-нехочеш, а потрібно... Підходжу я значить до одного, а той бурмоче числа якісь, кілька разів повторив, ну я "допоміг" бідоласі. Коли повернувся - мене осінило, що ці цифри це координати, тільки от координати чого? Ось тут...</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi, récemment, Loukache m'a demandé de descendre à la barrière ... Il a dit qu'il y avait une sorte de problème ... Eh bien, j'ai attrapé ces singes qui sont assis derrière le feu, vous voyez? Eh bien, sur la barrière ... Et alors - une attaque massive de zombies! Une cinquantaine de pièces, probablement ... Seul le tireur d’élite a été perdu, bien que j’ai pensé que ce serait un jeu d’enfants. Bien, les zombies sont des reptiles viables, alors tu veux tuer, tu ne veux pas, mais tu as besoin ... Je veux dire, je veux dire une chose, et il marmonne quelques chiffres, répétés plusieurs fois, eh bien, j'ai "aidé" le pauvre garçon. Quand je suis rentré, il m'est apparu que les chiffres ne sont que les coordonnées, seulement les coordonnées de quoi? Juste ici...</fra>
		<pln>Ano, niedawno Łukasz mówi, żeby iść na Barierę... Mówią, że jakieś nieszczęście tam się stało... No to ja biorę te swoje małpy, co to przy ognisku siedzą, widzisz? No i na Barierę... A tam - zmasowany atak zombie! Przynajmniej 50 sztuk... Straciłem tylko snajpera, chociaż myślałem, że nikt z nas nie wróci. No a zombifikowani - draństwo wyjątkowe, dlatego chcesz czy nie chcesz, a dobijać trzeba... Podchodzę znaczy do jednego, a ten mamrocze jakieś liczby, kilka razy powtarzał, no to ja "pomogłem" biedakowi. Kiedy wróciłem - mnie oświeciło, że te liczby to koordynaty, tylko że koordynaty czego? O tutaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_73">
		<rus>Да что тут у нас может происходить? Недавно план приносили - очуметь! Если хочешь приобрести, то обращайся к Скряге - он знает где взять. А ты приходи ещё, поболтаем...</rus>
		<eng>What can be here? Recently they brought dope, awesome! If you want to buy, then go to Skinflint, he knows where to get it. And come again, we'll talk...</eng>
		<ukr>Та що тут у нас може відбуватися? Нещодавно план приносили - ачумєть! Якщо хочеш придбати, то звертайся до Скнари - він знає де взяти. А ти приходь ще, побалакаємо...</ukr>
		<fra>Que peut-il se passer ici? Récemment apporté un plan - pour devenir fou! Si vous voulez acheter, référez-vous à Avare - il sait où aller. Et vous revenez, bavardez...</fra>
		<pln>A co tu u nas może się dziać? Niedawno zioło przynieśli - prawdziwy odlot! Jeśli chcesz coś dostać, to idź do Kutwy - on wie co i gdzie można znaleźć. A w ogóle przyjdź jeszcze, pogadamy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_81">
		<rus>Да эти зомбики постоянно что-то бубнят. Не обращай внимания.</rus>
		<eng>These zombies are constantly muttering something. Do not pay attention.</eng>
		<ukr>Та ці зомбики постійно щось бубонять. Не звертай уваги</ukr>
		<fra>Ces zombies murmurent constamment quelque chose. Ne faites pas attention.</fra>
		<pln>Te zombiaki ciągle coś bełkoczą. Nie warto zwracać uwagi.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_2_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ну, до встречи! Идти мне надо.</rus>
		<eng>Well, see you soon! I have to go.</eng>
		<ukr>Ну, до зустрічі! Йти мені треба.</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, à bientôt! Je dois y aller.</fra>
		<pln>No, do zobaczenia! Pora iść.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_0">
		<rus>Приветствую, мужики! Можно к вам?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, guys! Can I join you?</eng>
		<ukr>Вітаю, мужики! Можна до вас?</ukr>
		<fra>Hé les gars! Puis-je vous rejoindre?</fra>
		<pln>Witam panów! Można do was?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_1">
		<rus>Здоровы были, Меченый! Ну-ка, двиньтесь парни, дайте место авторитетному!</rus>
		<eng>Hey, Marked One! Well, guys, move, clear a space for the shots caller!</eng>
		<ukr>Здоровенькі були, Мічений! Нуж бо, посуньтесь хлопці, дайте місце авторитетному!</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, le Marqué! Bonne santé... Allez, passez les gars, donnez une place à ceux qui font autorité!</fra>
		<pln>Cholera, cześć Naznaczony! No co jest, posuńcie się trochę, zróbcie miejsce dla osobistości!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_2">
		<rus>Спасибо за гостеприимство! Душа просит ананасов в шампанском, а организм требует водки... Может, по стопочке?</rus>
		<eng>Thanks for your hospitality! My heart asks for pineapple in champagne, but my body requires vodka... What about a shot?</eng>
		<ukr>Спасибі за гостинність! Душа просить ананасів у шампанському, а організм вимагає горілки... Може, по чарочці?</ukr>
		<fra>Merci pour votre hospitalité! L'âme demande des ananas au champagne et le corps a besoin de vodka ... Peut-être un coup de feu?</fra>
		<pln>Dziękuję za gościnność. Może po maluchu?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_3">
		<rus>Вот это я понимаю! Вон как раз для этого дела кабанчик жарится! Ну, где "это дело"?</rus>
		<eng>That's the talk! Look, the boar is being fried for this! So where is it?</eng>
		<ukr>Ось це я розумію! Он якраз для такої справи кабанчик смажиться! Ну де "це діло"?</ukr>
		<fra>C'est ce que j'ai compris! Il y a juste pour cette affaire des rôtis de sanglier! Eh bien, où est cette entreprise?</fra>
		<pln>To ja rozumiem! Akurat jak na zawołanie szaszłyk się piecze! No to gdzie "Ta sprawa"?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_41">
		<rus>"Это дело" у меня всегда при себе! Держи!</rus>
		<eng>It is always with me! Take it!</eng>
		<ukr>"Це діло" у мене завжди при собі! Тримай!</ukr>
		<fra>C'est toujours avec moi! Prenez-le!</fra>
		<pln>"Tą sprawę" mam zawsze przy sobie! Trzymaj!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_42">
		<rus>Куда же я её засунул?.. Короче, где-то посеял. Шас к Скряге сбегаю...</rus>
		<eng>Where did I put it?.. In short, I lost it somewhere. I'll go to Skinflint for it...</eng>
		<ukr>Куди ж я її засунув?.. Коротше десь посіяв. Зара до Скнари збігаю...</ukr>
		<fra>Où l'ai-je mis?.. Bref, je l'ai perdu quelque part. Je vais aller à Avare pour ça...</fra>
		<pln>Gdzie ja ją wsadziłem?.. Chyba gdzieś posiałem. Zaraz skoczę do Kutwy...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_5">
		<rus>Бррр... Ты где эту бодягу взял? Скажи точку - брать там всегда буду!</rus>
		<eng>Ugh... Where did you take tainted vodka? Tell me the place, I'll always take it there!</eng>
		<ukr>Бррр... Ти де цю бодягу взяв? Скажи точку - брати там завжди буду!</ukr>
		<fra>Brrr ... Où avez-vous eu cette vodka contaminée? Dis-moi le point - je vais toujours le prendre là-bas!</fra>
		<pln>Brrr... Skąd ty tę gorzałę wziąłeś? Powiedz gdzie - zawsze tam będę brał!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_6">
		<rus>Да-а! Не говори - лучшая, какую я пил! Я её в нычке нашёл, тут неподалёку...</rus>
		<eng>Yeah! True, it's the best I've ever drunk! I found it in the stash, here nearby...</eng>
		<ukr>Та-ак! Не говори - найкраща, яку я пив! Я її в ничці знайшов, тут недалеко...</ukr>
		<fra>Ouais! C'est vrai, c'est le meilleur que j'ai jamais bu! Je l'ai trouvé dans la réserve, ici à proximité...</fra>
		<pln>Tak..! Nie ma co - najlepsza jaką piłem! Ja ją w skrytce znalazłem, tu niedaleko...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_71">
		<rus>Слушай, а может это Повар наш её заныкал на чёрный день? Пили как-то с ним, так он проговорился что во-от тут разгружается. Он же у нас дегустатор! Может сбегаешь? Будет продолжение банкета!</rus>
		<eng>Listen, maybe our Chef stashed it for a rainy day? We drank with him once, so he ran his mouth about unloading here. He's a taster! Can you run and check? And we will continue the banquet!</eng>
		<ukr>Слухай, а може це Повар наш її заникав на чорний день? Пили якось з ним, так він проговорився що о-ось тут розвантажується. Він же у нас дегустатор! Може збігаєш? Буде продовження банкету!</ukr>
		<fra>Écoutez, c'est peut-être notre Cuistot, qui l'a caché un jour de pluie? Ils ont bu avec lui d'une manière ou d'une autre, alors il a laissé échapper qu'il était en train de se décharger.C'est un dégustateur! Pouvez-vous courir et vérifier? Et nous allons continuer le banquet!</fra>
		<pln>Słuchaj, a może to nasz Kucharz ją schował na czarną godzinę? Piliśmy z nim raz, to się wygadał co tu się dzieje. On u nas za degustatora robi! Może skoczysz? Będzie przedłużenie bankietu!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_73">
		<rus>Жаль, а то бы я ящиками её выкупил, зачётная водичка! Ну если будет ещё - приходи! А я на боковую.</rus>
		<eng>It's a pity, otherwise I would have bought several boxes, perfect vodka! Well, if there is more, come! And I'm going to bed.</eng>
		<ukr>Шкода, а то б я ящиками її викупив, зачотна водичка! Ну якщо буде ще - приходь! А я на бокову.</ukr>
		<fra>Désolé, sinon je l'aurais acheté avec des boîtes, de l'eau valide! Eh bien, s'il y a plus - viens! Et je suis sur le côté.</fra>
		<pln>Szkoda, bo bym ją skrzynkami kupował, niesamowita wódka! Jak będziesz miał jeszcze - przychodź! Ja tu stale jestem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_81">
		<rus>Да... Повар, наверное, чемпион по литрболу в Зоне. Ну, увидимся...</rus>
		<eng>Yes... Chef must be a champion in the drinking competition in the Zone. Well, see you...</eng>
		<ukr>Так... Кухар напевно чемпіон по літрболу в Зоні... Ну побачимося...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui... Cuistot, probablement le champion de la boisson dans la Zone. Eh bien, à bientôt...</fra>
		<pln>Tak... Kucharz to na pewno największy czempion Zony w chlaniu ... No, do zobaczenia...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_3_dialog_82">
		<rus>Конечно, приду... Ну, гуд лак!</rus>
		<eng>Of course, I will come... Well, good luck!</eng>
		<ukr>Звичайно, прийду... Ну, гуд лак!</ukr>
		<fra>Bien sûr, je viendrai ... Et bien, bonne chance!</fra>
		<pln>Na pewno przyjdę... good luck!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_0">
		<rus>Привет! Что скучаешь? Что расстроенный такой?</rus>
		<eng>Hello! Why are you so bored and sad?</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт! Що сумуєш? Що засмучений такий?</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour! Pourquoi es-tu si ennuyé et si triste?</fra>
		<pln>Cześć! Coś taki smętny?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_1">
		<rus>Привет, Меченый. Да что же тут не скучать-то? Артефактов нет, баб нет, водки нет...</rus>
		<eng>Hey, Marked One. How not to get bored here? There are no artifacts, no women, no vodka...</eng>
		<ukr>Привіт, Мічений. Та чого ж тут не нудьгувати? Артефактів немає, баб немає, горілки немає...</ukr>
		<fra>Bonjour, le Marqué. Comment ne pas s'ennuyer ici? Pas d’artefacts, pas de femmes, pas de vodka ...</fra>
		<pln>Cześć, Naznaczony. A z czego tu się cieszyć? Artefaktów nie ma, bab nie ma, wódki nie ma...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_2">
		<rus>А не скажи... У меня где-то валялось пол литра...</rus>
		<eng>Not true... I had about half a liter somewhere...</eng>
		<ukr>А не скажи... У мене десь валялася півлітра...</ukr>
		<fra>Mais ne me dites pas ... j’avais environ un demi-litre quelque part...</fra>
		<pln>A nie gadaj... U mnie gdzieś walało się pół litra...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_3">
		<rus>Так что ж ты молчал-то? Падай рядом, вскрывай свой рюкзак. Вот у меня пара стаканчиков есть.</rus>
		<eng>So why did you keep silent? Have a seat and open your backpack. I have a couple of glasses.</eng>
		<ukr>Так чого ж ти мовчав? Падай поруч, розкривай свій рюкзак. Ось у мене пара стаканчиків є.</ukr>
		<fra>Alors pourquoi êtes-vous silencieux? Tombe près de toi, ouvre ton sac à dos. Ici, j'ai quelques verres.</fra>
		<pln>No, to czego nic nie mówisz? Siadaj tutaj, plecak otwieraj. Szklaneczki mam.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_41">
		<rus>Куда же я её положил? Ах вот она - на дне самом! Выпьем и за баб, и за арты!</rus>
		<eng>Where did I put it? Oh, here it is at the bottom! Let's drink to women and artifacts!</eng>
		<ukr>Куди ж я її поклав? А, ось вона - на дні самому! Вип'ємо і за баб, і за арти!</ukr>
		<fra>Où l'ai-je mis? Oh, la voici - au bas de l'échelle! Buvons aux femmes et aux artéfacts!</fra>
		<pln>Gdzież ja ją włożyłem? Aaa, jest - na samym dnie! Wypijmy i za baby, i za arty!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_42">
		<rus>Где же... куда я её? Погоди тут пару минут, шас сгоняю по одному адресу, будет чем поправить здоровье.</rus>
		<eng>Where... where did I...Wait a couple of minutes, I'll visit one place and bring it.</eng>
		<ukr>Де ж... куди я її? Зачекай тут кілька хвилин, зара зганяю за однією адресою, буде чим поправити здоров'я.</ukr>
		<fra>Où est ... où suis-je? Attendez quelques minutes, je vais à la même adresse, ce sera quelque chose pour améliorer ma santé.</fra>
		<pln>Gdzie żesz... gdzie ja ją? Poczekajcie tu parę minut, zaraz skoczę pod jeden adres, będzie czym poprawić zdrowie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_5">
		<rus>Ничего так у тебя арсенальчик... Покруче нашего будет... Стаканчики маленькие. Ну, пьём за прекрасный пол!</rus>
		<eng>You have cool armory... Better than ours... The glasses are small. Well, let's drink to women!</eng>
		<ukr>Нічо так у тебе арсенальчик... Покруче нашого буде... Стаканчики маленькі. Ну, п'ємо за прекрасну стать!</ukr>
		<fra>Vous avez un arsenal cool ... Mieux que le nôtre ... Les verres sont petits. Eh bien, buvons aux femmes!</fra>
		<pln>Niczego sobie arsenalik... Ale od naszego mniejszy... Kieliszeczki malutkie. No, za zdrowie płci pięknej!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_6">
		<rus>Пьём! ... Уух, хорошо пошла! Что слышно?</rus>
		<eng>Drink!... Uhh, it's good! What's new?</eng>
		<ukr>П'ємо! ... Уух, добре пішла! Що чути?</ukr>
		<fra>Bois! ... Euh, c'est bon! Quoi de neuf?</fra>
		<pln>Pijmy!... uuh dobrze poszła! Co słychać?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_71">
		<rus>Да вот, недавно посылали группу, и я в том числе, в Тёмную Долину, разведать проход туда прямо со Складов, сам понимаешь, мы тут как в клетке - с одной стороны Долг, с другой Выжигатель. Дело было по вечеру. Ну так вот наблюдали такую картину - быстрее пули бежит жиган бежит... ну мы в непонятках. Видимо он нас заметил и на нас вектор сменил - у нас челюсти поотвисали, думаем что за Рембо? Тут наш глазастый Роман говорит: "он там не один бежит", ну он с тепловизором шёл. Мы пригляделись - и в правду... Позади него как будто воздух искажался. Подбежал он ещё на метров 20 - тут мы поняли что дело плохо - за ним 4 кровососа!!! Пришлось положить всех, включая урку. Видать шестёрка какая-то. В КПК нашли точку на карте вот тут, без комментариев. У бедного бандюги джинсы все коричневые были - обсерился. Да любой бы на его месте пересрался бы с испугу.</rus>
		<eng>Lately they sent a group, including me, to the Dark Valley, to scout the passage there right from the depots, you understand, we are like in a cage here, on the one side there is Duty, on the other - Brain Scorcher. It was evening. So we saw the following: a rough was running faster than a bullet... We didn't get anything. Probably he noticed us and changed a direction. Our mouths were stuck open in shock because of that Rambo. Then our big-eyed Roman said: "He's not alone", well, he had a thermal camera. We looked carefully and saw that behind him the air was distorted. He ran about 20 meters and then we realized that it was bad. Behind him there were 4 bloodsuckers! We had to kill all of them, including the bandit. He must have been a garbage boy. In the PDA we found a mark on the map right here, no comment. The poor bandit's jeans were brown - he shitted his pants. Yes, anyone would fill their pants in his place.</eng>
		<ukr>Так от, нещодавно посилали групу, і я в тому числі, в Темну Долину, розвідати прохід туди прямо зі складів, сам розумієш, ми тут як у клітці - з однієї сторони Долг, з іншої Випалювач. Справа була ввечері. Ну так от спостерігали таку картину - швидше кулі жиган біжить... ну ми в непонятках. Мабуть він нас помітив і на нас вектор змінив - у нас щелепи повідвисали, думаємо, що за Рембо? Тут наш окатий Роман каже: "він там не один біжить", ну він з тепловізором йшов. Ми придивилися - і справді... позаду нього наче повітря спотворювалося. Підбіг він ще метрів на 20 - тут ми зрозуміли що справи погані - за ним 4 кровососа!!! Довелося покласти всіх, включаючи урку. Видноь шістка якась. У КПК знайшли точку на карті ось тут, без коментарів. У бідного бандюги джинси всі коричневі були - обісрався. Та будь-хто би на його місці обісрався би з переляку.</ukr>
		<fra> Pourquoi, nous avons récemment envoyé un groupe, y compris moi-même, à la Vallée Sombre, afin de surveiller le passage depuis les entrepôts, vous savez, nous sommes ici comme dans une cage - Devoir d'un côté, le brûleur de cerveaux de l'autre. C'était le soir. Eh bien, nous avons vu une telle image: une sangsue va plus vite qu’une balle, bien, nous sommes incompréhensibles. Apparemment, il nous a remarqués et nous a remplacés par le vecteur - nos mâchoires ont piqué, nous pensons que pour Rambo? Ici notre Romain aux grands yeux dit: "Ce n’est pas le seul à courir là-bas", eh bien, il marchait avec une caméra thermique. Nous avons regardé - et en vérité ... Derrière lui, comme si l'air était déformé. Il a couru encore 20 mètres - nous avons alors réalisé que la situation était mauvaise - derrière lui 4 suceurs de sang !!! Je devais mettre tout le monde, y compris le urku. On dirait une sorte de six. Le PDA a trouvé un point sur la carte ici, sans commentaires. Les pauvres voyous avaient tous un jean brun - obsité. Oui, n'importe qui à sa place aurait eu peur..</fra>
		<pln>Niedawno wysłaliśmy grupę, i ja też brałem udział, do Doliny Mroku, żeby znaleźć bezpośrednie przejście tam prosto z Magazynów, sam rozumiesz, my tu jak w klatce - z jednej strony "Powinność", z drugiej "Mózgozwęglacz". Było tak pod wieczór. No i widzimy taki obrazek - jakaś postać pędzi szybciej od kuli... a my nie wiemy co jest grane. Widać nas zauważył i zmienił kierunek na nas - a nam szczęki poopadały, cóż to za Rambo taki? Tu nasz sokole oko Roman mówi: "on tam nie jeden biegnie", bo on szedł z założonym noktowizorem. Przyglądamy się - faktycznie... za nim jakby zniekształcenie powietrza. Podbiegł jeszcze na jakieś 20 m - i zrozumieliśmy że jest kiepsko - za nim 4 pijawki!!! Trzeba było załatwić wszystkich, z tym urką włącznie. W PDA znależliśmy punkt na mapie i tyle, bez komentarza. U biednego bandyty dżinsy całe brązowe były - obsrał się. Ale każdy na jego miejscu ze strachu by się pofajdał.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_73">
		<rus>Постоянно слышно крики где-то тут неподалёку. Жуть прямо. А если по сути я как то не в курсе того что тут происходит.</rus>
		<eng>I constantly hear shouts somewhere nearby. Horror. But actually I have no idea what's happening here.</eng>
		<ukr>Постійно чутно крики десь тут неподалік. Жах прямо. А якщо по суті я якось не в курсі того що тут відбувається.</ukr>
		<fra>Constamment entendu les cris quelque part ici. Horreur droit. Et si en fait je ne sais pas ce qui se passe ici.</fra>
		<pln>Stale słychać krzyki gdzieś tu niedaleko. Normalnie aż strach. Widocznie faktycznie nie bardzo wiem co się tu dzieje.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_81">
		<rus>Мда, не повезло парню. Ну что давай на посошок и я пошёл.</rus>
		<eng>Hmm, the guy was out of luck. Well, let's have a drink and I will go.</eng>
		<ukr>Мда, неповезло хлопцеві. Ну що давай на посошок і я пішов.</ukr>
		<fra>Hmm, le gars n'avait pas de chance. Eh bien, prenons un verre et j'irai.</fra>
		<pln>Taa, nie miał chłopak fartu. Dawaj rozchodniaka i pójdę już.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_4_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ну тогда на посошок, и на боковую, устал я сегодня...</rus>
		<eng>Ok and then I will go to bed, I'm tired today...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну тоді на посошок, і на бічну, втомився я сьогодні...</ukr>
		<fra>Ok et ensuite je vais me coucher, je suis fatigué aujourd'hui...</fra>
		<pln>No to rozchodniaka, i na bok, zmęczyłem się dzisiaj...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорова, мужики!</rus>
		<eng>Hey, men!</eng>
		<ukr>Здорово, мужики!</ukr>
		<fra>Hé, les gars!</fra>
		<pln>Zdrowia, chłopy!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_1">
		<rus>Да не ори ты так, жуткое это место... неуважения не любит. Не маячь ты, присаживайся. Чего хотел?</rus>
		<eng>Do not shout that much, this terrible place... doesn't like disrespect. Do not loom, sit down. What do you want?</eng>
		<ukr>Та не кричи ти так, жахливе це місце... неповаги не любить. Не маячив би ти, сідай. Чого хотів?</ukr>
		<fra>Ne criez pas beaucoup, cet endroit terrible ... n'aime pas le manque de respect. Ne t'approches pas, assieds-toi. Que voulez-vous?</fra>
		<pln>Nie wrzeszcz tak, to dziwne miejsce... braku szacunku nie lubi. Nie marudź i siadaj. Co chciałeś?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_2">
		<rus>Да думал вот выпить с мужиками...</rus>
		<eng>I was thinking about drinking with the guys...</eng>
		<ukr>Так думав от випити з мужиками...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, je pensais que je boirais ici avec les gars...</fra>
		<pln>Chciałem wypić z ludźmi...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_3">
		<rus>Ну это как раз кстати, а то мы тут уже замёрзли. Доставай родимую.</rus>
		<eng>Well this is just in time, as we feel cold. Take it out.</eng>
		<ukr>Ну це якраз до речі, а то ми тут вже замерзли. Діставай рідненьку.</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, c’est la solution, sinon nous sommes déjà figés ici. Obtenez votre boisson.</fra>
		<pln>Akurat w porę, już tu prawie zamarzliśmy. Wyciągaj naszą kochaną.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_41">
		<rus>Чего-то, братец, не хватает. Может, выпить не мешает? Тащи стакан - я угощаю.</rus>
		<eng>Something is missing, bro. Maybe we should have a drink? Bring a glass, my treat.</eng>
		<ukr>Чогось, брате, не вистачає. Може, випити не завадить? Тягни склянку - пригощаю.</ukr>
		<fra>Quelque chose, mon frère, ne suffit pas. Peut-être que la boisson n'interfère pas? Apportez un verre, je soigne.</fra>
		<pln>Czego ci bracie brakuje? Wyciągaj szklanki - ja stawiam.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_42">
		<rus>Ну мужики, я думал вы меня угостите. Ладно сбегаю щас на базу, зацеплю бутылочку.</rus>
		<eng>Hm, guys, I thought you'd treat me. Okay I'll run to the base and take a bottle.</eng>
		<ukr>Ну мужики, я думав ви мене почастуєте. Гаразд збігаю зара на базу, зачеплю пляшечку.</ukr>
		<fra>Hum, les gars, je pensais que vous me traiteriez. D'accord, je vais à la base et prends une bouteille.</fra>
		<pln>No chłopy, myślałem, że to wy mnie ugościcie. Dobra, lecę na bazę, złapię jakąś flaszkę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_5">
		<rus>Уважаю, не дал умереть от холода... А мы тут сидим, ждём ребят, ждём... пошли в деревню зачищать логово кровососов... видать больше мы их не увидим... жаль парней... мда.</rus>
		<eng>My respect, did not let us die of cold... And we're sitting here, waiting for the guys...They went to the village to rob bloodsuckers' stash... I guess we won't see them anymore... too bad...</eng>
		<ukr>Поважаю, не дав померти від холоду... А ми тут сидимо чекаємо хлопців... пішли в село зачищати лігво кровососів... видно більше ми їх не побачимо... жаль хлопців... мда.</ukr>
		<fra>Respect, je ne me suis pas laissé mourir de froid ... Et nous sommes assis ici, attendant les gars, attendant ... sommes allés au village pour nettoyer le repaire de la sangsue ... plus nous ne les verrons pas ... désolé les gars,dommage...</fra>
		<pln>Szacun, nie dał zamarznąć... A my tu siedzimy i czekamy na chłopaków, czekamy... poszli do wioski czyścić legowisko pijawek... chyba już ich więcej nie zobaczymy... szkoda chłopaków... taa.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_6">
		<rus>Мда, у мня волосы на заднице дыбом уже стоят. Даже водка не помогает. А что тут ещё происходит?</rus>
		<eng>Hmm, hair on my ass stands like a mountain now. Even vodka does not help. And what else is happening here?</eng>
		<ukr>Мда, у мене волосся на дупі дибки вже стоїть. Навіть горілка не допомагає. А що тут ще відбувається?</ukr>
		<fra>Hmm, mes cheveux sur mon cul sont déjà dressés. Même la vodka n'aide pas. Et que se passe-t-il ici?</fra>
		<pln>Taa, mnie tu włosy na tyłku dęba stają. Nawet wódka nie pomaga. A co tu się jeszcze dzieje?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_71">
		<rus>Ооо, ты священную тему затронул. Про это место столько легенд ходит. До Выброса 2006 года эта деревня была похожа на деревню новичков как на Кордоне, и брат мой там жил. Все жили тихо мирно... Как вдруг грянул Выброс такой силы, что выжить удалось далеко не всем... крики... волны мутантов пёрли со стороны барьера, одна за другой. Выброс был где-то минут 10-15, а казалось все 3 часа, многие тогда потеряли своих друзей, на следующий день нас отправили забрать трупы и похоронить, да мы бы это и без приказов сделали бы... Нашёл я своего брата, понимаешь, своего родного брата, лежал он в подвале, смотреть было жалко. Взял я себе его ствол, вот видишь как блестит, и КПК. В КПК я нашёл единственную отметку на карте вот здесь, и ещё записку адресованную мне, но это уже личное.</rus>
		<eng>Ooh, you have touched on a sacred topic. There are so many legends about this place. Before the 2006 Blowout, this village looked like a village of newcomers in the Cordon, my brother lived there. Everyone lived peacefully... Suddenly a powerful blowout took place and not all could survive... screams... groups of mutants were coming from the side of the barrier, one after another. The blowout lasted around 10-15 minutes but it seemed like 3 hours, many people lost their friends, the next day we were sent to take corpses and bury, yes we would have done it without orders... I found my brother, you know , my own brother, he was lying in the basement, it was impossible to look. I took his gun, you see how it's shining, and his PDA. In the PDA, I found the only mark on the map here, and a note addressed to me, but this is personal.</eng>
		<ukr>Ооо, ти священну тему порушив. Про це місце стільки легенд ходить. До викиду 2006 року це село була схоже на село новачків як на Кордоні, і брат мій там жив. Всі жили тихо мирно... Як раптом грянув викид такої сили, що вижити вдалось далеко не всім... крики... хвилі мутантів перли з боку бар'єру, одна за одною. Викид був десь хвилин 10-15, а здавалося всі 3 години, багато хто тоді втратив своїх друзів, на наступний день нас відправили забрати трупи і поховати, та ми б це і без наказів зробили би... Знайшов я свого брата, розумієш, свого рідного брата, лежав він у підвалі, дивитися було шкода. Взяв я собі його ствол, ось бачиш як блищить, і КПК. У КПК я знайшов єдину позначку на карті ось тут, і ще записку адресовану мені, але це вже особисте.</ukr>
		<fra> Oooh, vous avez soulevé le sujet sacré. À propos de cet endroit tant de légendes disparaissent. Avant l’émission de 2006, ce village ressemblait à un village de recrues comme Cordona et mon frère y vivait. Tout le monde vivait dans le calme et la tranquillité ... Soudain, une explosion d'une telle force frappa que tout le monde ne réussit pas à survivre ... des cris ... des vagues de mutants se déversèrent l'une après l'autre du côté de la barrière. La libération a duré environ 10-15 minutes, et il semblait que toutes les 3 heures, beaucoup ont ensuite perdu leurs amis, le lendemain nous avons été envoyés pour ramasser les cadavres et enterrer, mais nous l'aurions fait sans ordres ... J'ai trouvé mon frère, vous savez , son frère, il était allongé au sous-sol, c’était dommage à regarder. Je me suis pris sa malle, vous voyez comme brillant, et le PDA. Dans le PDA, j’ai trouvé la seule marque sur la carte et une autre note m’adressant à moi, mais c’est personnel.</fra>
		<pln>Ooo, ty drażliwy temat poruszyłeś. O tym miejscu tyle legend krąży. Do wybuchu 2006 roku ta wioska była podobna do wioski kotów na Kordonie, i mój brat tam mieszkał. Wszyscy żyli cicho i spokojnie... Az nagle gruchnęła emisja takiej siły, że nie wszystkim udało się przeżyć... krzyki... fale mutantów które nacierały od strony bariery, jedna za drugą. Emisja trwała jakieś 10-15 minut, a wydawało się, że 3 godziny, wielu wtedy utraciło przyjaciół, na drugi dzień nas wysłano, żeby zebrać trupy i pochować, ale my byśmy to i bez rozkazu zrobili... Znalazłem swojego brata, rozumiesz, swojego rodzonego brata, leżał w piwnicy, patrzeć było żal. Wziąłem sobie jego broń, widzisz jak błyszczy, i PDA. W PDA znalazłem jeden znak na mapie, o tu, i jeszcze notatkę do mnie, ale to już osobista sprawa.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_73">
		<rus>Да много тут чего происходит... А вообще пореже ты сюда заходи - тут тебе весь зверинец Зоны. Тут и кровососы, и бюреры, и контролёры, и собаки, даже химеры бывает заглядывают...</rus>
		<eng>There are a lot of things happening here... But in general, don't come here so often, here there is a wild beast show of the Zone. Bloodsuckers, burers, controllers, dogs, even chimeras appear...</eng>
		<ukr>Та багато тут чого відбувається... А взагалі рідше ти сюди заходь - тут тобі весь звіринець зони. Тут і кровососи, і бюрери, і контролери, і собаки, навіть химери буває заглядають...</ukr>
		<fra>Oui, beaucoup de choses se passent ici ... En général, moins vous venez ici, vous êtes ici le zoo de la Zone. Ici, les sangsues, les burers, les contrôleurs, et les chiens, même les chimères tombent...</fra>
		<pln>Dużo się tu różnych rzeczy dzieje... A w ogóle lepiej tu często nie zachodzić - tu jest cały zwierzyniec Zony. I pijawki, i burery, i kontrolery, i psy, nawet chimera czasem zagląda...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_81">
		<rus>Мда, сочувствую, извини. Ну давай на посошок, у меня тут дел не в проворот.</rus>
		<eng>Hmm, I'm sorry. Well, let's have a drink, I have a lot of work to do.</eng>
		<ukr>Мда, співчуваю, вибач. Ну давай на посошок, у мене тут справ не в проворот.</ukr>
		<fra>Hmm, je suis désolé. Eh bien, prenons un verre, j'ai beaucoup de travail.</fra>
		<pln>Taa, współczuję, wybacz. No to dawaj rozchodniaka, mam trochę do zrobienia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_5_dialog_82">
		<rus>Спасибо за совет, но как-нибудь ещё увидимся.</rus>
		<eng>Thanks for the advice, but I'll see you somehow.</eng>
		<ukr>Спасибі за ражу, але як-небудь ще побачимось.</ukr>
		<fra>Merci pour le conseil, mais je vais vous voir.</fra>
		<pln>Dziękuję za radę, chyba się jeszcze zobaczymy.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_0">
		<rus>Здорова, хлопец. Есть чё закусить?</rus>
		<eng>Hey, pal. Is there any snack?</eng>
		<ukr>Здоров, хлопче. Є що закусити?</ukr>
		<fra>En bonne santé, parlez. Une collation?</fra>
		<pln>Zdrówko, chłopcze. Masz co zakąsić?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_1">
		<rus>Есть, а что?</rus>
		<eng>I have, why?</eng>
		<ukr>Є, а що?</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai, pourquoi?</fra>
		<pln>Jest, a co?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_2">
		<rus>Не хлебом единым жив человек. Нужно что-то и выпить. Ты как, согласен?</rus>
		<eng>Man does not live by bread alone. It's necessary to drink something. Do you agree?</eng>
		<ukr>Не хлібом одним жива людина. Потрібно щось і випити. Ти як, згоден?</ukr>
		<fra> L’homme ne vit pas que du pain. Il faut boire quelque chose. Êtes-vous d'accord?</fra>
		<pln>Nie samym chlebem człowiek żyje. Trzeba by coś wypić, To jak, zainteresowany?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_3">
		<rus>Как говорится: не откладывай на послезавтра то, что можно выпить сегодня. Так что, не будем откладывать?</rus>
		<eng>As they say: never put off until tomorrow what you can drink today. So, we will not put off, right?</eng>
		<ukr>Як то кажуть: не відкладай на післязавтра те, що можна випити сьогодні. Тому, не будемо відкладати.</ukr>
		<fra>Comme on dit: ne remettez pas à demain ce que vous pouvez boire aujourd'hui. Alors, ne remettons pas à plus tard?</fra>
		<pln>Jak to się mówi: co masz wypić jutro, lepiej wypij dzisiaj. To co, nie będziemy odkładać?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ну вот видишь? Что бы мы без друг друга делали? Уже сообразили поляну... держи стакан! За что пить будем?</rus>
		<eng>You see now? What would we do without each other? The table is ready... hold a glass! To what will we drink?</eng>
		<ukr>Ну ось бачиш? Що б ми без одне одного робили? Вже організували поляну... тримай стакан! За що пити будемо?</ukr>
		<fra>Vous voyez maintenant? Que ferions-nous l'un sans l'autre? La table est prête ... tenez un verre! A quoi allons-nous boire?</fra>
		<pln>No i widzisz? Co my byśmy bez siebie zrobili? I już mamy piknik... trzymaj szklankę! Za co będziemy pić?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_42">
		<rus>Жаль, у меня тоже нет.</rus>
		<eng>Sorry, I don't have either.</eng>
		<ukr>Шкода, у мене теж немає.</ukr>
		<fra>Désolé, je n'en ai pas non plus.</fra>
		<pln>Szkoda, ja też nie mam.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_5">
		<rus>Оперативно однако. Будем пить за то чтобы всегда были такие люди как ты, и чтобы они всегда находили таких людей как я! Ну давай! Уух, горькая зараза!</rus>
		<eng>Fast. We will drink to the people like you, for them to find people like me! Cheers! Ouch, it's bitter!</eng>
		<ukr>Однак, оперативно. Будемо пити за те щоб завжди були такі люди як ти, і щоб вони завжди знаходили таких людей як я! Ну давай! Уух гірка зараза!</ukr>
		<fra>Toutefois, sur le plan opérationnel. Nous allons boire pour faire en sorte qu'il y ait toujours des gens comme vous et qu'ils trouvent toujours des gens comme moi! Viens! Wow, une infection amère!</fra>
		<pln>W zasadzie wszystko jedno. Będziemy pić za to, żeby zawsze byli tacy ludzie jak ty, i żeby oni zawsze znajdowali ludzi takich jak ja! No ciach! Uuh, gorzka zaraza!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_6">
		<rus>Не говори... Жжёт! ты может быть знаешь, случаем, того, чего я не знаю, а?</rus>
		<eng>You tell me!... Burning! Maybe you know, by chance, something that I do not know, eh?</eng>
		<ukr>Не говори... Пече! Ти, випадково, не знаєш чогось такого чого не знаю я?</ukr>
		<fra>Ne dites pas… ça brûle! vous savez peut-être, par hasard, ce que je ne sais pas, hein?</fra>
		<pln>Nie gadaj... Piecze! Być może ty wiesz, przypadkiem, to, czego ja nie wiem, co?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_71">
		<rus>Ну, братела, ты, наверное, тут всю Зону сам исколесил... Нет? Ты что-нибудь знаешь о Мёртвом городе? Нет? Там основная база наёмников. Взяли меня в плен где-то пол года назад . Ну все по правилам киллерского дела - мешок на голову, прикладом по чайнику и повезли в неизвестном направлении... Привезли, начали выпытывать из меня как пробраться к нам на базу в тихую... ну я естественно ни слова им не сказал. Оставили меня на ночь в клетке. На против меня ещё двое были... один кстати очень на тебя был похож... чета там общались насчёт как оттуда слинять... заметил я там карту Зоны... точки какие-то, ну запомнить смог только одну вот здесь вот вроде она была... потом меня выволокли и по башке дали прикладом, очнулся уже в машине, с капюшоном на голове. Выволокли, поставили на краю обрыва, говорят типа - последнее желание... и тут, к моему счастью - Выброс... пришлось спрыгнуть. Это оказалось какое-то болото, посреди болота - вагончик, в нем переждал Выброс. Оказалось привезли они меня на Агропром... еле до дома добрался... Рассказал всем - не поверили, ибо я сильно не трезвый был, сам понимаешь, пережить такое...</rus>
		<eng>Well, brother, you probably walked around all the Zone... Didn't you? Do you know anything about the Dead City? No? There is the main base of mercenaries there. They took me prisoner about half a year ago. Everything was according to the rules of the killer case - put a bag on the head, hit in the pate with a gun-butt and drove in an unknown direction... They brought me, began to ask the way to our base... of course, I did not say a word to them. They left me in the cage for the night. There were two more opposite me... one by the way looked like you... they discussed how to get out of there... I noticed there was a map of the Zone... some marks, but I remember only one, I guess it was here... then they dragged me out and hit me again with a butt, I woke up in the car, with a hood on my head. They dragged me out, put on the edge of the cliff and asked what my last wish was... and then, lucky for me, a blowout... I had to jump. It turned out to be a swamp, in the middle of the swamp there was a trailer, in it I waited out the blowout. It appeared they brought me to the Agroprom... I hardly reached home... I told everyone, they did not believe me, because I was not sober, you know, after all this...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну, брателла, ти напевно тут всю зону сам об'їздив... Ні? Ти що небудь знаєш про Мертве Місто? Ні? Там основна база найманців. Взяли мене в полон десь пів року тому. Ну все за правилами кілерського діла - мішок на голову, прикладом по чайнику і повезли в невідомому напрямку... Привезли, почали випитувати з мене як пробратися до нас на базу в тиху... ну я природно ні слова їм не сказав. Залишили мене на ніч у клітці. На проти мене ще двоє були... один, доречі, дуже на тебе був схожий... щось там спілкувалися на рахунок як звідти злиняти... помітив я там карту зони... точки якісь, ну запам'ятати зміг тільки одну ось тут ось ніби вона була... потім мене виволокли і по довбешці дали прикладом, прокинувся вже в машині, з капюшоном на голові. Виволокли, поставили на краю обриву, кажуть типу - останнє бажання... і тут, на моє щастя - викид... довелося зістрибнути. Це виявилося якесь болото, посеред болота - вагончик, в ньому перечекав викид. Виявилося привезли вони мене на Агропром... ледве до будинку добрався... Розповів всім - не повірили, бо я сильно не тверезий був, сам розумієш, пережити таке...</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien,mon frère, probablement, ici vous avez parcouru toute la zone ... Non? Savez-vous quelque chose à propos de la ville morte? Non? Là, la base principale de mercenaires. Ils m'ont fait prisonnier il y a environ six mois. Eh bien, tout est conforme aux règles de l'affaire du tueur - un sac sur la tête, une crosse sur une théière et emmenés dans une direction inconnue ... Ils m'ont amené et ont commencé à me demander comment aller à notre base dans un endroit calme ... eh bien, je ne leur ai naturellement pas dit un mot. M'a laissé dans une cage pour la nuit. Deux autres étaient contre moi ... l'un d'entre eux était d'ailleurs très semblable à vous ... le couple a expliqué comment éjecter de là ... j'ai remarqué un plan du site là-bas ... certains points, eh bien, je ne m'en souvenais plus ici comme si elle était ... alors ils m'ont traîné dehors et m'ont donné un coup de tête sur la tête, je me suis déjà réveillé dans la voiture, avec un capuchon sur la tête. Ils l'ont sorti, l'ont mis au bord d'une falaise, ils ont dit: "dernier souhait ... et ensuite, pour mon bonheur" - Libération ... j'ai dû sauter. Il s’est avéré qu’il s’agissait d’une sorte de marécage, au milieu du marais - une remorque, dans laquelle il attendait son congé. En fin de compte, ils m'ont amené à Agroprom ... Je suis à peine arrivé à la maison ... J'ai dit à tout le monde - ils ne l'ont pas cru, parce que je n'étais pas très sobre, vous savez, survivre après tout ça...</fra>
		<pln>No, braciak, ty przecież na pewno już sam całą Zonę tam i z powrotem obleciałeś... Nie? Wiesz cokolwiek o Martwym Mieście? Nie? Tam jest główna baza najemników. Wzięli mnie do niewoli jakieś pół roku temu . Wszystko według kilerskich zasad - worek na głowę, kolbą w plecy i powieźli w nieznanym kierunku... Przywieźli, zaczęli mnie wypytywać, jak po cichu dostać się do bazy... ale ja naprawdę ani słowa im nie powiedziałem. Zostawili mnie na noc w klatce. Naprzeciw mnie jeszcze dwóch było... jeden nawet bardzo do ciebie był podobny... trochę tam gadaliśmy na temat jak stąd uciec... Zauważyłem tam mapę Zony... jakieś kropki, ale zapamiętałem tylko jedną, gdzieś tutaj jakby była... potem mnie wywlekli i po głowie dali kolbą, ocknąłem się już w samochodzie, z kapturem na głowie. Wywlekli, postawili na skraju urwiska, gadka w rodzaju - ostatnie życzenie... I tu, na moje szczęście - emisja... trzeba było zeskoczyć. Okazało się, że to jakieś bagno, pośrodku bagna - wagonik, w nim przeczekałem emisję. Oni mnie na Agroprom przywieźli... ledwo do domu dotarłem... Opowiedziałem wszystkim - nie uwierzyli, bo ja też mocno nietrzeźwy byłem, sam rozumiesz, przeżyć takie coś...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_73">
		<rus>Ой, да куда мне? Я тут целыми меня сюда только неделю назад поставили, так что ниче тут интересного не видел. Приходи позже, может что и разузнаю.</rus>
		<eng>Me? I am here all day long, they brought me here only a week ago, so I did not see anything interesting. I will come back later, maybe I'll find out something.</eng>
		<ukr>Ой, та куди мені? Мене сюди тільки тиждень тому поставили, так що нічо тут цікавого не бачив. Приходь пізніше, може щось і дізнаюся.</ukr>
		<fra>Oh, où suis-je? Je suis ici depuis une semaine et je n’ai rien vu d’intéressant ici. Revenez plus tard, peut-être découvrir.</fra>
		<pln>A ja to skąd mam niby wiedzieć? Ja tu siedzę cały czas, mnie dopiero tydzień temu postawili, tak że nic tu ciekawego nie widziałem. Przyjdź później, może czegoś się i dowiem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_81">
		<rus>Интересно, чудо вообще что ты жив остался. Ну, бывай.</rus>
		<eng>Interesting, it's a miracle that you are alive. Well, take care.</eng>
		<ukr>Цікаво, чудо взагалі що ти живий залишився. Ну, бувай.</ukr>
		<fra>Je me demande si c’est un miracle que vous ayez survécu. Eh bien, soyez sûr.</fra>
		<pln>Ciekawe, cud prawdziwy, że w ogóle przeżyłeś. No, bywaj.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_6_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ну ладно, зайду как-нибудь. До встречи.</rus>
		<eng>Well, I'll come later. See you.</eng>
		<ukr>Ну гаразд, зайду як-небудь. До зустрічі</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, je viendrai plus tard. A bientôt.</fra>
		<pln>No dobra, zajdę przy okazji. Do zobaczenia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_0">
		<rus>Чё бледный-то такой?</rus>
		<eng>Why are you so pale?</eng>
		<ukr>Чого блідий то такий?</ukr>
		<fra> Pourquoi es-tu si pâle?</fra>
		<pln>Coś taki blady?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_1">
		<rus>Холодина то какая...</rus>
		<eng>It's so cold...</eng>
		<ukr>Чолоднеча то яка...</ukr>
		<fra>Il fait si froid...</fra>
		<pln>Zimno jak diabli...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_2">
		<rus>А чё не согреешься?</rus>
		<eng>Why don't you warm up?</eng>
		<ukr>А чого не зігрієшся?</ukr>
		<fra>Pourquoi ne peux-tu pas avoir chaud?</fra>
		<pln>To czemu się nie rozgrzejesz?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_3">
		<rus>Было бы чем...</rus>
		<eng>Only if I had...</eng>
		<ukr>Було б чим...</ukr>
		<fra>Seulement si j'avais...</fra>
		<pln>Trzeba mieć czym...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_41">
		<rus>Ну я тебе помогу в этом деле! Держи! За что пьём?</rus>
		<eng>Well, I can help you! Hold it! To what will we drink?</eng>
		<ukr>Ну я тобі допоможу в цій справі! Тримай! За що п'ємо?</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, je vais vous aider dans cette affaire! Tiens bon! Que buvons-nous?</fra>
		<pln>No, to ja ci pomogę w tej sprawie! Trzymaj! Za co pijemy?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_42">
		<rus>И я тут мёрзну... Думал кто согреет.</rus>
		<eng>And I'm freezing here... I thought who would warm me.</eng>
		<ukr>І я тут мерзну... Думав хто зігріє.</ukr>
		<fra>Et je gèle ici ... Je pensais que quelqu'un réchaufferait.</fra>
		<pln>I ja tu marznę... Myślałem, że ktoś będzie miał coś na rozgrzewkę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_5">
		<rus>Пьём за то, чтобы завтра было за что выпить! Уух, крепкая. На, закусишь сразу колбаской.</rus>
		<eng>Let's drink to having something to drink to tomorrow! Ugh, strong. Take, eat some sausage.</eng>
		<ukr>П'ємо за те щоб завтра було за що випити! Уух, міцна. На закуси відразу ковбаскою.</ukr>
		<fra>Bois pour que demain soit quelque chose à boire! Wow, fort. Sur, prenez une collation immédiatement saucisse.</fra>
		<pln>Pijemy za to, żeby jutro było za co wypić! Uuh, mocna. Masz, zakąś od razu kiełbaską.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_6">
		<rus>Мда, спасибо. Слушай, где тут хабаром разжиться можно?</rus>
		<eng>Hmm, thanks. Listen, where can I get some loot here?</eng>
		<ukr>Мда, спасибі. Слухай, де тут хабаром розжитися можна?</ukr>
		<fra>Hmm, merci. Écoutez, où est-il possible de se procurer un butin?</fra>
		<pln>Taa, dziękuję. Słuchaj, gdzie tu fanty można jakieś znaleźć?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_71">
		<rus>Ну с этим сейчас у всех проблемы. говорят есть хабарок за барьером, но суваться туда опасно. Убедился на своём опыте - денег не было, много кому должен был, ну судьба вынудила двинуться за барьер. Иду... вокруг тишина... смотрю что-то впереди шевелится, ну я за камень. Запнулся, оказался лицом к лицу с давним знакомым моим, пропал он давно уже, только сейчас он уже полуразложившийся был, как вспомню блевать тянет. Ну он был авторитетным сталкером, ВАЛ-ом сумел разжиться. Ну я рюкзак с него снял, зачем, думаю, он ему нужен? Только приподнялся - смотрю монолитовцы общаются с мычащими... Втирают им типа "Во имя монолита...", тьфу, ну я быстрым ходом в обратном направлении... и буквально через пол часа отбивались от полусотни зомбарей. Вот так вот. В КПК нашёл пару схронов вот тут и тут. Вот этот я по пути обчистил, а до другого в лень идти, да и нагружен был под самое ни хочу, и в местах тех я не разу не был...</rus>
		<eng>Well, it's problematic now. They say there is loot behind the barrier, but it's dangerous to go there. I was convinced by my own experience - I had no money and owed a lot of people, so my fate forced me to move behind the barrier. I went... silence around... I saw something was moving, I stumbled on a stone and faced my old friend, he disappeared long ago, but then he was partially decomposed, when I recall it, I want to puke. Well, he was a respected stalker, he knew how to make a haul.  Well, I took off his backpack, why would he need it? When I stood up, I saw Monolithians talking with the mumbling... They told them something like "In the name of a Monolith...", ugh, well, I ran in the opposite direction... and literally in half an hour was defending myself against fifty zombies. This is it. In the PDA I found a couple of stashes here and there. This one I cleaned up on the way, as for that, I was too lazy to go there, had too many things to carry, and I've never been there...</eng>
		<ukr>Ну з цим зараз у всіх проблеми. кажуть є хабарок за бар'єром, але лізти туди небезпечно. Переконався на власному досвіді - грошей не було, багато кому боргував, ну доля змусила рушити за бар'єр. Іду... навколо тиша... дивлюся щось попереду ворушиться, ну я за камінь. Запнувся, опинився віч-на-віч з давнім знайомим моїм, пропав він давно вже, тільки зараз він вже напіврозклався, як згадаю блювати тягне. Ну він був авторитетним сталкером, ВАЛ-ом зумів розжитися. Ну я рюкзак з нього зняв, навіщо, думаю, він йому потрібен..? Тільки підвівся - дивлюся монолітівці спілкуються з мукючими... Втирають їм типу "В ім'я моноліту...", тьфу, ну я швидким ходом у зворотному напрямку... і буквально через пів години відбивалися від півсотні зомбі. Ось так от. У КПК знайшов пару схронів ось тут і тут. Ось цей я по шляху обчистив, а до іншого ліньки йти, та й навантажений був під саме нехочу, і в місцях тих я ні разу не був...</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, maintenant tout le monde a des problèmes avec cela. Ils disent qu’il ya un butin derrière la barrière, mais c’est dangereux d’y aller. Ma propre expérience m'a convaincu - il n'y avait pas d'argent, j'avais beaucoup de gens, eh bien, le destin nous a forcés à passer la barrière. Je vais ... autour du silence ... Je regarde quelque chose qui bouge devant moi, eh bien, je suis pour une pierre. Il a hésité, s'est retrouvé face à face avec une de mes connaissances, il avait disparu il y a longtemps. Seulement maintenant, il est déjà à moitié décomposé. Eh bien, il était un harceleur de bonne réputation, que VAL-th a réussi à se procurer. Eh bien, j'ai enlevé mon sac à dos, pourquoi je pense qu'il a besoin de lui? Je viens juste de me lever - je regarde les monolithes qui communiquent avec les bas ... Ils les ont frottés comme: "Au nom d'un monolithe ...", hum, eh bien, je vais vite dans la direction opposée ... et littéralement une demi-heure plus tard, nous avons combattu cinquante zombies. C'est comme ça. Dans le PCC, j'ai trouvé quelques caches ici et ici. J'ai nettoyé celui-ci en cours de route, mais je suis trop paresseux pour aller à l'autre, et je ne veux pas être chargé, et je ne suis jamais allé dans ces endroits-là...</fra>
		<pln>No, z tym teraz u wszystkich problemy. Mówią, że jest towarek za Barierą, ale iść tam niebezpiecznie. Przekonałem się na własnym przykładzie - kasy nie było, długów sporo, i los przymusił iść za Barierę. Idę... cisza wokół... widzę że coś się z przodu rusza, to ja za kamień. Obracam się, i twarzą w twarz ze starym znajomym, który przepadł już dawno, tylko że teraz on już na wpół rozłożony był, jak wspomnę to mnie mdli. To był doświadczony stalker, Wal-em umiał się posługiwać. Zdjąłem z niego plecak, po co, myślę, on mu potrzebny..? Zdążyłem się podnieść - widzę jak monolitowcy rozmawiają z zombiakami... Wciskają im teksty w rodzaju "W imieniu monolitu...", tfu, no to ja szybkim krokiem w odwrotnym kierunku... i dosłownie przez pół godziny uciekałem przed pół setką zombie. Ano tak. W PDA znalazłem parę schowków, o tu i tu. Ten ja sam po drodze wyczyściłem, i do drugiego już mi się nie chciało iść, a i obciążony byłem po zęby, dlatego w tych miejscach nie byłem ani razu...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_73">
		<rus>Ну говорят на Агропроме бывали когда то раньше горы артефактов, теперь не знаю... Ладно, Меченый, если что, заходи.</rus>
		<eng>Well, they say there were mountains of artifacts in the Agroprom long ago, now I do not know... Ok, Marked One, if there is something, come.</eng>
		<ukr>Ну кажуть на Агропромі бували колись раніше гори артефактів, тепер не знаю... Гаразд, Мічений, якщо що, заходь.</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, ils parlent à Agroprom quand il y avait des montagnes d’artéfacts, maintenant je ne sais pas ... Ok, le Marqué, si vous voulez, entrez.</fra>
		<pln>Mówią, że na Agropromie bywały kiedyś góry artefaktów, teraz nie wiem... Dobra, Naznaczony, jak by co, przychodź.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_81">
		<rus>Повезло тебе. Советую больше так не делать. Ладно, не спи - замёрзнешь. До встречи.</rus>
		<eng>You are lucky. I advise you not to do so again. Ok, do not sleep, you'll freeze. See you.</eng>
		<ukr>Пощастило тобі. Раджу більше так не робити. Гаразд, не спи - замерзнеш. До зустрічі.</ukr>
		<fra>Heureusement pour toi. Je vous conseille de ne pas recommencer. Ok, ne dors pas - congèle. A bientôt.</fra>
		<pln>Miałeś szczęście. Radzę więcej tak nie robić. Dobra, nie śpij - bo zamarzniesz. Do zobaczenia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_7_dialog_82">
		<rus>Ну ладно, зайду как-нибудь.</rus>
		<eng>Ok, I'll come one day.</eng>
		<ukr>Ну гаразд, зайду як-небудь.</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, je reviendrai un jour.</fra>
		<pln>No dobra, wpadnę kiedyś.</pln>
	</string>
</string_table>
