<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="about_enciclopedia">
		<rus>Этот раздел - энциклопедия. В процессе игры информация об окружающем мире будет заноситься сюда и сортироваться по темам.</rus>
		<eng>This is the encyclopaedia. As you progress in the game, information about the world around you will be added here, sorted by topic.</eng>
		<ukr>Цей розділ - енциклопедія. У процесі гри інформація про навколишній світ заноситиметься сюди і сортуватиметься за темами.</ukr>
		<fra>Voici l'Encyclopédie. Au fil de votre progression, vous y trouverez de précieuses informations, classées par rubrique.</fra>
		<pln>To jest encyklopedia. W miarę postępów w grze będą tu dodawane posegregowane tematycznie informacje o otaczającym cię świecie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="about_pda">
		<rus>Об энциклопедии</rus>
		<eng>About the encyclopaedia</eng>
		<ukr>Про енциклопедії</ukr>
		<fra>À propos de l'Encyclopédie</fra>
		<pln>O encyklopedii</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="Bandit's flash">
		<rus>КПК бандита с фабрики</rus>
		<eng>Factory bandit's PDA</eng>
		<ukr>КПК бандита із фабрики</ukr>
		<fra>PDA du bandit</fra>
		<pln>PDA bandyty z fabryki</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="blokpost_case_text">
		<rus>Торговец: проникнуть на блокпост и оттуда украсть кейс с отчётом военной экспедиции с севера Зоны.\n \n \n \n \n</rus>
		<eng>Trader: get inside the army outpost and steal the case containing the report of the military expedition to the northern part of the Zone.\n \n \n \n \n</eng>
		<ukr>Крамар: «Проникнути на блокпост і вкрасти звідти кейс зі звітом військової експедиції з півночі Зони».\n \n \n \n \n</ukr>
		<fra>===Marchand : rejoins l'avant-poste militaire et vole la mallette contenant le rapport relatif à l'expédition menée dans la partie nord de la Zone.\n \n \n \n \n</fra>
		<pln>===Handlarz: dostań się na posterunek wojskowy i ukradnij walizkę zawierającą raport z ekspedycji wojskowej, przeprowadzonej w północnej części Zony.\n \n \n \n \n</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dead_novice_flash">
		<rus>КПК мёртвого новичка</rus>
		<eng>Dead rookie's PDA</eng>
		<ukr>КПК мертвого новачка</ukr>
		<fra>PDA du Stalker mort</fra>
		<pln>PDA martwego nowicjusza</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="defend_lager_text">
		<rus>Фанат: помочь отбиться от наёмников, которые пришли и потребовали новичков освободить лагерь. Все ныкаются, чтобы на глаза не попадаться, пропускают наёмников в лагерь, а потом по команде атакуем.</rus>
		<eng>Devotee: Help us defend against the Mercs who ordered the rookies to clear off the camp. The plan goes like this: everyone hides, so that the camp looks deserted. We let the Mercs inside the camp, and then we attack when the captain orders to do so.</eng>
		<ukr>Фанат: «Допоможи відбитися від найманців, які прийшли й зажадали від новачків, щоб ті полишили табір. Усі никаємося, щоб на очі не трапляти, пропускаємо найманців до табору, а потім за командою атакуємо.»</ukr>
		<fra>Accro: Aide-nous à nous défendre des Mercenaires qui ont ordonné aux nouveaux de quitter le camp. Voilà le plan. Tout le monde se cache pour faire croire aux Mercenaires que le camp est désert. Et là, lorsque le capitaine en donne l'ordre, on attaque.</fra>
		<pln>Fanat: Pomóż nam obronić się przed najemnikami, którzy kazali nowicjuszom wynieść się z obozu. Plan jest taki: wszyscy się chowają, żeby obóz wyglądał na opuszczony, wpuszczamy najemników do obozu, a potem atakujemy na mój rozkaz.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="doctor_meet">
		<rus>КПК Проводника</rus>
		<eng>Guide's PDA</eng>
		<ukr>КПК Провідника</ukr>
		<fra>PDA de Guide</fra>
		<pln>PDA Przewodnika</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="doctor_meet_2">
		<rus>Встреча с Доктором</rus>
		<eng>Meeting Doctor</eng>
		<ukr>Зустріч із доктором</ukr>
		<fra>Rencontre avec le Docteur</fra>
		<pln>Spotkanie z Doktorem</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="doctor_meet_quest_text">
		<rus>Доктор: "Я буду ждать человека от Стрелка в тайнике его группировки. Если это свой - он знает место".</rus>
		<eng>Doctor: "I will be waiting for a man who comes from Strelok to the hiding place used by Strelok and his men. If he's our man, he'll know the place."</eng>
		<ukr>Доктор: «Я чекатиму на людину від Стрільця у схованці угруповання Стрільця. Якщо це свій - він знає місце.»</ukr>
		<fra>Le Docteur: J'attends un type pour rejoindre la planque utilisée par Strelok et ses hommes. C'est notre homme, il connaîtra les lieux.</fra>
		<pln>Doktor: "Będę czekał na człowieka od Striełoka w kryjówce używanej przez niego i jego ludzi. Jeśli to jeden z naszych, zna to miejsce".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="doctor_meet_text">
		<rus>Хорошо, я встречусь с человеком Призрака. Буду ждать его в тайнике Стрелка. Если это кто-то из своих, значит знает, где меня искать. Доктор.</rus>
		<eng>OK, I'll meet with Ghost's man. I will be waiting for him in Strelok's hiding place. If he's one of our own, he will know where to look for me. Doctor.</eng>
		<ukr>«Добре, я зустрінуся із людиною Привида. Чекатиму на нього у схованці Стрільця. Якщо це хтось зі своїх, то знає, де мене шукати. Доктор.»</ukr>
		<fra>OK, je vais retrouver l'homme de Spectre. Je l'attendrai dans la planque de Strelok. S'il est un des nôtres, il saura où me trouver. Le Docteur.</fra>
		<pln>OK, spotkam się z człowiekiem Ducha. Będę na niego czekał w kryjówce Striełoka. Jeśli to jeden z naszych, to wie, gdzie mnie szukać. Doktor.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_flash_task_descr">
		<rus>Торговец: "... мои ребята возвращались с задания и пропали. Один из них - звать Шустрый - нёс мне кой-какую инфу... И пропали совсем рядом, под боком, потому что мост прошли. Не знаю, что и думать. Решили кому другому инфу скинуть или сидят водку глушат? Короче: найди Шустрого, живого или мёртвого - главное, чтобы флешка при нём была. Принесёшь мне. Шустрый был из людей Волка, а он тут, в лагере. Спроси его: наверняка что-то знает. C оружием и боеприпасами он тебе поможет."</rus>
		<eng>Trader: "...my guys were coming back from an assignment and disappeared. One of them - called Nimble - was bringing me some info... And they all disappeared really close by because they missed the bridge. Don't know what to think. Anyway: find Nimble, dead or alive, just as long as he has the flash drive. Bring it to me. Nimble was one of Wolf's men - and Wolf is here in the camp. Ask him, he probably knows something. He'll help you with weapons and gear."</eng>
		<ukr>Крамар: «... мої хлопці поверталися із завдання і пропали. Один з них - звати Спритним - ніс мені певну інформацію... І пропали десь зовсім поруч, бо міст вони точно пройшли. Не знаю, що й думати. Коротше: знайди Спритного, живого чи мертвого - головне, щоб флешка при ньому була. Принесеш мені. Спритний був одним із людей Вовка - а Вовк тут, у таборі. Запитай, може він щось знає. Зі зброєю та боєприпасами він тобі допоможе.»</ukr>
		<fra>Marchand: "... mes gars revenaient de mission et se sont volatilisés. L'un d'entre eux, un certain Agile, m'apportait quelques nouvelles... Et ils se sont tous volatilisés car ils ont loupé le pont. Je sais pas quoi en penser. Quoi qu'il en soit, retrouve Agile, mort ou vif, du moment qu'il ait la clé USB. Apporte-la-moi. Agile faisait partie des hommes du Loup et le Loup est ici, au camp. Interroge-le, il sait sûrement quelque chose. Il te fournira des armes et du matériel."</fra>
		<pln>Handlarz: "...Moi chłopcy wracali z akcji i nagle ich wcięło. Jeden z nich, Żwawy, miał dla mnie informacje... Zniknęli gdzieś tu blisko, pod bokiem, bo most już minęli. Nie wiem co o tym myśleć. Postanowili komuś innemu spuścić informację, czy siedzą gdzieś i chleją?... W każdym razie znajdź Żwawego, żywego lub martwego - ważne, żeby miał fleszkę. Przynieś mi ją. Żwawy był jednym z ludzi Wilka, a ten jest tu, w obozie. Spytaj go. Pewnie coś wie."</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_info">
		<rus>Серый - Лису:\nОдин знакомый попросил встретить группу сталкеров, раскопавших тайник Стрелка, я буду cо своими людьми на Свалке в ангаре, если что - подходи.</rus>
		<eng>Grey to Fox:\nA friend wants me to give a helping hand to a bunch of stalkers that dug out Strelok's stash. I'm off to the hangar at the Garbage with my boys. That's where you can find me.</eng>
		<ukr>Сірий - Лисові:\n«Один знайомий попрохав зустріти групу сталкерів, які розкопали схованку Стрільця. Я буду зі своїми людьми на Звалищі в ангарі, то як щось станеться - підходь.»</ukr>
		<fra>Gris à Renard:\nUn ami veut m'aider à m'occuper des stalkers qui ont découvert la planque de Strelok. Avec mes gars, on se dirige vers le hangar de la décharge. C'est là que tu me trouveras.</fra>
		<pln>Sieryj do Lisa:\nJeden znajomy prosi, żeby pomóc grupie stalkerów, którzy znaleźli kryjówkę Striełoka. Będę ze swoimi chłopakami w hangarze na Wysypisku. Tam możesz mnie znaleźć.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kolyan_lost">
		<rus>Один братан вчера ушёл на разведку на заброшенную мельницу, и о нём до сих пор ничего не слышно. Надо бы сходить узнать, куда он подевался.</rus>
		<eng>Yesterday one brother went to scout the deserted mill and we haven't heard from him since. We need to go there and see where he disappeared to.</eng>
		<ukr>Один братан учора пішов на розвідку на старий млин і про нього дотепер нічого не чутно. Треба сходити довідатися, куди він подівся.</ukr>
		<fra>Hier, un de mes frères est allé reconnaître le moulin déserté, mais depuis, plus de nouvelles. Il faut qu'on y aille pour en savoir plus.</fra>
		<pln>Wczoraj jeden z naszych braciaków wyruszył na zwiad do opuszczonej fabryki i od tego czasu nie mieliśmy od niego żadnych wieści. Musimy się tam udać i sprawdzić, gdzie się podział.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="factory_dynamit_text">
		<rus>Волк: принести динамит, спёртый бандитами на фабрике. В помощь - под мостом разведчики; подойти, сказать: "Привет из преисподней" (пароль). Повести их в атаку.</rus>
		<eng>Wolf: bring the dynamite stolen by the bandits at the factory. To help you, there are scouts under the bridge, come to them and say "Hello from the underworld" - that's the password. Lead them into battle.</eng>
		<ukr>Вовк: «Принести динаміт, що його вкрали бандити з фабрики. На допомогу тобі - мої розвідники під мостом. Підійдеш, скажеш «Привіт із пекла» - то пароль. Поведеш їх в атаку.»</ukr>
		<fra>Loup: apporte la dynamite volee par les bandits a l'usine. Pour t'aider, il y a des eclaireurs sous le pont, va les voir et dit : "Bonjour de l'enfer", c'est le mot de passe. Mene-les au combat.</fra>
		<pln>Wilk: przynieś dynamit skradziony przez bandytów z fabryki. Pod mostem ukryci są zwiadowcy, którzy ci pomogą. Podejdź do nich i powiedz: "Pozdrowienia z krainy cieni" - takie jest hasło. Poprowadź ich do ataku.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="factory_trader_text">
		<rus>Волк: уничтожить бандитов на фабрике с помощью моих разведчиков за мостом, потом прийти и отчитаться.</rus>
		<eng>Wolf: clear the bandits at the factory with the help of my scouts behind the bridge, then return and report.</eng>
		<ukr>Вовк: «Зачистити бандитів на фабриці за допомогою моїх розвідників за мостом. Потім прийти і відзвітувати.»</ukr>
		<fra>Loup: élimine les bandits de l'usine avec l'aide des éclaireurs situés sous le ont, puis reviens et fais un rapport.</fra>
		<pln>Wilk: pozbądź się bandytów z fabryki z pomocą moich zwiadowców, którzy czekają za mostem, a następnie wróć i zdaj mi raport.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="Flash dead stalker">
		<rus>КПК мёртвого сталкера</rus>
		<eng>Dead stalker's PDA</eng>
		<ukr>КПК мертвого сталкера</ukr>
		<fra>PDA du Stalker mort</fra>
		<pln>PDA martwego stalkera</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="gunslinger_clan_cache">
		<rus>... очнулся возле разбитого грузовика с горой трупов, ничего не помню. При себе только КПК и фотография какого-то мужика. В КПК одна запись - убить Стрелка.</rus>
		<eng>...came to in the den of some dude, can't remember anything. Just have a PDA on me with a picture of some other dude. There's just one message in the PDA - kill Strelok.</eng>
		<ukr>«...прийшов до тями біля розбитої вантажівки з горою трупів… нічого не пам'ятаю. При собі лише КПК та фотографія якогось дядька. У КПК лише один запис: «Убити Стрільця».»</ukr>
		<fra>... Je me suis réveillé près d'un camion accidenté et d'un tas de cadavres... a surgi dans le repaire, je me souviens plus de rien. J'avais juste un PDA sur moi avec la photo d'un autre type. Il n'y a qu'un message dans le PDA - tuer Strelok.</fra>
		<pln>... Ocknąłem się przy rozbitej ciężarówce z górą trupów, nic nie pamiętam. Mam tylko przy sobie PDA ze zdjęciem jakiegoś gościa. W PDA jedyna wiadomość - zabij Striełoka.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="help_to_fox">
		<rus>Торговец: вернулся из рейда Лис, просит о помощи. Возможно, знает о Стрелке.\n \n \n \n \n</rus>
		<eng>Trader: Fox has come back from his raid and is asking for help. Perhaps he knows something about Strelok.\n \n \n \n \n</eng>
		<ukr>Крамар: «Повернувся з рейду Лис, прохає про допомогу. Можливо, цей щось знає про Стрільця.»\n \n \n \n \n</ukr>
		<fra>Marchand: Renard est revenu de son raid pour demander de l'aide. Il sait peut-être quelque chose à propos de Strelok.</fra>
		<pln>Handlarz: Lis wrócił z wypadu i prosi o pomoc. Może wie coś o Striełoku.\n \n \n \n \n</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_seryi_text">
		<rus>Лис: Серый сидит в ангаре на Свалке, он знает о Стрелке больше.</rus>
		<eng>Fox: Grey is sitting in the hangar at the Garbage, he knows more about Strelok.</eng>
		<ukr>Лис: «Сірий сидить в ангарі на Звалищі, він знає про Стрільця більше»</ukr>
		<fra>Renard: Gris se trouve dans le hangar de la Décharge, il en sait plus sur Strelok.</fra>
		<pln>Lis: Sieryj siedzi w hangarze na Wysypisku - on wie więcej o Striełoku.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="military_case_text">
		<rus>Торговец: на НИИ Агропром у военных выкрасть результаты экспедиции и отнести в бар "100 рентген" Бармену.</rus>
		<eng>Trader: steal the expedition report from the military at the Agroprom Research Institute, take it to the 100 Rads bar and give it to Barkeep.</eng>
		<ukr>Крамар: «На Агропромі у військових викрасти результати експедиції й віднести до бара «100 Рентген». Віддати Барменові.»</ukr>
		<fra>Marchand : vole le rapport de l'expédition à l'institut de recherche "Agroprom", rapporte-le au 100 Rads et remets-le au Barman.</fra>
		<pln>Handlarz: ukradnij żołnierzom z Instytutu Badawczego Agroprom raport z ekspedycji, zabierz go do baru "100 Rentgenów" i przekaż Barmanowi.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="Seryi flash">
		<rus>КПК Лиса</rus>
		<eng>Fox's PDA</eng>
		<ukr>КПК Лиса</ukr>
		<fra>PDA de Renard</fra>
		<pln>PDA Lisa</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_fox_flash_info">
		<rus>Торговец послал следить за военными на НИИ Агропром. Туда припёрлись, всех постреляли, бандитов и военных. Нарыли что-то интересное, остальное передаю шифром *абракадабра, типа, шифр*</rus>
		<eng>Trader sent us to spy on the military at the Agroprom Research Institute. Got there and shot everybody, bandits and military alike. Dug out some interesting stuff, I'm encoding the rest *gibberish text that looks like a cipher*</eng>
		<ukr>Щоденник Толіка: «Крамар послав стежити за військовими на НДІ «Агропром». Туди приперлися, усіх постріляли, бандитів і військових. Нарили щось цікаве, інше передаю шифром *абракадабра, типу шифр*.»</ukr>
		<fra>===Journal de Tolik. Le marchand nous a envoyés espionner les militaires de l'institut de recherche "Agroprom". On y est allé et on a tué tout le monde, bandits et militaires confondus. J'ai déniché des trucs intéressants, je vais m'occuper du reste du *charabia qui ressemble à un code*.</fra>
		<pln>Handlarz wysłał nas, żebyśmy szpiegowali żołnierzy w Instytucie Badawczym Agroprom. Zaszliśmy tam i wystrzelaliśmy wszystkich, i bandytów, i żołnierzy. Wyszperaliśmy parę ciekawych rzeczy, koduję resztę "bezsensowny tekst, który wygląda na szyfr"</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_seryi_info">
		<rus>Серый - Лису:\nОдин знакомый попросил встретить группу сталкеров, раскопавших тайник Стрелка, я буду на Свалке, если что - подходи.</rus>
		<eng>Grey to Fox:\nOne guy I know asked to meet a group of stalkers who sniffed out Strelok's hiding place. I'll be at the Garbage, come over if you want.</eng>
		<ukr>Сірий - Лисові:\n«Один знайомий попрохав зустріти групу сталкерів, які розкопали схованку Стрільця. Я буду на Звалищі, як щось треба - підходь.»</ukr>
		<fra>Gris à Renard:\nUn type que je connais voudrait qu'on retrouve le groupe de stalkers qui a déniché la planque de Strelok. Je serai à la Décharge. Rejoins-moi si tu veux.</fra>
		<pln>Sieryj do Lisa:\nJeden znajomy poprosił o spotkanie z grupą stalkerów, którzy wytropili kryjówkę Striełoka. Będę na Wysypisku. Jak chcesz, to przyjdź.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="Tolik flash">
		<rus>КПК Толика</rus>
		<eng>Tolik's PDA</eng>
		<ukr>КПК Толіка</ukr>
		<fra>PDA de Tolik</fra>
		<pln>PDA Tolika</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_artefact_find">
		<rus>Торговец: тут рядом поле аномалий "Мясорубка". Артефакт в её центре. Достать.</rus>
		<eng>Trader: there is a Whirligig anomaly field close by. There is an artifact in its center. Get it.</eng>
		<ukr>Крамар: «Тут поруч поле аномалій «М'ясорубка». Артефакт знаходиться у центрі аномалії. Треба дістати.»</ukr>
		<fra>Marchand : Il y a un champ d'anomalies "hachoir" dans le coin, avec un artefact en son centre. Récupère-le.</fra>
		<pln>Handlarz: w pobliżu znajduje się pole anomalii. W jego centrum jest artefakt. Zdobądź go.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_moving_anomaly_text">
		<rus>Тут какая-то очень странная аномалия. Похоже, что она передвигается. Я попытаюсь вычислить её траекторию и время перемещения, потому что платить солдатам на мосту за проход у меня нет денег.</rus>
		<eng>There's a very strange anomaly here. It looks like it's moving. I'll try to calculate its movement times and path, because I don't have the cash to pay the soldiers for passage.</eng>
		<ukr>Тут якась дуже дивна аномалія. Схоже, що вона пересувається. Я спробую обчислити її траєкторію та час переміщення, бо платити солдатам на мосту за прохід у мене грошей не стане.</ukr>
		<fra>Il y a ici une anomalie très étrange. Elle a l'air de se déplacer. J'essaie de calculer sa fréquence et sa trajectoire, parce que je n'ai pas les moyens de payer les soldats pour passer.</fra>
		<pln>Występuje tu bardzo dziwna anomalia. Wygląda, jakby się przemieszczała. Postaram się obliczyć czas i trajektorię przemieszczania, bo nie jestem w stanie opłacić się żołnierzom za przejście.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_secret_place">
		<rus>Я оставил на заброшенной ферме небольшой тайник. Там немного еды, патроны. Нести уже не могу, силы на исходе. Не уверен, смогу ли я добраться до лагеря.</rus>
		<eng>I left a small cache at the deserted farm. It's got some food and ammo. I'm way too weak to carry it now. I'm not sure if I can make it to the camp.</eng>
		<ukr>Я залишив на покинутій фермі невеличку схованку. Там трохи їжі, патрони. Нести вже не можу, сил нема. Не впевнений, чи зможу я дістатися табору.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai caché un peu de nourriture et des munitions dans une petite planque, à la ferme désertée. Je suis trop faible pour les transporter. Je suis pas sûr de pouvoir rejoindre le camp.</fra>
		<pln>Na opuszczonym gospodarstwie zostawiłem niewielką kryjówkę. Znajdziesz tam trochę jedzenia i amunicji. Jestem teraz zbyt słaby, żeby to nosić. Nie wiem, czy uda mi się dotrzeć do obozu.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_actor_main_quest_descr">
		<rus>По словам генерала Воронина, эта пушка есть только у группировки Свобода, как я её достану - дело моё. Но как я понял, один из способов - это втереться в доверие к сталкеру Свободы - Повару. Со слов генерала, большому любителю выпить. Так что надо на всякий случай затариться водкой, может пригодится.</rus>
		<eng>According to general Voronin, only Freedom has one of these guns. How I get it is my own business. I was told that one way would be to hang out with the Freedom stalker called Chef. The General says he likes his drink more than he should. I should stock up on vodka just in case I can use it.</eng>
		<ukr>За словами генерала Вороніна, така пушка є лише в угруповання «Воля»… і як я її дістану - то моя справа. Але, як я зрозумів, є спосіб - підлабузнитися до Кухаря, одного зі сталкерів «Волі». Як сказав генерал, той дуже полюбляє залити очі. Тож треба, про всяк випадок, мати запас горілки - може стати у пригоді.</ukr>
		<fra>D'après le général Voronine, seule la Liberté possède ce genre d'armes. Comment je me la suis procurée, ça me regarde. On m'a dit qu'il fallait que je fréquente un Stalker de la Liberté, un certain Cuistot. D'après le général, il a tendance à boire. Je vais prévoir de la vodka au cas où.</fra>
		<pln>Według generała Woronina, tylko "Wolność" ma jedną z tych broni. Jak ją zdobyć, to moja sprawa. Dowiedziałem się, że jedna z możliwości - to zdobyć zaufanie stalkera z "Wolności", Kucharza. Generał mówi, że gość wyjątkowo lubi sobie wypić. Chyba powinienem zrobić zapas wódki na wszelki wypadek.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_blockpost_job_descr">
		<rus>Необходимо помочь защитить барьер от атаки со стороны Выжигателя мозгов.</rus>
		<eng>It's imperative to protect the barrier from attack from the direction of the Brain Scorcher.</eng>
		<ukr>Необхідно допомогти захистити Бар'єр від атаки з боку Випалювача Мізків</ukr>
		<fra>Il faut à tout prix protéger la Barrière des attaques émanant du lobotomisateur.</fra>
		<pln>Koniecznie trzeba pomóc ochronić Barierę przed atakami od strony Mózgozwęglacza.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_blockpost_job2_descr">
		<rus>Лукаш: "Если чувствуешь в себе силы, то можешь пойти на заставу у выхода на Радар. По некоторым признакам там ожидается очередная попытка прорыва мутантов или Монолита. Надо помочь ребятам".</rus>
		<eng>Lukash: "If you have it in you, you can go to the security checkpoint by the exit to Radar - based on some indications they're expecting another attempt at a break in from the mutants or Monolith. Someone has to help them."</eng>
		<ukr>Лукаш: «Якщо є така спроможність, то можеш піти на заставу біля виходу на Радар - за деякими ознаками, там очікується чергова спроба прориву мутантів або «Моноліту». Треба допомогти хлопцям.»</ukr>
		<fra>Loukache: "Essaie de rejoindre le poste de contrôle de la sécurité par la sortie de la Forêt rouge. Visiblement, ils s'attendent à voir arriver des mutants ou le Monolithe</fra>
		<pln>Łukasz: "Jeśli czujesz się na siłach, weź udział w zasadzce przy wyjściu na Radar. Są pewne oznaki, że należy spodziewać się tam kolejnej próby przedarcia się mutantów lub "Monolitu". Trzeba pomóc chłopakom".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_courier_doc_descr">
		<rus>У Свободы появились гранатомёты типа РГ-6. Две штуки. Один в арсенале, второй где-то в деревне.\n\n</rus>
		<eng>Freedom has acquired a few RG-6 grenade launchers. Two of them. One is in the arsenal, the other somewhere in the village.\n\n</eng>
		<ukr>У «Волі» з'явилися гранатомети типу «Бульдог-6». Дві штуки. Одна в арсеналі, друга десь у селі.\n\n</ukr>
		<fra>La Liberté s'est procurée des lance-grenades Bulldog 6. Deux. Il y en a un dans l'arsenal et l'autre, quelque part dans le village.\n\n</fra>
		<pln>"Wolność" zdobyła dwa granatniki RG-6. Jeden znajduje się w arsenale, a drugi gdzieś w wiosce.\n\n</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_courier_job_descr">
		<rus>Лукаш: "Прискорбно признавать, однако у нас завёлся стукач... Павликом зовут. Информацию передаёт на сторону, и это дело надо прекращать. Твоя задача - пойти за ним на хутор и узнать, кому он передаёт информацию. Он недавно ушёл, так что придётся догонять. Запомни: шлёпнуть его можно и нужно, но не раньше, чем он засветит того, кому сливает информацию. Второго тоже придётся убрать".</rus>
		<eng>Lukash: "Sad but true - we have a snitch among us...His name is Pavlik. He's sending information to the other side, and we need to stop it. Your job is to follow him to the farmstead and find out who he's reporting the information to. He left a while ago, so you'll have to catch up. Remember this: You can and need to finish him off, but not before he reveals the one he's giving the information to. You'll have to eliminate the second dude too."</eng>
		<ukr>Лукаш: «Сумно визнавати, однак у нас завівся стукач. Павлусем кличуть. Інформацію зливає кудись, але це діло треба припиняти. Твоє завдання - піти за ним на хутір і довідатися, кому він передає інформацію. Він уже пішов, тож доведеться доганяти. Запам'ятай: шльопнути його можна і треба, але не раніше, ніж він засвітить того, на кого працює. Того другого теж треба прибрати.»</ukr>
		<fra>Loukache: "C'est terrible, il y a une Balance parmi nous... Il s'appelle Pavlik. Il envoie des informations à l'ennemi et ça ne peut pas continuer. Tu vas devoir le suivre jusqu'à la ferme pour savoir à qui il donne ces informations. Il est parti il n'y a pas longtemps et tu devrais pouvoir le rattraper. Attention, tu peux et tu dois l'éliminer, mais pas avant de savoir à qui il donne ces informations. Et lui aussi, tu devras l'éliminer."</fra>
		<pln>Łukasz: "Smutne, ale prawdziwe - mamy wśród nas donosiciela... Nazywa się Pawlik. Przekazuje informacje drugiej stronie i trzeba z tym skończyć. Idź za nim do gospodarstwa i dowiedz się, z kim się kontaktuje. Wyruszył przed chwilą, więc musisz go dogonić. Pamiętaj: wykończyć go można, a nawet trzeba, ale nie przedtem, zanim nie dowiesz się komu przekazuje informacje. Tego drugiego też trzeba będzie zlikwidować".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_flash_info">
		<rus>... сегодня мы отправились в деревню на очередную охоту на арты. Всё как всегда. \n\n... откуда взялась эта тварь? Не иначе, как с Радара пролезла. Все полегли, я один... Попробую уйти ночью...\n\n... Я не помню, как я выбрался - это был настоящий ад... Моя голова раскалывается - образы, звуки, я не знаю откуда они берутся, чёртова радиация. И датчик, сука, сломался. Я должен отдохнуть, и мне станет легче.</rus>
		<eng>... today we went to the village again on a hunt. Everything same as always. \n\n Where did that beast come from? Must have sneaked through near Radar. All the guys are down, I'm the only one standing... I'll try to sneak out at night... \n\n I don't remember how I got out. It was pure hell... My head is splitting open - pictures, sounds, I don't know where they are coming from. Goddamn radiation. On top of that, the bloody detector is kaput. I must rest and I'll feel better.</eng>
		<ukr>«...сьогодні ми відправилися до селища задля чергового полювання на артефакти. Усе як завжди.» \n\n «...звідки взялася ця тварюка?! Мабуть, з боку Радара пролізла. Усі вже лежать, я один... Спробую відповзти у темряві...»\n\n «...Не пам'ятаю, як вибрався - це було правдиве пекло... Голова розколюється: видіння, звуки… я не знаю, відки вони беруться… чортова радіація! І датчик, курва, зламався... Я маю перепочити… мені полегшає...»</ukr>
		<fra>... Aujourd'hui, on est encore allés au village. C'est toujours la même chose.\n\n D'où venait cette bête ? Elle a dû se faufiler à travers la Forêt rouge. Les gars sont morts et je suis le seul à tenir encore debout... Je vais tâcher d'y aller cette nuit...\n\n Je sais pas comment je m'en suis sorti. C'était l'enfer... Des tas d'images défilent et des tas de bruits résonnent dans ma tête et je ne sais pas d'où ils viennent. Fichues radiations. Et pour couronner le tout, le détecteur marche plus. Un peu de repos et ça ira mieux.</fra>
		<pln>... Dzisiaj znowu poszliśmy do wioski polować na artefakty. Wszystko jak zawsze. \n\n... Skąd się wzięła ta bestia? Musiała przyleźć z Radaru. Wszyscy polegli, zostałem tylko ja... Postaram się stąd wykraść w nocy... \n\n Nie pamiętam, jak się wydostałem - to było prawdziwe piekło... Głowa mi pęka - obrazy, dźwięki, nie wiem skąd pochodzą, cholerne promieniowanie. A na dodatek ten pieprzony detektor się zepsuł. Muszę odpocząć, to poczuję się lepiej.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_dolg_kill_lukash_descr">
		<rus>Зайти с долговцами на базу\nУничтожить трёх снайперов\nУбить Лукаша</rus>
		<eng>Enter the base with Duty members.\nEliminate three snipers. \nKill Lukash.</eng>
		<ukr>Зайти із «долгівцями» на базу.\nЗнищити трьох снайперів. \nУбити Лукаша.</ukr>
		<fra>Pénètre sur la base avec les membres du Devoir.\n Élimine trois snipers. \nTue Loukache.</fra>
		<pln>Wejdź do bazy z bojownikami "Powinności".\nWyeliminuj trzech snajperów. \nZabij Łukasza</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_dolg_kill_sniper_descr">
		<rus>Убить снайпера на вышке. Нужно действовать аккуратно, чтобы не схлопотать пулю в жбан.</rus>
		<eng>Kill the sniper at the tower. Be careful, don't catch a bullet between the eyes.</eng>
		<ukr>Убити снайпера на вишці. Слід діяти акуратно, щоб не отримати кулю в макітру.</ukr>
		<fra>Tue le sniper de la tour. Mais attention, ne te fais pas descendre.</fra>
		<pln>Zabij snajpera na wieży. Musisz uważać, żeby nie zarobić kulki w głowę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_bandit_descr">
		<rus>Блин, козлы из Долга нас согнали с рыбного места. Окопались на нашем хуторе. Мы даже свои вещички с чердака забрать не успели. Ничего, база Свободы рядом, так что их быстро оттуда выкурят.</rus>
		<eng>Crap, those Duty assholes kicked us out from a fat place. They dug in near our farmstead. We didn't even have time to get our things from the attic. No big deal though - Freedom base is near, so they won't hang on too long.</eng>
		<ukr>Курва, ці козли з «Долгу» нас зігнали з рибного місця! Засіли на наш хуторі. Ми навіть свої лахи з горища забрати не встигли. Нічого, база «Волі» поруч, тож їх швидко звідтіля випруть.</ukr>
		<fra>Bon sang, ces enfoirés du Devoir nous ont chassés de ce fichu endroit. Ils s'étaient retranchés près de notre ferme. On a même pas eu le temps de récupérer les trucs qu'on avait au grenier. Enfin, c'est pas grave... La base de la Liberté est pas loin, et ils vont pas rester bien longtemps.</fra>
		<pln>Ale syf! Te dupki z "Powinności" wysiudały nas ze świetnego miejsca. Okopali się w naszym gospodarstwie. Nie mieliśmy nawet czasu zabrać rzeczy ze strychu. Ale to nic -  jest baza "Wolności" niedaleko, nie zostaną tu długo.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_max_descr">
		<rus>Сегодня пошерстили военных, которые шли на Радар, поимели пару РГ-6. Классная штука. Одну взял Лукаш, а вторую Угрюмый спрятал в деревне, в подвале дома.</rus>
		<eng>Today we shook down a few soldiers on their way to Radar - scored some RG-6's. They are awesome. Lukash took one, and Morose hid the other in the village, in one of the basements.</eng>
		<ukr>Сьогодні причесали військових, котрі йшли на Радар, тепер маємо пару «Бульдогів-6». Ех, класні штуки! Одну взяв Лукаш, а другу Похмурий сховав у селі, у підвалі будинку.</ukr>
		<fra>Aujourd'hui, on a descendu quelques soldats qui se dirigeaient vers la Forêt rouge équipés de Bulldog 6. Ils sont redoutables. Loukache en a pris un et le Magouilleur en a caché un autre dans un des souterrains du village.</fra>
		<pln>Dzisiaj przetrzepaliśmy kilku żołnierzy, którzy szli na Radar - zgarnęliśmy dwa RG-6. Świetna rzecz! Łukasz wziął jeden z nich, a Mruk ukrył drugi w wiosce, w jednej z piwnic.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_ugrumy_descr">
		<rus>1. Чёрт меня дёрнул пойти на Радар, еле проскочил - ещё немного, и был бы ещё один экспонат с разжиженными мозгами.\n\n2. Четверо бандитов окружили меня как маленького, и я хорош - прохлопал засаду. Меня спасла их болтливость и жадность, вместо того чтоб меня изрешетить, они выскочили и захотели меня предварительно раздеть - позарились на костюм. Это была их последняя ошибка, но один всё-таки меня задел. Эх, старею...\n\n3. Посланник Стрелка к моему приходу уже не дышал. Да, с тремя кровососами не каждый справится, а этот уложил четверых, и ещё несколько кровавых следов уходят в разные стороны. Единственная информация, бывшая при нём, это код двери (19840519), но от какой, пока не представляется возможность узнать.\n\n4. Перехватили вояк, которые шли на Радар. Документов и приказов у них не было, но по крайней мере, затарились боеприпасами. Положу пока свой РГ-6 в подвальчике, потом заберу.</rus>
		<eng>1. The Devil made me go to Radar. I barely made it - a little slower and I would have made for just another exhibit with liquified brains.\n\n 2: Four thugs surrounded me like I was a three-year old. I did my part - didn't see their trap. I was only saved by their chattiness and greed. Instead of stuffing me full of lead, they jumped out and began disrobing me - got hooked on the suit. That was their last mistake; still, one of them caught me with a bullet... heh, I'm getting old...\n\n 3: By the time I arrived, Strelok's messenger was no longer breathing. Three bloodsuckers are a match for anyone, but this guy took out four of them, and a few more bloody trails lead out in different directions. The only information on him is a door code (19840519), but identifying the door it unlocks doesn't seem possible.\n\n 4: We intercepted a few army men on their way to Radar. They carried no documents or orders, but were very adequately equipped. I think I'll leave that RG-6 in the basement until I need it.</eng>
		<ukr>1: Чорти мене підбили піти на Радар! Ледь проскочив - ще трохи, і був би новий експонат із розім'яклими мізками.\n\n 2: Четверо бандитів оточили мене як маленького… та то, ясна річ, сам винен - пропустив засідку. Мене врятували їхня балакучість та жадібність: замість того, щоб наробити в мені дірок, вони вискочили, бо хтіли мене попередньо роздягнути - обладунок мій їм сподобався... То була їхня остання помилка, але один усе-таки мене зачепив. Ет, старий я, мабуть, став...\n\n 3: Посланник Стрільця до мого приходу вже не дихав. Так, із трьома кровососами не кожен упорається, а цей поклав чотирьох і ще кілька кривавих слідів пішли у різні боки. Єдина інформація при ньому - код до дверей 19840519, але від яких, поки немає можливості довідатися.\n\n 4: Перехопили вояків, які йшли на Радар. Документів та наказів у них не було, але ми хоч хапонули боєприпасів. Покладу поки свого «Бульдога-6» у льосі, потім заберу.</ukr>
		<fra>1. Le diable m'a entraîné dans la Forêt rouge. J'y suis à peine arrivé... J'étais à deux doigts de me liquéfier.\n\n 2. Quatre voyous m'ont encerclé comme si j'étais un gamin de trois ans. J'ai pas vu leur piège. Si j'ai réussi à m'en sortir, c'est grâce à leur bêtise. Au lieu de m'étouffer, ils m'ont sauté dessus pour me déshabiller et je me suis accrochée à ma combi. Mais un deux m'a dégommé avec une balle... Ah, je me fais vieux...\n\n 3. Quand je suis arrivé, le messager de Strelok ne respirait plus. Ces sangsues sont redoutables, mais ce type en avait eu quatre, et des traces de sang menaient vers différentes directions. La seule information qu'il avait sur lui, c'est un code de porte (19840519), mais trouver cette porte semble impossible.\n\n 4. On a intercepté plusieurs militaires qui se dirigeaient vers la Forêt rouge. Ils n'avaient ni documents ni ordres, mais étaient drôlement bien équipés. Je crois que je vais laisser ce Bulldog 6 dans le souterrain tant que j'en ai pas besoin.</fra>
		<pln>1. Chyba diabeł mnie podkusił, żebym się wybrał na Radar. Ledwo mi się udało - odrobinę wolniej, i teraz pewnie byłbym kolejnym eksponatem ze spalonym mózgiem.\n\n 2. Czterech bandytów otoczyło mnie jak dziecko, a ja też dobry - nie zauważyłem ich zasadzki. Uratowała mnie jedynie ich gadatliwość i chciwość. Zamiast wpakować we mnie cały magazynek, rzucili się na mnie i zaczęli mnie rozbierać - spodobał im się mój kombinezon. To był ich ostatni błąd, a mimo to jeden z nich mnie zahaczył... Ha, starzeję się...\n\n 3. Kiedy przybyłem, posłaniec Striełoka już nie oddychał. Nikt nie ma szans z trzema pijawkami, a ten gościu zakatrupił cztery. Poza tym widziałem jeszcze kilka krwawych tropów. Jedyne informacje, jakie przy nim znalazłem, to kod do drzwi (19840519), ale nie sądzę, by udało mi się dowiedzieć, które drzwi otwiera.\n\n 4. Przechwyciliśmy kilku wojskowych, którzy zmierzali na Radar. Nie mieli przy sobie żadnych dokumentów ani rozkazów, ale byli odpowiednio wyposażeni. Na razie zostawię swojego RG-6 w piwnicy, zabiorę jak będę go potrzebować.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_rg6_task_descr">
		<rus>Воронин: "У Свободы есть несколько отличных гранатомётов РГ-6, если бы у тебя получилось проникнуть на территорию Свободы и выкрасть хотя бы один такой гранатомёт, то я бы щедро тебя вознаградил. Так как ты не в нашей группировке, ты легко можешь втереться в доверие к Свободе и при удачном раскладе спереть РГ-6. Я скину тебе информацию по местонахождению базы Свободы. Там тебе надо найти некоего Повара, члена группы Свободы, он знает, где именно хранится РГ-6. Он слаб на выпивку, поэтому постарайся его опоить. Возьми для этого побольше водки".</rus>
		<eng>Voronin: "Freedom has a few RG-6 grenade launchers. If you could manage to sneak into their territory and steal at least one grenadelauncher, then I would handsomely reward you. Since you're not in our faction, you can easily befriend some Freedom members and, with any luck, steal the RG-6. I'll forward you the info about the location of Freedom. There you have to find a certain Chef, a member of the group Freedom, he knows exactly where the RG-6's are stored. He has a weakness for drink, so try to get him drunk. For that, take a lot of vodka along."</eng>
		<ukr>Воронін: «У «Волі» є кілька чудових гранатометів «Бульдог-6». Якби в тебе вийшло пробратися на територію «Волі» та поцупити хоча б один такий гранатомет, то з мене була б пристойна винагорода. Оскільки ти не в нашому угрупованні, то легко зможеш увійти там у довіру й за слушного випадку викрасти цю зброю. Там тобі треба знайти такого собі Кухаря - він знає, де саме зберігається ця собачка. Кухар ласий випити, тож спробуй його обпоїти. Візьми для цього побільше горілки.»</ukr>
		<fra>Voronine: "L'ennemi possède plusieurs excellents lance-grenades Bulldog 6. Si tu réussissais à t'en procurer t'en procurer un, je te récompenserais comme il se doit. Puisque tu ne fais pas partie de notre faction, tu devrais pouvoir approcher la Liberté et, avec un peu de chance, lui piquer un Bulldog 6. Je t'indiquerai l'endroit où se trouve la Liberté. Là, il faudra que tu trouves un certain Cuistot, un membre du groupe ; il sait où sont stockés les Bulldog 6. Il a tendance à boire, alors essaie de le saouler. Pour ça, apporte beaucoup de vodka."</fra>
		<pln>Woronin: ""Wolność" ma kilka wspaniałych granatników RG-6. Gdyby ci się udało przekraść na ich teren i wynieść stamtąd przynajmniej jeden, dobrze bym cię wynagrodził. Nie należysz do naszej frakcji, więc łatwo możesz ułożyć sobie dobre stosunki z "Wolnością" i przy odrobinie szczęścia zdobyć dla nas "RG-6". Prześlę ci dane co do dokładnego położenia bazy "Wolności". Tam musisz znaleźć niejakiego Kucharza, członka "Wolności", który wie, gdzie składowane są te granatniki. Ma słabość do alkoholu, więc postaraj się go upić. Weź ze sobą dużo wódki".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_go_to_miser_descr">
		<rus>Хм. Награду выдаст Скряга на базе Свободы... Хорошее имя. Может, хоть на просроченные консервы расщедрится.</rus>
		<eng>Hrm. I will get my reward at Freedom's base from Skinflint... Nice name. I should hope for a can of meat with last year's best by date.</eng>
		<ukr>Гм-м... Винагороду видасть Скнара на базі «Волі»... Гарне ім'я. Може, хоч на стару консерву розщедриться?</ukr>
		<fra>Hrm. Le Radin va me donner ma récompense... Joli nom ! J'espère un boite de viande avec une date de péremption datant de l'année dernière.</fra>
		<pln>Hm. W bazie "Wolności" otrzymam nagrodę od kogoś, kto zwie się Kutwa... Ciekawa ksywka. Może da chociaż przeterminowaną konserwę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_hunters_task_descr">
		<rus>Уничтожить кровососов в деревне. Действовать аккуратно, а то они могут меня без крови оставить.</rus>
		<eng>Clean out the bloodsuckers in the village. Got to be careful or they'll drink all my blood and leave me for dead.</eng>
		<ukr>Знищити кровососів у селищі. Діяти акуратно, бо такі швидко без крові залишать.</ukr>
		<fra>Élimine les sangsues du village. Fais gaffe, sinon elles vont te vider de ton sang et te laisser pour mort.</fra>
		<pln>Oczyścić wioskę z pijawek. Trzeba uważać, bo inaczej wypiją ze mnie całą krew.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_hunters_task_descr2">
		<rus>Уничтожить кровососов в деревне. Действовать аккуратно, а то они могут меня без крови оставить.</rus>
		<eng>Clean out the bloodsuckers in the village. Got to be careful or they'll drink all my blood and leave me for dead.</eng>
		<ukr>Знищити кровососів у селищі. Діяти акуратно, бо такі швидко без крові залишать.</ukr>
		<fra>Élimine les sangsues du village. Fais gaffe, sinon elles vont te vider de mon sang et te laisser pour mort.</fra>
		<pln>Oczyścić wioskę z pijawek. Trzeba uważać, bo inaczej wypiją ze mnie całą krew.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_lukash_job_descr">
		<rus>Лукаш решил нанести контрудар по отряду Долга на хуторе. Операцию возглавит Макс - один из ветеранов Свободы. Моя задача - помочь им.</rus>
		<eng>Lukash decided to carry out a counterattack on the Duty detachment at the cottage. Max, one of the veterans from Freedom, will head the operation. My job is to help them.</eng>
		<ukr>Лукаш вирішив завдати контрудар по загону «Долгу» на хуторі. Операцію очолить Макс - один із ветеранів «Волі». Моя задача - допомогти їм.</ukr>
		<fra>Loukache a décidé de contre-attaquer le détachement du Devoir. Max, un des vétérans de la Liberté, va diriger l'opération. Je dois lui prêter main-forte.</fra>
		<pln>Łukasz zdecydował się przeprowadzić kontratak na oddział "Powinności" w wiosce. Akcją będzie dowodził Maks, jeden z weteranów z "Wolności". Moim zadaniem jest im pomóc.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_mad_flash_job_descr">
		<rus>Что, интересно, может знать такого этот безумец на болоте? Разберёмся. Главное не нарваться на старые мины, но они должны быть настолько в ржавом состоянии, что взорвутся от болта.</rus>
		<eng>I wonder what this crazy guy at the swamp can possibly know. I'll figure it out. The important thing is to avoid all those old mines. But - they must be rusty enough to explode from a bolt.</eng>
		<ukr>Що, цікаво, може знати такого цей безголовий на болоті? Ну добре, розберемося. Головне - не нарватися на старі міни… хоча вони, мабуть, настільки проіржавіли, що від болта вибухатимуть.</ukr>
		<fra>Je me demande ce que ce dingue du marécage peut bien savoir. Je vais trouver. Mais il faut à tout prix éviter ces vieilles mines. D'accord, elles sont rouillées, mais ça ne les empêche pas d'exploser.</fra>
		<pln>Ciekawe, co ten szaleniec z bagna może właściwie wiedzieć. Dowiem się. Ważne, żeby nie wpaść na stare miny. Pewnie rdza je tak przeżarła, że mogą wybuchnąć od uderzenia śrubą.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_code_door_info">
		<rus>У мёртвого учёного была какая-то карта с отметкой двери. Код - 1287975.</rus>
		<eng>The dead scientist had a map with a door marked on it. Code 1287975</eng>
		<ukr>Мертвий вчений мав якусь карту з оцінкою дверей. Код - 1287975.</ukr>
		<fra>Le scientifique mort avait une carte indiquant l'emplacement d'une porte. Code 1287975</fra>
		<pln>Martwy naukowiec miał mapę, na której oznaczone są drzwi. Kod 1287975.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_code_door_info_name">
		<rus>Кодовая дверь</rus>
		<eng>Code for the door</eng>
		<ukr>Кодові двері</ukr>
		<fra>Code pour la porte</fra>
		<pln>Drzwi z zamkiem szyfrowym</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_get_to_aes_desc">
		<rus>Бармен: "Тут все просто с ума посходили, когда узнали! Все кто мог, тут же ринулись пробиваться к центру Зоны. Одиночки, Свобода, Долг, даже наёмники. Кто первый доберётся, тот и получит всё! Исполнитель желаний, Клондайк артефактов и, чёрт его знает, что ещё. Поспеши, если Исполнитель действительно в саркофаге станции, то тот, кто первый доберётся, того желание и исполнится. Сейчас как раз перед Припятью собирается отряд ветеранов. Если поспешишь, пойдёшь с ними".</rus>
		<eng>Barkeep:"Everyone here just went crazy when they found out! Everyone who could started pushing towards the center of the Zone: loners, Freedom, Duty, even mercs. The one who gets there first will get everything! Wish granter, the klondike of artifacts, and the devil knows what else. Hurry up, if the Granter is indeed in the sarcophagus of the station, then the one who gets there first will get his wishes granted. Right now there's a detachment of veterans gathering in front of Pripyat. If you hurry, you'll be able to go with them."</eng>
		<ukr>Бармен: "Тут всі просто з глузду з'їхали, коли дізналися! Всі хто міг, тут же кинулися пробиватися до центру Зони. Одинаки, Воля, Долг, навіть найманці. Хто перший добереться, той і отримає все! Виконавець бажань, Клондайк артефактів і, чорт його знає, що ще. Поспішай, якщо Виконавець дійсно в саркофазі станції, то той, хто перший добереться, того бажання й здійсниться. Зараз якраз перед Прип'яттю збирається загін ветеранів. якщо поспішиш, підеш з ними ".</ukr>
		<fra>Barman:"Ils sont tous devenus dingues ici quand ils ont fait cette découverte! Tous ceux qui le pouvaient sont partis pour le centre de la Zone : les solitaires, les membres de la Liberté, les membres du Devoir et même les mercenaires. Le premier qui arrivera sur place décrochera le gros lot ! L'exauceur, la ruée vers les artefacts et que sais-je encore. Dépêche-toi, si l'exauceur est bien dans le sarcophage de la centrale, le premier qui arrivera sur place verra ses voeux exaucés. En ce moment, il y a un détachement de vétérans qui se rassemble devant Pripyat. Si tu dépêches, tu pourras les accompagner".</fra>
		<pln>Barman: "Wszyscy tutaj po prostu oszaleli, kiedy się dowiedzieli! Kto tylko mógł, ruszał do centrum Zony: Samotnicy, "Wolność", "Powinność", nawet najemnicy. Kto się tam znajdzie pierwszy, zgarnie wszystko! Spełniacz Życzeń, kopalnię artefaktów i czort wie, co jeszcze. Pośpiesz się, jeśli Spełniacz rzeczywiście znajduje się w sarkofagu elektrowni, to spełni życzenia tego, kto dotrze tam pierwszy. W tym momencie przed Prypecią zbiera się oddział weteranów. Jeśli się pośpieszysz, będziesz mógł wyruszyć razem z nimi".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_sleep_info">
		<rus>Я отключил Выжигатель. По какой-то причине в момент выключения потерял сознание. И увидел сон: опять громада Чернобыльской станции и саркофага. Потом вспышка. Сияющий "Монолит" внутри саркофага. Я понимаю, что это и есть Исполнитель желаний. Сталкер, оборванный и измождённый, из последних сил протягивает к нему дрожащие руки... яркая вспышка, и я опять вижу отрывок из первого сна... Человек стоит к нам спиной и стреляет. Вдруг раздаётся окрик: "Стрелок!" Человек вздрагивает, застывает на мгновение и медленно начинает поворачиваться... но как кинолента, пущенная в обратную сторону, прокручиваются кадры, как он автоматом загоняет крыс обратно на станцию... Я понимаю одно - я был там. Я должен идти к "Монолиту".</rus>
		<eng>I turned off the Scorcher. For some reason, I lost conciousness just as I did it. Then, I had a dream: I saw again the massive Chernobyl power plant and the sarcophagus. Then a flash. The shining Monolith inside the sarcophagus. I understand that it is the Wish-Granting Machine. A stalker, exhausted and in rags, reaches feebly out to it...a bright flash and I see a fragment of the first dream... A man stands with his back to me and keeps shooting. Someone shouts, "Strelok!". The man shudders, freezes for a moment and then starts to turn slowly...but the pictures slide past, as if a film was played backwards, and I see how he uses his weapon to force the rats back into the station... I realize that I was there. I must go to the Monolith.</eng>
		<ukr>Я відключив Випалювач. З якоїсь причини в момент вимикання знепритомнів… і побачив сон: знову громада Чорнобильської станції та Саркофага. Потім спалах. Сяючий Моноліт усередині саркофага. Я розумію, що це і є Виконавець Бажань. Сталкер, обірваний і виснажений, з останніх сил простягає до нього тремтячі руки... яскравий спалах, і я знову бачу уривок із першого сну... Людина, яка стоїть до мене спиною і стріляє. Раптом чути вигук: «Стрілець!». Людина здригається, застигає на мить і повільно починає обертатися... але потім чомусь, мов кінострічка, пущена у зворотній бік, прокручуються кадри, як вона автоматом заганяє пацюків назад на станцію. Розумію одне: я був там. І я маю йти до Моноліту.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai désactivé le lobotomisateur et au même moment, j'ai perdu connaissance. Ensuite, j'ai fait un rêve : j'ai vu l'immense centrale de Tchernobyl et le sarcophage. Et puis, un flash. Le Monolithe brille à l'intérieur du sarcophage. Je comprends que c'est la machine à exaucer les vœux. Un stalker, épuisé et en guenilles, s'en approche péniblement... Et encore un flash, suivi d'un fragment du premier rêve... Un homme, dos à moi, n'arrête pas de tirer. Quelqu'un crie "Strelok!". L'homme tressaille, s'immobilise un moment et se retourne lentement... Mais les images reviennent en arrière, comme un film à l'envers, et je le vois utiliser son arme pour forcer les rats à retourner dans la centrale... J'ai vécu cette scène, j'en suis sûr. Je dois aller au Monolithe.</fra>
		<pln>Wyłączyłem "Mózgozwęglacz". Z jakiegoś powodu w tym momencie straciłem przytomność. I miałem sen, że znowu... Masyw Czarnobylskiej elektrowni i sarkofagu. Potem błysk. Lśniący Monolit wewnątrz sarkofagu. Rozumiem, że to właśnie jest Spełniacz Życzeń. Wykończony, obdarty stalker z wysiłkiem wyciąga drżące ręce w jego stronę... Jasny błysk!  I znowu... widzę fragment pierwszego snu... Jakiś człowiek stoi plecami do mnie i strzela. Nagle słychać okrzyk: "Striełok!"... Człowiek wzdryga się, na moment zastyga, a potem powoli zaczyna się odwracać w moją stronę... Ale, jak na filmie przewijanym do tyłu, zaczynają przeskakiwać kadry, jak on automatem zagania szczury z powrotem do elektrowni... Pamiętam jedno - byłem tam. Muszę iść do Monolitu.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_sleep_info1">
		<rus>С Выжигателем покончено</rus>
		<eng>The Scorcher is done with</eng>
		<ukr>Із Випалювачем покінчено</ukr>
		<fra>Le lobotomisateur a fini</fra>
		<pln>Koniec z "Mózgozwęglaczem"</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_find_ghost_task">
		<rus>Васильев: "...это координаты входа в лабораторию X-16. Вход находится в подвале центрального здания, задачи этого здания не известны. Предположительно, тех.обеспечение подземных излучателей: изучение документации от N*** раскрывает предназначение этого проекта - крупномасштабная психотропная разработка по массовому воздействию на...\n\n... все необходимые документы у нас, мы знаем, как отключить излучатель. Продолжаем спускаться с Призраком в лабораторию. Зомби повсюду лезут на свет...\n\n... всё летит к чертям собачьим, Призрак абсолютно невменяем, несёт какой-то бред. Похоже, его накрыло излучением. Я всё бросил и ухожу по тоннелям...\n\n... я на болотах, где бункер? Чёрт, чёрт, чёрт!!! Я не могу определить, где я нахожусь! Сахаров - трус, не отвечает!!! Что происходит??? Кругом зомби, у меня кончаются патроны..."</rus>
		<eng>Vasiliev: "...these are the co-ordinates of the entrance to Lab X16. The entrance is located in the basement of the central building; the building's purpose is unknown. I guess it is used for the technical servicing of the underground emitters: based on the documentation from N***, the intended purpose of this project is the full-scale development of psychotronic weapons with large area effects on...\n\n ...all the necessary documents are in our possession and we know how to turn off the emitter. We're going down inside the lab with Ghost. Zombies are coming out from everywhere...\n\n ...everything is going to the dogs, Ghost has gone absolutely insane and is delirious. Looks like he's succumbed to the emission. I've abandoned everything and started to go back through the tunnels...\n\n ...I'm in the swamps, where's the bunker? Damn, damn, damn!!! I can't pinpoint my location! That coward Sakharov isn't responding!!! What's happening??? ...zombies are everywhere and I'm running out of ammo..."</eng>
		<ukr>Васильєв: «...це координати входу до лабораторії X-16. Вхід знаходиться у підвалі центральної будівлі, призначення якої невідоме… ймовірно, технічне забезпечення підземних випромінювачів. Вивчення документації від N*** розкриває призначення цього проекту: великомасштабна розробка із масового психотропного впливу на...»\n\n «...усі необхідні документи в нас. Ми знаємо, як відключити випромінювач. Продовжуємо спускатися із Привидом до лабораторії. Зомбі всюди лізуть на світло...»\n\n «...усе летить до дідька! Привид з'їхав з глузду, торочить якусь маячню. Схоже, його накрило випромінюванням. Я усе кинув і йду тунелями...»\n\n «...я на болотах, де бункер? Паскудство, паскудство, паскудство!!! Я не можу визначити, де я знаходжуся! Сахаров - боягуз, не відповідає! Що відбувається?!» «...навкруги повно зомбі, в мене закінчуються набої...»</ukr>
		<fra>Vassiliev: "...voici les coordonnées de l'entrée du Labo X16. L'entrée se trouve au sous-sol du bâtiment central ; on ignore ce qu'il y a dans ce bâtiment. Je suppose qu'il sert à l'entretien technique des émetteurs souterrains : d'après la documentation de N***, ce projet est consacré au développement à grande échelle d'armes psychotroniques aux effets importants sur...\n\n ... on a tous les documents nécessaires et on sait comment désactiver l'émetteur. Je vais descendre dans le labo avec Spectre. Les zombies arrivent de partout...\n\n ... Spectre est devenu complètement fou, il délire. Il a dû succomber à l'émission. J'ai tout laissé tomber et commencé à rebrousser chemin par les tunnels...\n\n ... Je suis dans les marécages, où est le  bunker ? Merde, merde, merde !!! Je n'arrive pas à me repérer ! Ce lâche de Sakharov ne répond pas !!! Que se passe-t-il ??? ... Il y a des zombies partout et je suis à court de munitions... "</fra>
		<pln>Wasiliew: "...to współrzędne wejścia do laboratorium X-16. Znajduje się w piwnicy głównego budynku, którego przeznaczenia nie znamy. Podejrzewam, że to w nim odbywają się przeglądy techniczne podziemnych emiterów: na podstawie dokumentów od N*** wnoszę, że projekt ten ma na celu przeprowadzony na szeroką skalę rozwój broni psychotronicznej o dużym polu oddziaływania na...\n\n ...Posiadamy wszystkie niezbędne dokumenty i wiemy, jak wyłączyć emiter. Schodzimy z Duchem do laboratorium. Zewsząd wyłażą zombie...\n\n ...Wszystko idzie nie tak, Duch zupełnie oszalał i bredzi. Chyba uległ działaniu emisji. Rzuciłem wszystko i uciekam tunelami...\n\n ...Jestem na bagnach, gdzie ten bunkier? Do jasnej cholery!!! Nie potrafię określić swojego położenia! Ten tchórz, Sacharow, nie odpowiada!!! Co się dzieje??? Wszędzie pełno zombie, a mnie się kończy amunicja..."</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_find_lab">
		<rus>Сахаров: "Всё что тебе надо сделать, это найти труп Васильева и получить точную информацию о местонахождении лаборатории. Затем, проникнув в лабораторию, отыскать Призрака. Призрак знал, как отключить излучение и как потом выбраться".</rus>
		<eng>Sakharov: "All you need to do is find Vasiliev's corpse and obtain accurate information about the location of the laboratory. Then get inside the laboratory and find Ghost. Ghost knew how to turn off the emission and how to get out of there afterwards."</eng>
		<ukr>Сахаров: «Усе, що треба зробити - це знайти труп Васильєва та отримати точну інформацію про місцезнаходження лабораторії. Потім, проникнувши до лабораторії, відшукати Привида. Привид знав, як відключити випромінювання і як потім вибратися.»</ukr>
		<fra>Sakharov: "Trouvez le cadavre de Vassiliev et des informations précises sur l'emplacement du laboratoire. Puis entrez-y et trouvez Spectre. Il sait comment désactiver les émissions et quitter les lieux."</fra>
		<pln>Sacharow: "Musisz jedynie odnaleźć ciało Wasiliewa i zdobyć dokładne informacje o położeniu laboratorium X-16. Potem, przeniknąwszy do laboratorium, odnaleźć Ducha. On wiedział, jak wyłączyć emisję i jak się później stamtąd wydostać".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_find_scientist">
		<rus>Сахаров: "Если Вы вместе с нашим сотрудником сделаете замеры, я дам настроенный прототип, который позволит Вам проникнуть в лабораторию".</rus>
		<eng>Sakharov: "If you can take the measurements together with our associate, I will give you a calibrated prototype that will let you get inside the laboratory."</eng>
		<ukr>Сахаров: «Якщо ти разом із нашим співробітником зробиш виміри, я дам налаштований прототип, котрий дозволить проникнути до лабораторії.»</ukr>
		<fra>Sakharov: "Si votre associé et vous réussissez à prendre les mesures, je vous donnerai un prototype en état de marche pour vous permettre d'accéder au laboratoire."</fra>
		<pln>Sacharow: "Jeśli razem z naszym współpracownikiem wykonacie pomiary, ja dam skalibrowany prototyp, który pozwoli Wam wejść do laboratorium".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_find_scientist_semenov">
		<rus>Сахаров: "Если Вы вместе с нашим сотрудником сделаете замеры, я дам настроенный прототип, который позволит Вам проникнуть в лабораторию".</rus>
		<eng>Sakharov: "If you can take the measurements together with our associate, I will give you a calibrated prototype that will let you get inside the laboratory."</eng>
		<ukr>Сахаров: «Якщо ти разом із нашим співробітником зробиш виміри, я дам налаштований прототип, котрий дозволить проникнути до лабораторії.»</ukr>
		<fra>Sakharov: "Si votre associé et vous réussissez à prendre les mesures, je vous donnerai un prototype en état de marche pour vous permettre d'accéder au laboratoire."</fra>
		<pln>Sacharow: "Jeśli razem z naszym współpracownikiem wykonacie pomiary, ja dam skalibrowany prototyp, który pozwoli Wam wejść do laboratorium".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_kill_brain">
		<rus>Сахаров: "Молодец, Меченый, Вы добрались до лаборатории. Для нас крайне важно изучить установку, которая там находится. Попробуйте её отключить, чтобы мы смогли её исследовать.\n\nПослушайте, Меченый, прототип не сможет долго защищать от сильного излучения. Я предусмотрел такой случай, поэтому, когда Вы попадёте под сильное воздействие, включится таймер. Когда время истечёт, прототип перестанет Вас защищать. Будьте осторожней и не забывайте про таймер".</rus>
		<eng>Sakharov: "Well done, Marked One, you've made it to the laboratory after all. It is extremely important for us to study the mechanism that is based in the laboratory. Try to disable it so that we can investigate it.\n\n Listen, Marked One, the prototype will not be able to protect you against severe radiation. I've thought of this beforehand, so there is a timer in our armor that will start ticking when you come under strong exposure. When the time is up, the prototype will stop protecting you. Be most careful and don't forget about the timer."</eng>
		<ukr>Сахаров: «Молодець, Мічений, ти таки дістався лабораторії. Для нас украй важливо вивчити установку, що там знаходиться. Спробуй її вимкнути, щоб ми змогли її дослідити.».\n\n «Послухай, Мічений... прототип не зможе довго захищати від сильного випромінювання. Я передбачив такий випадок, тому, якщо потрапиш під сильний вплив, автоматично увімкнеться таймер. Коли час мине, прототип перестане тебе захищати. Обережніше там... і не забувай про таймер.»</ukr>
		<fra>Sakharov: "Bien joué, le Marqué, vous avez réussi à rejoindre le laboratoire. Il faut à tout prix qu'on étudie le mécanisme qui s'y trouve. Essayez de le désactiver pour nous permettre de l'examiner.\n\n ... Écoutez, le Marqué, le prototype ne vous protégera pas des pires radiations. J'y ai déjà réfléchi et j'ai intégré un chronomètre à notre armure qui se déclenchera en cas de forte exposition. Une fois le temps écoulé, le prototype ne vous protégera plus. Faites bien attention et n'oubliez pas ce chronomètre."</fra>
		<pln>Sacharow: "Dobra robota, Naznaczony, dotarliście do laboratorium. Zbadanie znajdującej się tam instalacji jest dla nas niezmiernie ważne. Postarajcie się ją wyłączyć, żebyśmy mogli to zrobić.\n\nPosłuchajcie, Naznaczony, prototyp nie może zbyt długo chronić Was przed silnym promieniowaniem. Przewidziałem to, i dlatego, gdy traficie w obszar silnego promieniowania, włączy się zegar. Kiedy czas minie, prototyp przestanie Was chronić. Zachowajcie wyjątkową ostrożność i nie zapominajcie o zegarze".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_kill_brain_2">
		<rus>Установка отключена. Осталось дело за малым - выбраться живым.</rus>
		<eng>The device is turned off. You will just have to get out of there alive.</eng>
		<ukr>Установку відключено. Залишилася іще одна справа: вибратися живим.</ukr>
		<fra>Le dispositif est désactivé. Vous allez quitter les lieux sans qu'il vous arrive quoi que ce soit.</fra>
		<pln>Urządzenie zostało wyłączone. Pozostał tylko drobiazg - wydostać się stamtąd żywym.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_provodnik_task">
		<rus>Призрак: "Проводник, я отправлю к тебе человека, у нас есть важная информация для Доктора, посодействуй ему".\n\nПроводник: "Хорошо. Только, Призрак, не как в прошлый раз. А лучше сам давай, давно хочу с тобой потолковать. Жду как обычно, в лагере возле моста. Не пропадай и смотри армейским патрулям не попадись".</rus>
		<eng>Ghost: "Entry #257\n Guide, I am sending a man to meet you, we have important information for Doctor, help him out. \n Guide: "Good. But, Ghost, let's not repeat what happened last time. You make the trip yourself, I've wanted to have a chat with you for a while. I'll be waiting at the usual place, in the camp by the bridge. Don't get lost and don't let the army patrols get you."</eng>
		<ukr>Привид: «Провідниче, я відправлю до тебе людину. Маємо важливу інформацію для Доктора, допоможи йому».\n\nПровідник: «Добре. Тільки одне, Привиде: щоб не було так, як минулого разу. А краще сам давай… давно хочу із тобою побалакати. Чекаю як завжди - у таборі поблизу мосту. Не пропадай… і, дивись, армійським патрулям не дайся.»</ukr>
		<fra>Spectre: "Entrée n°257\n Guide, je t'envoie quelqu'un. On a des infos importantes pour le Docteur, aide-le."\n\n Guide: "OK, Spectre. Mais, ne refaisons pas la même erreur que la dernière fois. Viens seul, je voudrais discuter un moment avec toi. J'attendrai à l'endroit habituel, au camp, près du pont. Ne te perds pas et essaie de ne pas te faire prendre par les patrouilles armées."</fra>
		<pln>Duch: "Przewodniku, wysyłam do ciebie człowieka. Mamy ważne informacje dla Doktora, pomóż mu". \n\nPrzewodnik: "Dobrze. Ale Duch, nie tak, jak ostatnim razem. A najlepiej sam przyjdź, już od dawna chcę z tobą porozmawiać. Będę czekać w stałym miejscu, przy moście. Nie zgub się i uważaj na patrole wojskowe".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_scientist_return_task">
		<rus>Сахаров: "Что случилось?! Он погиб?! Возьмите замеры и немедленно возвращайтесь!"</rus>
		<eng>Sakharov: "What happened??? He's dead??? Take the measurements and return immediately!!!"</eng>
		<ukr>Сахаров: «Що сталося?! Він загинув?.. Візьми результати вимірів і негайно повертайся!»</ukr>
		<fra>Sakharov : "Que s'est-il passé ??? Il est mort ??? Prenez les mesures et revenez immédiatement !!!"</fra>
		<pln>Sacharow: "Co się stało?! Nie żyje?! Zróbcie pomiary i natychmiast wracajcie!"</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_find_ghost">
		<rus>Я в шоке! Призрак и человек с фотографии в КПК, приложенной к заданию убить Стрелка, это один и тот же человек. Я ничего не понимаю. Значит, произошла какая-то ошибка. Вот только кто её допустил? Пока ответа нет. Из записей Призрака я узнал имя общего знакомого и четвёртого в группе Стрелка. Его зовут Доктор. Он долгое время помогал группе и выполнял, судя по всему, роль штаба. Найти его можно через сталкера по прозвищу Проводник, который частенько бывает на Кордоне. Ну что ж, Проводник, смотри, не умри случайно... до нашей встречи. На трупе Призрака также нашёл документы по установке "пси-мозг". Вся округа находилась под влиянием этой хрени - она зомбировала всех входящих в зону её действия. Я узнал, что существует ещё одна установка в лаборатории Х-19 и, скорее всего, она и является Выжигателем мозгов. Ещё я узнал, что эти установки не всегда работают на полную силу. Есть периоды, когда они понижают мощность излучения для охлаждения агрегатов.</rus>
		<eng>I'm shocked! Ghost is the same person as the man on the photo from the file attached to the mission to kill Strelok. I'm thoroughly confused. There must have been some mistake. But who made the mistake? There is no answer yet. From Ghost's records I learned the name of their "mutual acquaintance" - the fourth man in Strelok's group - Doctor. He has been helping the group for a long time playing the role of their "headquarters". He can be found through a stalker by the name of Guide, who frequents Cordon. Alright, Guide, just don't go dying all of a sudden... before we meet. On Ghost's dead body I also found documents regarding the "Psi-Brain" mechanism. The whole neigborhood was under the influence of that piece of trash - it zombified everyone who came within range. I learned that there is another mechanism in Lab X19, and that's what is likely to be the Brain Scorcher. I also learned that these mechanisms are not always operating at full strength. There are periods when their power is lowered to cool down the apparatus.</eng>
		<ukr>Голова обертом! Привид та людина із фотографії у КПК, доданої до завдання щодо вбивства Стрільця - це та сама людина! Я нічого не розумію. Значить, сталася якась помилка. Однак хто її припустився? Поки відповіді немає. Із записів Привида я довідався ім'я «загального знайомого»: це Доктор, четвертий у групі Стрільця. Він довгий час допомагав групі й виконував, судячи з усього, роль голови штабу. Знайти його можна через сталкера на прізвисько Провідник, якого часто бачать на кордоні. Ну що ж, Провідниче, аби ти тільки не помер раптово... до того, як відбудеться наша зустріч. На трупі Привида також знайшов документи про установку «псі-Мозок». Уся околиця знаходилася під впливом цього паскудства, котре зомбіювало усіх, хто входив до зони дії. Я довідався про існування ще однієї установки в лабораторії Х-19 - і, швидше за все, вона і є той легендарний Випалювач Мізків. Ще: ці установки не завжди працюють на повну силу - є періоди, коли вони знижують потужність випромінювання для профілактики устаткування.</ukr>
		<fra>Je suis sous le choc! Spectre est la même personne que celle en photo sur le dossier de la mission visant à tuer Strelok. Je n'y comprends plus rien. Il doit y avoir une erreur. Mais qui a fait cette erreur? Pas de réponse. Dans les archives de Spectre, j'ai vu le nom de leur "relation mutuelle", le quatrième homme du groupe de Strelok, le Docteur. Voilà longtemps qu'il aide le groupe en leur fournissant un "QG". En tant que stalker, il est connu sous le nom de Guide et fréquente le Cordon. Très bien, Guide, ne meurs pas avant qu'on se rencontre. Sur le cadavre de Spectre, j'ai aussi trouvé des documents concernant le mécanisme du "cerveau psi". Tout le voisinage était sous l'influence de ce truc... Il a zombifié tout ce qui était à sa portée. J'ai appris qu'il y a un autre mécanisme dans le Labo X19 et qu'il doit s'agir du lobotomisateur. J'ai appris que ces mécanismes ne fonctionnent pas toujours à plein régime, notamment lors de leur refroidissement.</fra>
		<pln>Jestem w szoku... Duch i człowiek z fotografii w PDA, dodanej do zadania na zabicie Striełoka, to... jeden i ten sam człowiek! Już nic z tego nie rozumiem. To chyba jakiś błąd. Ale kto go popełnił? Na razie nie znam odpowiedzi. Z zapisków Ducha poznałem imię ich wspólnego znajomego i czwartego członka grupy Striełoka. Nazywa się Doktor. Od dawna pomaga grupie, a miejsce, gdzie przebywa, robi za ich kwaterę główną. Można go znaleźć przez stalkera zwanego Przewodnikiem, który często bywa na Kordonie. W porządku, Przewodniku, tylko nie umrzyj nagle... zanim się nie spotkamy. Przy zwłokach Ducha znalazłem również dokumenty dotyczące mechanizmu "mózgu psionicznego". Cała okolica była pod wpływem tego draństwa - uzombifikował wszystkich, którzy znaleźli się w jego zasięgu. Dowiedziałem się, że w laboratorium X-10 jest jeszcze jedna instalacja i że prawdopodobnie to właśnie jest "Mózgozwęglacz". Wiem również, że te instalacje nie zawsze działają pełną parą. Są okresy, w których zmniejsza się moc ich promieniowania, żeby można było schłodzić agregaty.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_find_ghost_name">
		<rus>Ещё одна загадка</rus>
		<eng>One more puzzle</eng>
		<ukr>Ще одна загадка</ukr>
		<fra>Encore une énigme</fra>
		<pln>Kolejna zagadka</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_kill_brain">
		<rus>После отключения этого отвратительного мозга в колбе потерял сознание. Видимо, сказалось напряжение последних дней. Пока был в отключке, увидел сон... Фотография. Её держит седой человек, у его ног вертится огромный пёс. Человек смотрит в даль, но вокруг лишь болота, и пейзаж совсем не похож на то, что изображено на фотографии. В тумане едва можно разглядеть удаляющуюся фигуру. Человек бормочет, словно беседует сам с собой: "Если это так важно, то почему ты мне так толком и не объяснил, что это за место и откуда у тебя эта фотография..." Потом... я вижу со стороны молодого улыбающегося парня на пороге хижины, который весело объявляет: "Если бы ты знал, где мне удалось побывать, и что я там видел!" Он протягивает какую-то удивительную штуковину, от которой разливается сияние по хижине. Пёс начинает рычать и забивается в угол, а седой человек бормочет: "Ты когда-нибудь доиграешься". Вспышка... вот тот же парень с ужасно изуродованным и окровавленным лицом вваливается в двери хижины и падает на порог... За дверью бьют молнии, хлещет ливень. Вспышка... Кровать в избушке, на ней лежит тот же парень, но лицо у него всё в шрамах и бинтах. Парень без сознания, а седой человек бормочет: "Держись, сынок..." В углу свалены вещи, и среди них эта странная фотография... Вспышка... фотография в руках седого. Человек со шрамами на лице собирается уходить. Седой спрашивает его: "Куда ты теперь?" Следует мрачный ответ: "На север". Вспышка... и я очнулся.</rus>
		<eng>After turning off that horrible "brain in a tube" I fell unconscious. The pressure of the last few days must have taken its toll. While I was out, I had a dream...A photograph. A gray-haired man is holding it in his hands and a huge dog is at his feet. The man is looking into the distance, but around him there is only a swamp; the landscape doesn't look at all like what's on the photo. In the fog I can see the silhouette of someone walking away. The man is talking to himself: "If it's so important, why didn't you tell me what this place is and where you got the photo"... then... on the side I see a smiling young man standing on the threshold of the cabin, who says cheerfully: "If only you knew where I was and what I saw there!" He extends his arm holding a marvellous device which lights up the whole cabin. The dog starts to growl and squeezes into a corner; the gray-haired man mumbles: "Some day these games will spell trouble for you." ...flash... the same young man with his face covered in blood stumbles inside the cabin door and falls... Lightning flashes in the sky, heavy rain is pouring down ...flash... The cabin bed with the young man covered in bandages. He is unconscious; the gray-haired man mumbles: "Hang in there, son". Some personal things are piled in a corner and among them there is that strange photo ...flash... the photo is in the hands of the gray-haired man. The young man, now with scars on his face, is about to leave. The gray-haired man asks him: "Where are you off to now?". The gloomy answer follows: "The North"...flash... then I woke up.</eng>
		<ukr>Після відключення цього огидного мозку в колбі знепритомнів. Вочевидь, далася взнаки напруга останніх днів. Поки був у відключці, бачив сон... Фотографія, яку тримає сива людина, а біля її ніг сновигає пес. Людина вдивляється у далечінь, але навколо лише болота і пейзаж, зовсім не схожий на той, що зображений на фотографії. Потім бачу фігуру, що йде в імлу... ледь можна розгледіти. Людина бурмоче під носа, нібито розмовляє сама із собою: «Якщо це так важливо, то чому ти мені так і не пояснив, що то за місце і звідки в тебе ця фотографія…». Потім... потім я бачу молодого усміхненого хлопця на порозі хатини, який весело каже: «Якби ти знав, де мені вдалося побувати і що я там бачив!» Він простягує якусь дивну річ, від якої по хатині розливається сяйво. Пес починає гарчати і забивається в куток, а сива людина бурмоче: «Ти колись таки дограєшся». Потім спалах... і той самий хлопець із понівеченим, закривавленим обличчям пада у двері хатини і лишається на порозі... За дверима - блискавки, злива... Знову спалах. Ліжко в хатинці, на ньому лежить той хлопець і обличчя в нього усе в шрамах та бинтах. Він непритомний, а сива людина бурмоче: «Тримайся, синку...». У кутку звалені речі й серед них ця дивна фотографія... Спалах... фотографія в руках сивого. Людина зі шрамами на обличчі збирається йти. Сивий запитує його: «Куди ти тепер?». Той похмуро відповідає: «На північ». Знову спалах... тут я прокинувся.</ukr>
		<fra>Après avoir désactivé cet horrible "cerveau en tube", j'ai perdu connaissance. Sûrement la pression des derniers jours. Et j'ai fait un rêve... J'ai vu une photo. Un homme aux cheveux gris la tenait dans ses mains, avec à ses pieds un énorme chien. L'homme regardait au loin, mais autour de lui, il y avait un marécage ; le paysage ne ressemblait pas à celui de la photo. Dans le brouillard, j'ai vu une silhouette qui s'en allait. L'homme se parlait à lui-même : "Si c'est tellement important, pourquoi est-ce que tu ne me dis pas quel est cet endroit et où tu as eu cette photo"... Puis, sur le côté, j'ai vu un homme souriant qui se tenait sur le seuil d'une cabane et qui a dit chaleureusement : "Si seulement tu savais où j'étais et ce que j'ai vu !" Il a tendu le bras et tenait un appareil extraordinaire qui a éclairé toute la cabane. Le chien a commencé à grogner et à se blottir dans un coin, l'homme aux cheveux gris a marmonné : "Un jour, ces jeux se retourneront contre toi." Puis le même jeune homme, le visage couvert de sang, a titubé avant de tomber... Des éclairs ont illuminé le ciel, la pluie s'est mise à tomber… Le jeune homme était allongé dans la cabane, recouvert de bandages. Il était inconscient ; l'homme aux cheveux gris a marmonné : "Tiens bon, fiston". Des effets personnels étaient empilés dans un coin et parmi eux, cette étrange photo… Le jeune homme, le visage présent couvert de cicatrices, était sur le point de partir. L'homme aux cheveux gris lui a demandé : "Où est-ce que tu vas, maintenant ?". Ce à quoi, le jeune homme lui a répondu : "Au nord"... Et là, je me suis réveillé.</fra>
		<pln>Po wyłączeniu tego potwornego mózgu w kolbie straciłem przytomność. Napięcie ostatnich dni dało chyba o sobie znać. Gdy byłem nieprzytomny, miałem sen... Zdjęcie. Trzyma je siwowłosy mężczyzna, a u jego stóp siedzi wielki pies. Mężczyzna patrzy w dal, ale wokół niego widać tylko bagno, a krajobraz wcale nie przypomina tego ze zdjęcia. We mgle ledwo można odróżnić sylwetkę oddalającej się postaci. Mężczyzna mamrocze, jakby rozmawiał z samym sobą: "Jeśli to takie ważne, dlaczego mi nie powiedziałeś, co to za miejsce i skąd masz to zdjęcie..." Potem...  widzę z boku uśmiechającego się młodego mężczyznę, który stoi na progu chaty i mówi wesoło: "Gdybyś tylko wiedział, gdzie byłem i co tam widziałem!" Wyciąga rękę, w której trzyma dziwaczną rzecz, od której płynie blask na całą chatę. Pies zaczyna warczeć i chowa się w kącie, a siwy mężczyzna mamrocze: "Któregoś dnia te gierki sprowadzą na ciebie kłopoty"... Błysk... Ten sam młody mężczyzna, z twarzą zniekształconą i pokrytą krwią, niepewnym krokiem wchodzi do chaty i pada za progiem... Niebo przecinają błyskawice, chlasta ulewny deszcz... Błysk... Łóżko w izbie, na nim ten młody mężczyzna, jego twarz cała w szramach i bandażach. Jest nieprzytomny, a siwowłosy mamrocze: "Trzymaj się, synu". W kącie zwalone na stos leżą rzeczy, wśród nich to dziwne zdjęcie... Błysk... zdjęcie w rękach siwego. Młody mężczyzna z bliznami na twarzy zbiera się do odejścia. Siwowłosy pyta: "A dokąd teraz?". Pada ponura odpowiedź: "Na północ"... Błysk... potem się obudziłem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_kill_brain_name">
		<rus>Второй сон</rus>
		<eng>The second dream</eng>
		<ukr>Другий сон</ukr>
		<fra>Le deuxième rêve</fra>
		<pln>Drugi sen</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_vasilyev_pda">
		<rus>Ну вот я почти в шаге от одного из людей Стрелка. Призрак с одним из учёных ушёл в подземную лабораторию Х-16. Одно но - я вряд ли найду его живым. Учёный вернулся оттуда один и погиб уже на подходе к лагерю. Учёные выдали мне некое защитное устройство для защиты от этого неизвестного излучения. Надеюсь, оно оправдает себя. Они хотят, чтобы я проник внутрь и отключил источник излучения - тогда они смогут изучить всё на месте. Ну что ж, с Богом.</rus>
		<eng>So, here I am just one step away from one of Strelok's men. Ghost went to the underground Lab X16 with one of the scientists. There is only one "but" - I'm not likely to find him alive. The scientist was coming back from there alone and was killed when approaching the camp. The scientists gave me some kind of device to protect me against these obscure emissions. I hope it works. They want me to get inside and unplug the emitter - then they will be able to study it on site. God help me.</eng>
		<ukr>Ну от, я за півкрока від одного з людей Стрільця. Привид з одним із учених пішли до підземної лабораторії Х-16. Одне «але» - я навряд чи знайду Привида живим. Учений вийшов звідти один і загинув уже на підході до табору. Його колеги видали мені якийсь захисний пристрій проти цього невідомого випромінювання. Сподіваюся, він виправдає себе. Вони хочуть, щоб я зайшов усередину і відключив джерело випромінювання: тоді можна буде вивчити усе на місці. Що ж… хай нам щастить.</ukr>
		<fra>Alors, comme ça, je suis tout près d'un des hommes de Strelok. Spectre est allé au Labo X16 souterrain avec un scientifique mais j'ai peu de chance de le retrouver en vie. Le scientifique rentrait au camp quand il a été tué. Ses collègues m'ont donné un dispositif pour me protéger de ces obscures émissions. J'espère que ça marchera. Ils veulent que j'aille à l'intérieur et que je débranche l'émetteur, après quoi ils l'étudieront sur place. Ça promet !</fra>
		<pln>No i znalazłem się niemal o krok od jednego z ludzi Striełoka. Duch zszedł do podziemnego laboratorium X-16 wraz z jednym z naukowców. Jest tylko jedno ale... Raczej nie odnajdę go żywego. Naukowiec wrócił stamtąd sam i zginął, gdy zbliżał się do obozu. Naukowcy dali mi jakieś urządzenie, które ma mnie chronić przed tymi tajemniczymi emisjami. Mam nadzieję, że zadziała. Chcą, żebym się dostał do środka i wyłączył emiter. Wtedy będą w stanie zbadać go na miejscu. No cóż... Z Bogiem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_vasilyev_pda_name">
		<rus>В шаге от Призрака</rus>
		<eng>One step away from Ghost</eng>
		<ukr>В одному кроку від Привида</ukr>
		<fra>Tout près de Spectre</fra>
		<pln>O krok od Ducha</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_ghost_info">
		<rus>Запись N257\n&gt;&gt;Проводник, я отправлю к тебе человека, у нас есть важная информация для Доктора, посодействуй ему\n&gt;&gt;Хорошо. Только, Призрак, не как в прошлый раз. А лучше сам давай, давно хочу с тобой потолковать. Жду как обычно, в лагере возле моста. Не пропадай и смотри армейским патрулям не попадись.\n\nЗапись N384\n...Васильев в последний момент струсил и вместо того, чтобы отключить нижние пульты, просто сбежал, когда открылась дверь. Не надо было на него полагаться, правильно Стрелок не доверял этим лживым собакам. Мой единственный шанс - добраться до двери раньше контролёра...</rus>
		<eng>Entry #257\n &gt;&gt;Guide, I am sending someone to meet you. We have important information for Doctor, help him out\n &gt;&gt;&gt; Good. But, Ghost, let's not repeat what happened last time. You come yourself, I've wanted to have a chat with you for a while. I'll be waiting at the usual place, in the camp near the bridge. Don't get lost and don't let the army patrols catch you."\n\n Entry #384\n …At the last moment, Vasiliev chickened out and instead of unplugging the lower console, he just ran off when the door opened. I shouldn't have relied on him - Strelok was right not to trust these lying dogs. My only chance is to reach the door before the controller...</eng>
		<ukr>Запис №257\n &gt;&gt;Провідниче, я відправлю до тебе людину: в нас є важлива інформація для Доктора, допоможи йому.\n &gt;&gt;Добре. Тільки, Привиде, не як минулого разу. А краще сам давай, давно хочу із тобою погомоніти. Чекаю як завжди, у таборі біля мосту. Не пропадай і, дивись, армійським патрулям на очі не трапляй.\n\n Запис N384\n «…Васильєв в останній момент перепудився і замість того, щоб відключити нижні пульти, просто втік, коли відкрилися двері. Не треба було на нього покладатися, правильно Стрілець не довіряв цим брехливим собакам! Мій єдиний шанс - дістатися дверей раніше за контролера...»</ukr>
		<fra>Entrée n°257\n &gt;&gt;Guide, je t'envoie quelqu'un. On a des infos importantes pour le Docteur, aide-le.\n &gt;&gt;&gt; OK, Spectre. Mais, ne refaisons pas la même erreur que la dernière fois. Viens seul, je voudrais discuter un moment avec toi. J'attendrai à l'endroit habituel, au camp, près du pont. Ne te perds pas et essaie de ne pas te faire prendre par les patrouilles armées."\n\n Entrée n°384\n ... Au dernier moment, Vassiliev a flanché et au lieu de débrancher la console inférieure, quand la porte s'est ouverte, il s'est enfui. Je n'aurais pas dû lui faire confiance - Strelok avait raison, on ne peut pas se fier à ces menteurs. Ma seule chance est d'atteindre la porte avant le manipulateur...</fra>
		<pln>Zapis nr257\n&gt;&gt;Przewodnik, wysyłam do ciebie człowieka. Mamy ważne informacje dla Doktora, pomóż mu.\n&gt;&gt;Dobrze. Ale Duch, nie tak, jak ostatnim razem. A najlepiej sam przyjdź, już od dawna chcę z tobą porozmawiać. Będę czekać w stałym miejscu, przy moście. Nie zgub się i uważaj na patrole wojskowe.\n\n Zapis nr384\n ...Wasiliew stchórzył w ostatniej chwili i zamiast odłączyć dolne tablice sterownicze, po prostu uciekł, gdy otworzyły się drzwi. Nie trzeba było na nim polegać. Miał rację Striełok, że nie należy ufać tym kłamliwym psom. Moja jedyna szansa - to dotarcie do drzwi, zanim kontroler...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_vasilyev_info">
		<rus>... это координаты входа в лабораторию X-16. Вход находится в подвале центрального здания, задачи этого здания не известны. Предположительно, тех.обеспечение подземных излучателей: изучение документации от N*** раскрывает предназначение этого проекта - крупномасштабная психотронная разработка по массовому воздействию на...\n\n... все необходимые документы у нас, мы знаем, как отключить излучатель. Продолжаем спускаться с Призраком в лабораторию. Зомби повсюду лезут на свет...\n\n... всё летит к чертям собачьим, Призрак абсолютно невменяем, несёт какой-то бред. Похоже, его накрыло излучением. Я всё бросил и ухожу по тоннелям...\n\n... я на болотах, где бункер? Чёрт, чёрт, чёрт!!! Я не могу определить, где я нахожусь! Сахаров - трус, не отвечает!!! Что происходит??? Кругом зомби, у меня кончаются патроны...</rus>
		<eng>...these are the co-ordinates of the entrance to Lab X16. The entrance is located in the basement of the central building; the building's purpose is unknown. I guess it is used for the technical servicing of the underground emitters: based on the documentation from N***, the intended purpose of this project is the full-scale development of psychotronic weapons with huge area effects on...\n\n ...all the necessary documents are in our possession and we know how to turn off the emitter. We're going down inside the lab with Ghost. Zombies are coming out from everywhere...\n\n ...everything is going to the dogs, Ghost has gone absolutely insane and is delirious. Looks like he's succumbed to the emission. I've abandoned everything and started to go back through the tunnels...\n\n ...I'm in the swamps, where's the bunker? Damn, damn, damn!!! I can't pinpoint my location! That coward Sakharov isn't responding!!! What's happening??? ...zombies are everywhere and I'm running out of ammo...</eng>
		<ukr>...це координати входу до лабораторії X-16. Вхід знаходиться у підвалі центральної будівлі. Призначення останньої невідоме - ймовірно, технічне забезпечення підземних випромінювачів, Вивчення документації від N*** розкриває призначення цього проекту: великомасштабне вивчення масового психотропного впливу на...\n\n ...усі необхідні документи в нас, ми знаємо, як відключити випромінювач. Продовжуємо спускатися із Привидом до лабораторії. Зомбі всюди лізуть на світло...\n\n ...усе летить шкереберть, Привид зовсім з'їхав з глузду, белькотить якусь маячню. Схоже, його накрило випромінюванням. Я все кинув і йду тунелями...\n\n ...я на болотах, де бункер? Паскудство, паскудство, паскудство! Я не можу визначити, де знаходжуся! Сахаров боягуз, не відповідає! Що відбувається?! ...навкруги зомбі, в мене закінчуються набої...</ukr>
		<fra>... voici les coordonnées de l'entrée du labo X-16. L'entrée se trouve au sous-sol du bâtiment central; on ignore ce qu'il y a dans ce bâtiment. Je suppose qu'il sert à l'entretien technique des émetteurs souterrains : d'après la documentation de N***, ce projet est consacré au développement à grande échelle d'armes psychotroniques aux effets importants sur...\n\n... on a tous les documents nécessaires et on sait comment désactiver l'émetteur. Je vais descendre dans la labo avec Spectre. Les zombies arrivent de partout...\n\n... Spectre est devenu complètement fou, il délire. Il a dû succomber à l'émission. J'ai tout laissé tomber et commencé à rebrousser chemin par les tunnels...\n\n... Je suis dans les marécages, où est le  bunker ? Merde, merde, merde !!! Je n'arrive pas à me repérer! Ce lâche de Sakharov ne répond pas!!! Que se passe-t-il???... Il y a des zombies partout et je suis à court de munitions...</fra>
		<pln>... to współrzędne wejścia do laboratorium X-16. Znajduje się w piwnicy głównego budynku, którego przeznaczenia nie znamy. Podejrzewam, że to w nim odbywają się przeglądy techniczne podziemnych emiterów: na podstawie dokumentów od N*** wnoszę, że projekt ten ma na celu przeprowadzony na szeroką skalę rozwój broni psychotronicznej o dużym polu oddziaływania na...\n\n ...posiadamy wszystkie niezbędne dokumenty i wiemy, jak wyłączyć emiter. Schodzimy z Duchem do laboratorium. Zewsząd wyłażą zombie...\n\n... wszystko jest nie tak, Duch jest całkiem niepoczytalny, ciągle coś majaczy. Prawdopodobnie, oberwał promieniowaniem psionicznym. Wszystko rzuciłem i odchodzę przez tunele...\n\n... jestem na bagnach, gdzie jest bunkier? Cholera, cholera, cholera!!! Nie mogę określić, gdzie się znajduję! Sacharow - tchórz, nie odpowiada!!! Co się dzieje??? Dookoła zombie, a mnie kończą się naboje</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_crazy_veterans_quest">
		<rus>Бармен: "Долг дорожит своей репутацией. Поэтому они хотят всё сделать тихо. Тебе достаточно уничтожить главаря по прозвищу Счастливчик и принести его КПК в качестве доказательства".</rus>
		<eng>Barkeep: "Duty has a reputation to uphold. That's why they want this thing done quietly. All you need to do it whack the leader called Lucky Devil and bring his PDA as proof."</eng>
		<ukr>Бармен: «Долг» дуже цінує свою репутацію. Тому вони хочуть усе зробити тихо. Тобі достатньо знищити ватажка на прізвисько Щасливчик і принести його КПК як доказ.»</ukr>
		<fra>Barman: "Le Devoir a la réputation de faire observer la loi et c'est pour ça qu'ils veulent que ça se passe dans le calme. Tu dois juste neutraliser le chef, Chançard, et rapporter son PDA en guise de preuve."</fra>
		<pln>Barman: "Powinność ceni sobie swą reputację i dlatego chcą, żebyś zrobił to po cichu. Masz zabić ich przywódcę, Farciarza, i przynieść mi jego PDA jako dowód".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_dolg_community_quest">
		<rus>Для того чтобы вступить в Долг тебе необходимо получить одобрение одного из самых авторитетных бойцов группировки. А также доказать лидеру Долга, что ты достоин быть одним из них.</rus>
		<eng>To join Duty, you will need the approval of one of the most respected fighters in the group and also prove to Duty's leader that you are worthy of your place in their ranks.</eng>
		<ukr>Для того, щоб вступити до лав «Долгу», тобі необхідно отримати схвалення одного із найавторитетніших бійців угруповання. А також довести його лідерові, що ти гідний бути одним із них.</ukr>
		<fra>Pour rejoindre le Devoir, il te faudra l'approbation d'un des combattants les plus respectés du groupe et prouver à leur chef que tu en es digne.</fra>
		<pln>Żeby wstąpić do "Powinności", musisz zyskać aprobatę jednego z najbardziej szanowanych żołnierzy w grupie. Poza tym musisz udowodnić przywódcy, że zasługujesz na miejsce w ich szeregach.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_dolg_svoboda_ambush_quest">
		<rus>Бармен: "Твоя задача - уничтожение Тирана, лидера группы наёмников. Отряд наёмников прорвался на Дикую Территорию и засел на стройке. Будь осторожен, часть боевиков сидит в засадах при подходах к стройке. Как только принесёшь мне КПК Тирана, награда твоя".</rus>
		<eng>Barkeep: "Your mission is to kill Tyrant, the leader of the mercs. His crew made it into the Wild Territory and set up a base at the construction site. Be careful, some of their fighters have set up ambushes on the way to the site. Bring me Tyrant's PDA and the reward is yours."</eng>
		<ukr>Бармен: «Твоя задача - знищити Тирана, лідера групи найманців. Загін найманців прорвався на Дику територію і засів на будівництві. Будь обережний: частина бойовиків сидить у засідках на підходах до місця. Як тільки принесеш мені КПК Тирана, нагорода твоя.»</ukr>
		<fra>Barman: "Ta mission est de tuer Tyran, le chef des Mercenaires. Ses hommes sont entrés dans les Terres abandonnées et y ont installé une base sur le chantier. Fais gaffe, ses hommes sont en embuscade sur le chemin du site. Rapporte-moi le PDA de Tyran et la récompense est à toi."</fra>
		<pln>Barman: "Twoje zadanie to zabić Tyrana, przywódcę najemników. Jego ludzie dotarli do Dziczy i założyli bazę na placu budowy. Pilnuj się - część ich żołnierzy przygotowała zasadzki po drodze. Jak tylko dostanę PDA Tyrana, nagroda wędruje do ciebie".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_dolg_svoboda_leader_kill_quest">
		<rus>Генерал Воронин: "Война со Свободой близится к концу, Меченый. Ты внёс вклад в общее дело, и теперь я хочу поставить точку в этой войне. Я хочу, чтобы ты уничтожил лидера Свободы".</rus>
		<eng>General Voronin: "The war with Freedom is coming to an end, Marked One. You played your part in fighting for the cause! Now I want to finish this war. The leader of the Freedom must be disposed of."</eng>
		<ukr>Генерал Воронін: «Війна із «Волею» наближається до кінця, Мічений. Ти зробив внесок у загальну справу і тепер я хочу поставити крапку в цій війні. Я хочу, щоб ти знищив лідера «Волі».»</ukr>
		<fra>Général Voronine: "La guerre contre la Liberté touche à sa fin, le Marqué. Tu as joué ton rôle dans ce combat et maintenant, je veux en finir avec cette guerre. Je veux que tu tues le leader de la Liberté."</fra>
		<pln>Generał Woronin: "Wojna z "Wolnością" niedługo dobiegnie końca, Naznaczony. Spełniłeś swą rolę, a teraz chcę zakończyć ten konflikt! Trzeba się pozbyć przywódcy wroga".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_dolg_test_quest">
		<rus>Капитан Иванцов: "... прежде чем делать выводы, пройди маленькую проверку. Тебе надо достать архивную папку из заброшенного здания напротив. Задание проще простого, просто войди внутрь, возьми папку и принеси её мне. Что может быть проще, правильно? Когда папка будет у меня, тогда и решим, годишься ты для Долга или нет".</rus>
		<eng>Captain Ivantsov: "...before we get to the conclusions, pass an easy test. You have to get a folder from the abandoned building opposite. It's not hard, just go inside, take the folder and bring it to me. Piece of cake, right? When I have the folder we'll decide whether you're fit to join Duty or not."</eng>
		<ukr>Капітан Іванцов: «...перш ніж робити висновки, пройди маленьку перевірку. Тобі треба дістати архівну теку із покинутого будинку навпроти. Простішого завдання й бути не може. Просто увійди всередину, візьми теку і принеси її мені. Як два пальця, вірно? Коли тека буде в мене, тоді й вирішимо, підходиш ти для «Долгу» чи ні.»</ukr>
		<fra>Capitaine Ivantsov: "... avant de conclure, tu vas devoir te soumettre à une épreuve simple. Procure-toi un dossier dans le bâtiment abandonné voisin. Ce n'est pas difficile, rentre, prends le dossier et apporte-le-moi. Un jeu d'enfant, pas vrai ? Lorsque ce sera chose faite, on choisira ou non de d'intégrer au Devoir."</fra>
		<pln>Kapitan Iwancow: "...Zanim wyciągniemy jakieś wnioski, chcę żebyś zdał łatwy test. Musisz zdobyć teczkę z opuszczonego budynku naprzeciwko. Nic trudnego - wejdź do środka, zabierz teczkę i przynieś ją do mnie. Bułka z masłem, prawda? A jak dostanę teczkę, zdecydujemy, czy nadajesz się do "Powinności", czy nie".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_hunter_rifle">
		<rus>Охотник: "Верни ружьё. Потерял я его возле жилища кровососов, сейчас скину тебе координаты этого места. И поосторожней там, твари эти очень злобные".</rus>
		<eng>Hunter: "Bring back the rifle. I lost it by the place where bloodsuckers live. I'll upload you the co-ordinates. And be careful, those bastards ain't no joke."</eng>
		<ukr>Мисливець: «Поверни мені рушницю! Я її втратив біля житла кровососів… зараз скину тобі координати цього місця. І обережніше там, ці тварюки дуже злі.»</ukr>
		<fra>Chasseur: "Rapporte le fusil. Je l'ai perdu non loin de là où vivent ces sangsues. Je vais te transmettre les coordonnées. Mais fais gaffe, ces ordures sont redoutables."</fra>
		<pln>Łowca: "Przynieś mi karabin. Zgubiłem go niedaleko miejsca, w którym żyją pijawki. Prześlę ci współrzędne. Uważaj na siebie, z tymi stworami nie ma żartów".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_kill_professor">
		<rus>Волкодав: "У нас тут небольшая охота. Зажали учёных, там за вертолётом. Мои ребята потихоньку их обстреливают, чтоб не сбежали. Ты давай подключайся, сейчас будем добивать. Если поможешь, то отдам тебе скафандр научный, из сбитого вертолёта вытащили. Твоя цель - профессор Круглов, убей его, иначе сбежит он во время боя, я их породу знаю. Если убьёшь его, скафандр твой, нет - значит не судьба".</rus>
		<eng>Wolfhound: "We've got a little hunt going on here. We pinned the scientists in over there behind the chopper. My boys are putting some fire down on them from time to time to make sure they don't escape. Join in, we're about to go in and finish 'em off. If you help us I'll give you the scientists' suit... we found it in the chopper we took down. Your target is professor Kruglov. Kill him or he'll run away during the shootout, I know his type. If you kill him, the suit is yours, if you don't, you don't get jack."</eng>
		<ukr>Вовкодав: "У нас тут невелике полювання. Затисли вчених, там за вертольотом. Мої хлопці потихеньку їх обстрілюють, щоб не втекли. Ти давай підключайся, зараз будемо добивати. Якщо допоможеш, то віддам тобі скафандр науковий, зі збитого вертольота витягли. Твоя ціль - професор Круглов, вбий його, інакше втече він під час бою, я їхню породу знаю. Якщо вб'єш його, скафандр твій, ні - значить не доля".</ukr>
		<fra>Volkodav: "On a quelque chose à faire ici. On a coincé des scientifiques là, derrière l'hélico. Mes gars tirent quelques salves pour veiller à ce qu'ils ne s'enfuient pas. Viens nous rejoindre, on est sur le point d'entrer pour les liquider. Si tu nous aides, je te donnerai la combi des scientifiques... qu'on a trouvée dans l'hélico. Ta cible est le professeur Krouglov. Tue-le sinon pour ne pas qu'il tente de s'échapper, je connais ce type. Tue-le et la combinaison est à toi."</fra>
		<pln>Wilczarz: "Mamy tu niewielkie polowanie. Zapędziliśmy naukowców tam, za śmigłowiec. Moi chłopcy od czasu do czasu do nich strzelają, żeby mieć pewność, że tamci nie uciekną. Przyłącz się, właśnie planujemy ich wykończyć. Jeśli nam pomożesz, dostaniesz kombinezon naukowca... Znaleźliśmy go w śmigłowcu, który zestrzeliliśmy. Twoim celem jest profesor Krugłow. Zabij go, bo inaczej ucieknie w trakcie strzelaniny - znam takich. Jeśli go zabijesz, dostaniesz kombinezon, jeśli ci się nie uda, guzik dostaniesz".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_radar_deactivate">
		<rus>Бармен: "Защитный прототип у тебя есть, чтобы от Выжигателя прикрыться, координаты бункера я знаю. Не забудь, что прототип не сможет бесконечно защищать тебя от излучения, поэтому ты должен как можно быстрее пробиться в бункер под антеннами и отключить Выжигатель. Всё, что нам надо, это пробраться к антеннам и отключить их".</rus>
		<eng>Barkeep: "You have the protective prototype to cover yourself against the Brain Scorcher, I know the coordinates of a bunker. Don't forget that the prototype can't protect against the emission forever, so you must get to the bunker under the antennae and shut down the Scorcher. All you have to do is to get to the antennae, and switch them off."</eng>
		<ukr>Бармен: «Отже, Мічений, захисний прототип у тебе є, щоб від Випалювача прикритися. Координати бункера я знаю. Не забувай тільки, що прототип не зможе нескінченно захищати тебе від випромінювання. Ти маєш якомога швидше пробитися до того бункера під антенами і вимкнути Випалювач. Що буде далі, я не знаю... але відчуваю: воно того варте. Точно знаю лише одне: дорогу до центру Зони буде відкрито.»</ukr>
		<fra>Barman: "Tu disposes du prototype de protection pour échapper au lobotomisateur, je connais les coordonnées d'un bunker. N'oublie pas que ce prototype ne protège pas des émissions indéfiniment, rejoins le bunker sous les antennes et élimine le lobotomisateur. Allez, fonce jusqu'au antennes et neutralise-les."</fra>
		<pln>Barman: "Ty masz prototyp, który ochroni cię przed Mózgozwęglaczem, a ja znam położenie bunkra. Nie zapominaj, że prototyp hełmu nie będzie cię chronił w nieskończoność, więc musisz jak najszybciej się dostać do bunkra pod antenami i wyłączyć "Zwęglacz". Masz tylko dostać się do anten i odłączyć je".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_resque_information">
		<rus>Круглов: "Сталкер, помоги! На нас напали наёмники, половина наших погибла. Помоги нам, мы в долгу не останемся..."\n\n"... ты там осторожней, их человек пятнадцать, точно мы не знаем".</rus>
		<eng>Kruglov: "Stalker, help! We were attacked by the Mercs and half of our team is dead. Help us and you won't regret it"\n \n "...be careful, there are about fifteen of them, but we don't know for sure."</eng>
		<ukr>Круглов: «Cталкере, допоможи! На нас напали найманці, половина наших загинула. Допоможи нам, ми віддячимо!»\n \n «...обережніше там - їх, може, із п'ятнадцять буде, точно ми не знаємо…»</ukr>
		<fra>Krouglov: "Vous, stalker, aidez-nous! Les Mercenaires nous ont attaqués, ils ont tué la moitié de notre équipe. Aidez-nous, vous ne le regretterez pas"\n\n"... attention, ils sont une quinzaine... On n'est pas très sûrs"</fra>
		<pln>Krugłow: "Stalkerze, pomocy! Zostaliśmy zaatakowani przez najemników, połowa naszych ludzi już nie żyje. Pomóż nam, a nie pożałujesz..."\n \n "...Uważaj, jest ich chyba około piętnastu, ale nie mamy pewności".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_resque_information_2">
		<rus>Круглов: "Мы возвращались с Янтаря, когда нас сбили наёмники. Говорят, что им информация нужна, но я то знаю - перестреляют они нас. Выведи меня к Янтарю, и я поделюсь с тобой тем, что знаю о вашем Выжигателе мозгов, а Бармен тебе за это хорошо заплатит. Боец из меня плохой, так что тебе придётся прикрывать меня по пути".</rus>
		<eng>Kruglov: "We were returning from Yantar, when the Mercs shot us down. People say that they need information, but I know better - they'll shoot us all. Take me out to Yantar and I'll tell you what I know about your Brain Scorcher, and Barkeep will pay you well for it. I make a bad warrior, but I know the way, so I'll lead and you cover us along the way."</eng>
		<ukr>Круглов: «Ми поверталися з Янтарю, коли нас збили найманці. Кажуть, що їм лише інформація потрібна, але я знаю - вони нас перестріляють. Виведи мене до Янтарю і я поділюся із тобою тим, що знаю про так званий Випалювач Мізків, а Бармен тобі за це добре заплатить. Боєць із мене поганий, але я знаю дорогу, тому я вестиму, а ти прикривай нас дорогою.»</ukr>
		<fra>Krouglov: "On revient de Yantar où on s'est fait attaquer par les Mercenaires. Visiblement, ils auraient besoin d'informations, mais je sais qu'ils vont tenter de tous nous abattre. Conduisez-moi à Yantar; je vous dirai tout ce que je sais sur votre lobotomisateur et le Barman vous récompensera comme il se doit. Je ne suis pas un très bon combattant, mais je connais le chemin. Je vous guiderai et vous me protégerez."</fra>
		<pln>Krugłow: "Wracaliśmy z Jantaru, kiedy zestrzelili nas najemnicy. Oni mówią, że potrzebują jedynie informacji, ale ja wiem lepiej - wszystkich nas zabiją. Zabierz mnie z powrotem nad Jantar, a powiem ci wszystko, co wiem o tym twoim Mózgozwęglaczu - Barman dobrze ci za to zapłaci. Żaden ze mnie wojownik, ale znam drogę, więc poprowadzę, a ty nas będziesz osłaniać".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_bar_x16_documents">
		<rus>Бармен: "Надо пробраться к учёным и узнать, где находится лаборатория Х-16, чтобы достать недостающую часть документов".</rus>
		<eng>Barkeep: "You need to get through to the scientists and find out where Lab X16 is located to find the missing documents."</eng>
		<ukr>Бармен: «Треба пробратися до вчених і довідатися, де знаходиться лабораторія Х-16, щоб дістати відсутню решту документів.»</ukr>
		<fra>Barman: "Rejoins les scientifiques et trouve le Labo X16 pour récupérer les documents manquants."</fra>
		<pln>Barman: "Musisz przedrzeć się do naukowców i dowiedzieć się, gdzie leży laboratorium X-16, żeby znaleźć brakujące dokumenty".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_agroprom_documents">
		<rus>Просмотрел документы, которые нашли военные в бывшем НИИ. Вывод такой: этот институт в последние годы до катастрофы являлся прикрытием негосударственной лаборатории Х-18, которая, судя по всему, проводила некий таинственный эксперимент. Где находится лаборатория, документы ответа не дают. Военные про эту лабораторию тоже, судя по всему, ничего не знают. М-да... Загадки множатся... Но возможно, это нить, которая нужна торговцам. Ну что ж, теперь предстоит путь дальше на север к торговцу по прозвищу Бармен.</rus>
		<eng>I looked through the documents found at the Institute. It appears that the Institute was used as a front for an unofficial lab called X18 in the years preceding the accident. This lab hosted a number of very unusual experiments; its location is not clear from the documents and the military don't seem to know anything about it either. Well, well... the plot thickens... But perhaps, this is the starting point which the traders need. Now I have to travel further North to a trader known as Barkeep.</eng>
		<ukr>Переглянув документи, котрі знайшли військові у колишньому НДІ. Висновок такий: цей інститут в останні роки до катастрофи був прикриттям недержавної лабораторії Х-18, котра, зважаючи на все, проводила якийсь не дуже зрозумілі експерименти. Де знаходиться лабораторія - документи відповіді не дають. Військові про цю лабораторію теж, зважаючи на все, достеменно нічого не знають. Таке... таємниць дедалі більшає... Але, можливо, це вже якась нитка. Ну що ж, тепер тобі шлях далі на північ, до одного з них на прізвисько Бармен.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai consulté les documents trouvés à l'Institut. Visiblement, cet institut a servi de façade à un labo officieux appelé X18 pendant les dix années qui ont précédé l'accident. Des expériences des plus inhabituelles y 	ont été menées. Son emplacement n'est pas clair et les militaires n'ont pas l'air d'en savoir grand-chose. Eh bien... Le complot se précise... Mais c'est peut-être le point de départ dont les marchands ont besoin. Bon, maintenant, il faut que j'aille vers le nord pour rencontrer le Barman.</fra>
		<pln>Przejrzałem dokumenty znalezione w Instytucie. Wygląda na to, że w latach poprzedzających wypadek, Instytut wykorzystywano jako przykrywkę dla nieoficjalnego laboratorium zwanego "X-18". Miało w nim miejsce kilka niezwykłych eksperymentów. Z dokumentów nie wynika, gdzie dokładnie znajduje się laboratorium, wojsko też nie wydaje się niczego o nim wiedzieć. No, czyli sprawy się komplikują... Ale może to właśnie jest punkt wyjścia, którego potrzebują handlarze. Muszę teraz wyruszyć dalej na północ, do handlarza zwanego Barmanem.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_agroprom_documents_name">
		<rus>Загадочная лаборатория X-18</rus>
		<eng>Mysterious laboratory X-18</eng>
		<ukr>Загадкова лабораторія X-18</ukr>
		<fra>Infos militaires sur le X-18</fra>
		<pln>Zagadkowe laboratorium X-18</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_darklab_documents">
		<rus>М-да... Невесёлое это место - лаборатория Х-18... и её нынешние обитатели... Даже не думал, что такая нечисть может существовать на свете. Нашёл какие-то документы... Из них мало что понял - это некие технические спецификации на какие-то блоки к излучателям Кайманова. Но вот что интересно, блоки эти предназначались для другой лаборатории с кодом Х-16 и, судя по всему, тоже засекреченной.</rus>
		<eng>Hell... Lab X18 wasn't fun...and its current residents...I didn't think things like that existed. I found some documents...I didn't understand much of what was written in there except that they contained technical specifications for some components for Kaimanov emitters. What's interesting is that the parts were destined for another lab with the codename X16 and it's probably a secret one too.</eng>
		<ukr>М-да...невеселе то місце - лабораторія Х-18... а що вже її нинішні мешканці!.. Навіть не думав, що така погань може існувати на світі. Знайшов якісь документи, з яких мало що зрозумів - це якісь технічні специфікації на блоки до випромінювачів Кайманова. Але що цікаво: блоки ці призначалися для іншої лабораторії із кодом Х-16 і, зважаючи на все, теж секретної.</ukr>
		<fra>Pff... Pas drôle ce Labo X18... Ni ses occupants actuels... Je savais pas que ça existait de tels trucs. J'ai trouvé des documents... J'ai pas bien compris ce qui était écrit mais ils contenaient les spécifications techniques de certains composants des émetteurs de Kaimanov. Ce qui est intéressant, c'est que ces pièces étaient destinées à un autre labo portant le nom de code X16, un labo secret sûrement.</fra>
		<pln>Psiakrew... W laboratorium X-18 nie było zbyt przyjemnie... A jego obecni mieszkańcy... Nie sądziłem, że takie coś może istnieć. Znalazłem jakieś dokumenty... Nie rozumiem za bardzo, o co w nich chodzi - na pewno zawierają jakieś szczegóły techniczne dotyczące części do emiterów Kajmanowa. Co ciekawe, komponenty te miały dotrzeć do innego laboratorium o kryptonimie X-16, które prawdopodobnie również jest tajne.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_darklab_documents_name">
		<rus>Связи между лабораториями?</rus>
		<eng>Communication between laboratories?</eng>
		<ukr>Зв'язки між лабораторіями?</ukr>
		<fra>Des relations entre laboratoires?</fra>
		<pln>Związki między laboratoriami?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_x16_documents">
		<rus>Хм-м... Торговцы действительно многое накопали по этим лабораториям. Для Бармена не стала неожиданностью информация про излучатели и про Х-16. И теперь он уверен, что этот Выжигатель мозгов рукотворен. Он думает, что эта лаборатория Х-16 находится недалеко от лагеря учёных возле озера Янтарь. Они как раз изучают там излучение, которое похоже на действие Выжигателя. Так что сейчас мой путь лежит к учёной братии Зоны.</rus>
		<eng>Hmm...The traders have dug up a lot of information about these laboratories. Barkeep wasn't surprised to find out about the emitters and X16. Now he's convinced that this Brain Scorcher is man-made. He thinks that Lab X16 is near the scientists' camp by Lake Yantar. It's interesting that they're studying emissions that resemble the effects of the Scorcher. So now I must pay a visit to the Zone's scientific community.</eng>
		<ukr>Хм-м… Торговці справді багато що накопали стосовно цих лабораторій. Для Бармена не стало несподіванкою інформація про випромінювачі та про Х-16. Тепер він упевнений, що цей Випалювач Мізків - штучний витвір. Він думає, що ця лабораторія знаходиться неподалік табору вчених біля озера Янтар. Вони саме вивчають там випромінювання, що схоже на дію Випалювача. Тож зараз мій шлях - до вченої братії Зони.</ukr>
		<fra>Hmm... Les marchands ont trouvé des tas d'informations sur ces laboratoires. Le Barman n'était pas surpris d'apprendre pour les émetteurs et le X16. Maintenant, il est convaincu que le lobotomisateur est une création humaine. Il pense que le labo X16 se trouve près du camp des scientifiques, au lac de Yantar. C'est intéressant qu'ils étudient des émissions qui ressemblent aux effets du lobotomisateur. Il faut que je rende une petite visite aux scientifiques de la Zone.</fra>
		<pln>Hm... Handlarze zdobyli sporo informacji o tych laboratoriach. Barman nie był zaskoczony, gdy dowiedział się o emiterach i o X-16. Jest już przekonany, że ten cały "Mózgozwęglacz" to dzieło człowieka. Sądzi, że laboratorium X-16 znajduje się niedaleko obozu naukowców nad jeziorem Jantar. Co ciekawe, oni właśnie badają tam emisje o efektach zbliżonych do tych wywoływanych przez "Zwęglacz". Muszę więc teraz złożyć wizytę społeczności naukowej Zony.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_darklab_documents">
		<rus>Встретился с Барменом. Проглядев документы из НИИ, он предположил, что эта Х-18 находится в так называемой Тёмной Долине, и предлагает мне туда наведаться на предмет поиска информации и документов. Говорит, что уже посылал долговцев с заданием проникнуть в это подземелье. Но они пропали. Бармен предположил, что они попали в плен к бандитам - у них там база недалеко. А если это так, то всё, что нарыли долговцы будет у лидера бандитов, Борова. Бармен призывает к осторожности и... и явно чего-то недоговаривает про это подземелье. Ну да ладно, за работу: сначала пообщаться с Боровом, а если "разговор" удастся, то потом лезть под землю.</rus>
		<eng>I met with Barkeep. Having looked through the documents from the Institute he thinks that this X18 is in the so called Dark Valley and asked me to go there to look for information and documents. He says he sent Duty scouts to get into the underground vaults there but they disappeared. Barkeep thinks they were captured by bandits who have a base nearby. If that's true, everything those Duty guys found will be in the hands of Hog, the leader of the bandits. Barkeep told me to be careful and... clearly didn't tell me everything about these underground vaults. Oh well, time to get to work: first of all I need to go pay Hog a visit and if the "conversation" goes well, I'll explore the underground.</eng>
		<ukr>Зустрівся із Барменом. Прогледівши документи з Агропрома, він припустив, що ця Х-18 знаходиться у так званій Темній долині й пропонує мені туди навідатися задля пошуку інформації та документів. Каже, що вже надсилав розвідників-долговців із завданням проникнути до цього підземелля, але ті пропали. Бармен припустив, що вони потрапили у полон до бандитів, котрі мають поблизу базу. А якщо це так, то все, що нарили долговці, опинилося в лідера бандитів - Кабана. Бармен нагадує про обережність і... і ще явно не каже щось про те підземелля. Нехай. Час до роботи: спочатку поспілкуватися із Кабаном, а якщо «розмова» закінчиться добре, доведеться ще лізти під землю.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai rencontré le Barman. D'après les documents de l'Institut, il pense que ce X18 se trouve dans la Vallée obscure et m'a demandé d'aller y chercher des informations et des documents. Il a dit qu'il avait envoyé des éclaireurs du Devoir dans les souterrains, mais qu'ils avaient disparu. Le Barman pense qu'ils ont été enlevés par les bandits d'une base voisine. Si c'est vrai, tout ce que ces types du Devoir ont trouvé est tombé entre les mains du Ragot, le chef des bandits. Le Barman m'a demandé de faire gaffe et... ne m'a certainement pas tout dit sur les souterrains. Eh bien, au travail : d'abord, il faut que j'aille voir le Ragot et si la "conversation" se passe bien, j'explorerai les souterrains.</fra>
		<pln>Spotkałem się z Barmanem. Po przejrzeniu dokumentów z Instytutu doszedł do wniosku, że X-18 znajduje się w tzw. Dolinie Mroku i poprosił mnie, żebym się tam wybrał w poszukiwaniu informacji i dokumentów. Powiedział, że wysłał zwiadowców "Powinności" do podziemi, ale ci zniknęli. Barman uważa, że pochwycili ich bandyci, którzy mają niedaleko bazę. Jeśli to prawda, wszystko, co znaleźli goście z "Powinności", znajduje się w rękach Borowa, przywódcy bandytów. Barman nakazał mi ostrożność, ale... Ewidentnie nie powiedział mi wszystkiego o tych podziemiach. No cóż, trzeba się zabrać do roboty: najpierw muszę złożyć wizytę Borowowi, a jeśli "rozmowa" się uda, zbadam podziemia.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_darklab_documents_name">
		<rus>Предположение Бармена</rus>
		<eng>Barkeep's guess</eng>
		<ukr>Припущення Бармен</ukr>
		<fra>La conjecture du Barman</fra>
		<pln>Przypuszczenia Barmana</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gordon_diary">
		<rus>КПК Гордона</rus>
		<eng>Gordon's PDA</eng>
		<ukr>КПК Гордона</ukr>
		<fra>PDA de Gordon</fra>
		<pln>PDA Gordona</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_command_center_text">
		<rus>Доктор: "Всё что ты говорил о "Монолите" верно - это просто иллюзия, которую наводят из некой лаборатории рядом с саркофагом... судя по всему, это единственная возможность пробраться к настоящей тайне Зоны... Которую ты всегда пытался разгадать".</rus>
		<eng>Doctor: "Everything that you said about Monolith is right - it's just an illusion created by a laboratory near the Sarcophagus... judging by everything, it's the only way to penetrate to the real secret of the Zone... Which you were always trying to figure out."</eng>
		<ukr>Доктор: «Усе, що ти казав про Моноліт, правда: це просто ілюзія, котру наводять з якоїсь лабораторії поблизу Саркофага... Зважаючи на все, це єдина можливість пробратися до справжньої таємниці Зони, яку ти завжди намагався розгадати.»</ukr>
		<fra>Le Docteur: "Tout ce que tu as dit sur le Monolithe est vrai, ce n'est qu'une illusion créée par un laboratoire situé près du sarcophage... Apparemment, c'est le seul moyen de percer le véritable secret de la Zone... Que tu cherchais toujours à comprendre."</fra>
		<pln>Doktor: "Wszystko, co mówiłeś o Monolicie, to prawda. To tylko iluzja, wytwarzana przez laboratorium znajdujące się niedaleko Sarkofagu... Śmiem sądzić, że to jedyny sposób na poznanie prawdziwych tajemnic Zony... Tych, które zawsze chciałeś poznać".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_monolith_call_text">
		<rus>Я слышал зов "Монолита". Он звал меня к себе. Следует пойти к нему и получить ответы на все вопросы.</rus>
		<eng>I heard the call of the Monolith. He called me to him. Now I ought to go to him and get the answers to all my questions.</eng>
		<ukr>Я чув заклик Моноліту - він кликав мене до себе. Варто піти до нього й отримати відповіді на всі питання.</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai entendu l'appel du Monolithe. Il m'a appelé. Il va falloir que j'aille sur place si je veux obtenir les réponses à toutes mes questions.</fra>
		<pln>Słyszałem zew Monolitu. Wzywał mnie do siebie. Powinienem tam pójść i zdobyć odpowiedzi na wszystkie pytania.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_secret_lab_text">
		<rus>Доктор: "В общем так, есть декодер для открытия двери, ведущей к системе управления "Монолитом". Декодер спрятан в тайнике в Припяти. Координаты тайника и ключ к нему я тебе даю. Возьмёшь декодер, найдёшь в саркофаге нужную дверь, а там... ну а там - по обстановке".</rus>
		<eng>Doctor: "So here's the deal. There's a decoder for opening the door which leads to the system of operation of Monolith. The decoder is hidden in a secret stash in Propyat. I'm giving you the coordinates of its location and the key. You'll take the decoder, find the right door in the sarcophagus, and then...and then you'll see how it goes."</eng>
		<ukr>Доктор: «Загалом так, є декодер для відкриття дверей, котрі ведуть до системи управління Монолітом. Декодер захований у схованці на Прип'яті. Координати схованки та ключ до неї я тобі даю. Візьмеш декодер, знайдеш у Саркофагу потрібні двері, а там... там уже дій за обставинами.»</ukr>
		<fra>Le Docteur: "Voilà le marché. Il y a un décodeur pour ouvrir la porte qui mène au système opérationnel du Monolithe. Le décodeur est caché dans une planque secrète à Propyat. Je te donne ses coordonnées et la clé. Prends le décodeur, trouve la bonne porte dans le sarcophage et... et tu aviseras sur place."</fra>
		<pln>Doktor: "W zasadzie tak: istnieje dekoder, który otwiera drzwi prowadzące do systemu sterowania Monolitu. Ukryto go w schowku w Prypeci. Tu masz współrzędne schowka i klucz. Weźmiesz dekoder, znajdziesz właściwe drzwi w sarkofagu, a potem... Potem - zależnie od okoliczności".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="zones_mystery_text">
		<rus>Ты всё-таки дошёл, сталкер. А ты оказался намного сильнее, чем нам вначале казалось. Ну что ж, пришло время поговорить. Иди на сигнал, мы будем тебя ждать.</rus>
		<eng>You made it after all, stalker. You turned out to be much stronger than we initially thought. Well, the time for us to talk has come. Head towards the signal. We'll be waiting for you.</eng>
		<ukr>Ти все-таки дійшов, сталкере. А ти виявився набагато сильнішим, ніж нам видавалося спочатку. То що ж, час поговорити. Йди на сигнал, ми чекатимемо на тебе.</ukr>
		<fra>Tu as réussi, Stalker. Finalement, tu es plus coriace qu'on le croyait. Bon, il temps qu'on ait une petite discussion. Suis le signal. On t'attend.</fra>
		<pln>Jednak doszedłeś, stalkerze. Okazałeś się o wiele silniejszy, niż początkowo nam się wydawało. No cóż... Nadszedł czas, żebyśmy porozmawiali. Kieruj się w stronę sygnału. Będziemy na ciebie czekać.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_decoder_docs_conclusion">
		<rus>Тайник в Припяти</rus>
		<eng>Stash in Pripyat</eng>
		<ukr>Схованка на Прип'яті</ukr>
		<fra>Planque de Pripyat</fra>
		<pln>Schowek w Prypeci</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_decoder_docs_conclusion_txt">
		<rus>В тайнике я нашёл короткий отчёт о том, как мы вместе с Клыком проникли внутрь подземных галерей вокруг саркофага на ЧАЭС и нашли некую подозрительную дверь. Клык сказал, что к следующему разу соберёт дешифратор для электронного замка. Потом мы были вынуждены спасаться бегством. Там немерено патрулей монолитовцев. Ну что ж, готовый дешифратор я тоже нашёл в тайнике. И есть план, как найти эту дверь. При этом, как я понял, приближаться к "Монолиту" смертельно опасно - во всяком случае мы избегали прошлый раз проникать под саркофаг над разрушенным реактором. А "Монолит", судя по всему, именно там.</rus>
		<eng>The stash contained a short report on how Fang and I infiltrated the underground galleries under the station sarcophagus and found a suspicious-looking door. Fang said that he'd put together a decoder for the electronic lock for our next visit. After that we had to run for our lives. There were hordes of Monolith patrols there. Well. I also found the decoder in the stash and directions for finding the door. However, it seems that approaching the Monolith is extremely dangerous - last time we avoided going under the sarcophagus above the destroyed reactor and it seems that's where the Monolith is.</eng>
		<ukr>У схованці я знайшов короткий звіт про те, як ми разом з Кликом пробралися всередину підземних галерей навколо Саркофага на ЧАЕС і знайшли якісь підозрілі двері. Клик ще сказав, до наступного разу збере дешифратор для електронного замка. Потім ми були змушені рятуватися втечею. Там до біса патрулів «монолітівців». Що ж… готовий дешифратор я теж знайшов у схованці. Є план, як знайти ці двері. При цьому, як я зрозумів, наближатися до Моноліту смертельно небезпечно - в усякому разі, ми тоді не стали лізти під Саркофаг над зруйнованим реактором. А Моноліт, зважаючи на все, саме там.</ukr>
		<fra>La planque contenait un bref rapport sur la façon dont le Croc et moi on a infiltré les galeries souterraines sous le sarcophage de la centrale et trouvé une porte suspecte. Le Croc a dit que d'ici notre prochaine visite, il allait mettre au point un décodeur pour ouvrir le verrou électronique. Après ça, on a dû s'enfuir pour sauver notre peau. Des hordes de Monolithes patrouillaient. Bref, à la planque, j'ai aussi trouvé le décodeur et des indications pour trouver la porte. Mais le Monolithe a l'air extrêmement dangereux. La dernière fois, on s'est bien gardé d'aller sous le sarcophage, au-dessus du réacteur détruit, et apparemment, c'est là que se trouve le Monolithe.</fra>
		<pln>W schowku znalazłem krótką relację o tym, jak Kieł i ja przeszukiwaliśmy podziemne galerie wokół sarkofagu w Elektrowni i jak znaleźliśmy podejrzane drzwi. Kieł stwierdził, że przed naszą następną wyprawą w to miejsce, zbuduje dekoder do elektronicznego zamka. Potem musieliśmy się ratować ucieczką. Było tam pełno patroli Monolitu. Hmm. W schowku znalazłem również dekoder. I wskazówki, jak odnaleźć te drzwi. Jak jednak zrozumiałem, zbliżanie się do Monolitu jest śmiertelnie niebezpieczne - na wszelki wypadek ostatnim razem unikaliśmy wchodzenia do sarkofagu nad zniszczonym reaktorem. A wygląda na to, że to właśnie tam znajduje się Monolit.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seryi_info">
		<rus>Крот и компания раскопали тайник Стрелка на Агропроме, недалеко от заброшенной фабрики. Надо бы сходить и узнать что там и как, благо он приглашал присоединиться к поискам.</rus>
		<eng>Mole and Co. moused out Strelok's stash at the Agroprom, not far from the derelict factory. Why don't you go and find out what's going on there. After all, he invited us to join the search.</eng>
		<ukr>Кріт із компанією розкопали схованку Стрільця на Агропромі, неподалік від старої фабрики. Треба б сходити і довідатися, що там і як - тим більше, він запрошував приєднатися до пошуків.</ukr>
		<fra>Taupe et compagnie a déniché la cache de Strelok à l'Agroprom, non loin de l'usine pourrie. Tu pourrais aller voir ce qui s'y passe. Après tout, il nous a invités à participer aux recherches.</fra>
		<pln>Kret i spółka wywęszyli kryjówkę Striełoka na Agropromie, niedaleko opuszczonej fabryki. Trzeba by pójść i sprawdzić, co się tam dzieje, skoro był tak dobry, że zaprosił mnie na poszukiwania.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="memuars">
		<rus>Личные заметки</rus>
		<eng>Personal note</eng>
		<ukr>Особисті нотатки</ukr>
		<fra>Note personnelle</fra>
		<pln>Notatki osobiste</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_beginning">
		<rus>Кто я?</rus>
		<eng>Who am I?</eng>
		<ukr>Хто я?</ukr>
		<fra>Qui suis-je?</fra>
		<pln>Kim jestem?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_beginning_text">
		<rus>Чёрт, смутно помню какую-то машину... долго везли, и болело всё тело, потом темнота, а что до этого? А вот что было до этого, ума не приложу... бред какой-то... Теперь этот толстый мужик называет меня Меченым, видимо из-за странной татуировки на руке, плюс это непонятное и единственное задание убить некоего Стрелка на моём КПК... ещё вопрос, моё ли это КПК? Фото Стрелка - как ни напрягаю мозги, не могу вспомнить, знаю я его или нет... Чёрт! Всё это напоминает дурной сон. Вот только проснуться не получается. Что делать? Куда идти? Хуже того - кто я? Так, успокоиться, держать себя в руках! Первое. Видимо, пока придётся-таки побегать кабанчиком по заданиям этого Сидоровича... да и может всё не так плохо, прогуляюсь, приду в себя - глядишь, мозги и прояснятся.\n Главное не налажать где-нибудь, а то репутацию испорчу, потом вообще никто помогать мне не станет. Будем ковать репутацию по ходу, помогать где возможно и главное без осечек, чтобы треплом не считали.</rus>
		<eng>Damn it, it's all a haze now... I remember a car... They drove me somewhere for a long time and my whole body hurt... There was darkness... What happened before that? I've no idea... So confused... Now this fat guy calls me the Marked One, probably because of the strange tattoo on my arm, and then there's this weird mission to kill some guy called Strelok on my PDA... Is it even my PDA? Looking at Strelok's photo I'm not even sure if I knew him or not... Dammit! It's all like a bad dream you can't wake up from! What to do? Where to go? And worst of all: who am I? OK, OK, calm down, control yourself. The first thing I'll have to do is do some jobs for this Sidorovich. He claims to have saved my life after all... That shouldn't be too bad. I'll take a walk, calm down myself and perhaps my head will be clearer.\n Most importantly, don't screw up somewhere, or I'll ruin my reputation, and then no one will help me. I'll build my reputation as I go along, help where possible, and most importantly, without stray bullets, so they don't think I'm a fool.</eng>
		<ukr>Чорт… що в мене із пам'яттю? Мов у імлі… якась машина... мене довго везуть… болить усе тіло. Потім темрява… а що до неї? Не знаю... маячня якась... Тепер цей тлустий дядько називає мене Міченим - вочевидь, через дивне татуювання на моїй руці. До того ж іще це незрозуміле завдання вбити якогось Стрільця... питання, чи мій це КПК узагалі? Фото Стрільця… як не напружую мозок, не можу пригадати, знав я його чи ні... Паскудство! Усе це нагадує поганий сон, лишень прокинутися не виходить. Що робити? Куди йти? Хто я є?! Так, заспокоїтися. Тримати себе в руках. По-перше, поки таки доведеться побігати, виконуючи завдання цього Сидоровича… може, він і справді не бреше про те, що життя мені врятував... Врешті, може, все не так погано. Прогуляюся, прийду до тями - може, мізки і прочухаються.\n Головне не налажати де-небудь, а то репутацію попорчу, потім взагалі ніхто мені допомагати не буде. Будемо кувати репутацію по ходу, допомагати де можливо і головне без осічок, щоб базікалом не вважали.</ukr>
		<fra>===C'est pas vrai, tout est embrouillé... Je me souviens d'une voiture... Ils m'ont emmené quelque part, le trajet a duré un bon moment et j'avais mal partout... Il faisait nuit... Mais qu'est-ce qui s'est passé avant ça ? Je n'en ai pas la moindre idée... C'est si confus... Et maintenant, il y a ce gros qui me surnomme le Marqué, sans doute à cause du tatouage que j'ai sur le bras. Et puis il y a cet étrange message sur mon PDA qui me dit de tuer un dénommé Strelok... D'ailleurs, est-ce qu'il est à moi ce PDA ? En regardant la photo de ce Strelok, je me demande si je le connais... Bon sang ! J'ai l'impression de faire un cauchemar dont je n'arrive pas à me réveiller ! Que faire ? Où aller ? Et pire encore : qui suis-je ? OK, OK, calme-toi, contrôle-toi. La première chose à faire, c'est d'accepter des petits boulots pour ce Sidorovitch. Après tout, il dit qu'il m'a sauvé la vie... Ça ne devrait pas être si terrible. Je vais aller marcher un peu pour me calmer, ça m'aidera peut-être à y voir un peu plus clair.Главное не налажать где-нибудь, а то репутацию испорчу, потом вообще никто помогать мне не станет. Будем ковать репутацию по ходу, помогать где возможно и главное без осечек, чтобы треплом не считали.</fra>
		<pln>===Do jasnej cholery, wszystko jest jakieś zamglone... Pamiętam samochód... Wieźli mnie gdzieś bardzo długo, bolało mnie całe ciało... Później ciemność... Co się stało wcześniej? Nie mam pojęcia... Jestem tak zagubiony... Teraz ten grubas nazywa mnie Naznaczonym - pewnie przez ten dziwny tatuaż na ramieniu - a na moim PDA jest to dziwne zlecenie na zabicie jakiegoś gościa o ksywce Striełok... A może to nie mój PDA? Jak patrzę na zdjęcie Striełoka, nie wiem, czy go w ogóle znałem, czy nie... Niech to diabli! To wszystko jakiś koszmar, z którego nie mogę się obudzić! Co mam zrobić? Gdzie iść? A co gorsza: kim jestem? Okej, okej, uspokój się, panuj nad sobą. Po pierwsze muszę wykonać parę zadań dla tego Sidorowicza. Przecież twierdzi, że uratował mi życie... To nie powinno być takie złe. Przejdę się, uspokoję nerwy i powinno mi się trochę rozjaśnić w głowie.Главное не налажать где-нибудь, а то репутацию испорчу, потом вообще никто помогать мне не станет. Будем ковать репутацию по ходу, помогать где возможно и главное без осечек, чтобы треплом не считали.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_deep_raid">
		<rus>Первая дальняя вылазка</rus>
		<eng>The first deep raid</eng>
		<ukr>Перша далека вилазка</ukr>
		<fra>La première mission importante</fra>
		<pln>Pierwszy dalszy wypad</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_deep_raid_text">
		<rus>Так, отправляюсь в первую дальнюю вылазку по Зоне, в бывший НИИ Агропром, за документами военной экспедиции. Вместе с заданием услышал информацию торговца, больше похожую на легенду, о местности где-то на севере по пути к центру Зоны, где "мозги закипают". Принимая тот факт, что с головой у меня явно не всё в порядке, надо к этой теме присмотреться и народ поспрашивать. Чем чёрт не шутит, а может я там тоже бывал... Да, ещё торговец узнал информацию, что как раз Стрелок эту местность вроде бы научился проходить. И торговцы хотят узнать как. Для чего им это нужно понятно - хотят доступ к нетронутым полям артефактов получить. Ну что ж, я готов к сотрудничеству.</rus>
		<eng>So, I am going on my first deep raid into the Zone. The target is the Agroprom Research Institute. I need to recover some documents belonging to a military expedition. Apart from the mission the trader gave me some information about an area to the North, on the way to the Zone's center, where the "brains boil"... Probably more of a legend than a fact, but since there's clearly something wrong with my head I probably should take a look at it and talk to some people. You never know - maybe I've been there before... Also, the trader told me that Strelok discovered a way to get through the area and the traders want to know it. Their reasons are clear - they want to access untouched artifact fields. Well, I'm going to help them, I guess.</eng>
		<ukr>«Отже, відправляюся у першу далеку вилазку Зоною, до колишнього НДІ «Агропом» за документами військової експедиції. Разом із завданням почув інформацію Крамара, більше схожу на легенду - про місцевість десь на півночі, дорогою до центру Зони, де «мізки закипають». Беручи до уваги той факт, що із головою в мене явно не все у порядку, треба цю тему пробити і людей поспитати. Хтозна, може, я теж там бував... Так, іще. Крамар має інформацію, що саме Стрілець цю місцевість начебто б навчився проходити. І торговці хочуть довідатися, в який спосіб. Для чого їм це потрібно, річ ясна: хочуть отримати доступ до неораних полів артефактів. То що ж, я до співробітництва готовий.»</ukr>
		<fra>Cette fois, je pars pour ma première mission importante dans la Zone. La cible est l'Institut de Recherche Agroprom. Je dois y récupérer des documents militaires. Le marchand m'a aussi donné des infos sur un secteur, dans le nord, sur la route qui mène au centre de la Zone, là où le "cerveau est en ébullition"... Ce n'est sans doute qu'une légende, mais comme ma tête ne tourne pas très rond, je devrais peut-être en profiter pour aller interroger quelques personnes. On ne sait jamais, je suis peut-être déjà allé là-bas... Le marchand m'a également dit que Strelok avait trouvé un moyen d'entrer dans le secteur et les marchands aimeraient en savoir plus. Leurs motivations sont évidentes : ils veulent accéder à des champs d'artefacts intacts. Eh bien, je vais essayer de les aider.</fra>
		<pln>No to wybieram się na pierwszy poważny wypad w głąb Zony. Moim celem jest Instytut Badawczy Agroprom. Muszę zdobyć jakieś dokumenty należące do ekspedycji wojskowej. Oprócz zadania dostałem też od handlarza informacje o pewnym terenie na północ, po drodze do centrum Zony, gdzie "gotują się mózgi"... Pewnie więcej w tym legendy niż prawdy, ale skoro bez wątpienia coś jest nie tak z moją głową, chyba powinienem obejrzeć to miejsce i pogadać z ludźmi. Nigdy nie wiadomo - może kiedyś tam byłem... Handlarz powiedział mi również że Striełok odkrył sposób na przedostanie się przez ten teren, oraz że handlarze chcą ten sposób poznać. Ich pobudki są jasne - dostęp do dziewiczych pól artefaktów. No cóż, chyba im pomogę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_sherstuk_zametka">
		<rus>Прапорщик с Агропрома</rus>
		<eng>Warrant Officer at Agroprom</eng>
		<ukr>Прапорщик з Агропрома</ukr>
		<fra>===Прапорщик l'Agroprom</fra>
		<pln>===Прапорщик с Агропрома</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_sherstuk_zametka_text">
		<rus>Сидорович предупредил меня, что за документами в бывший НИИ Агропром лучше идти в светлое время суток, так как ночью в казарме отдыхает некий прапорщик, который может мне быть в последствии полезен, а спокойно поговорить с ним и вести дела можно только утром или днём, когда он уходит с базы и встаёт под опору ЛЭП, неподалёку. И, если я полезу за документами ночью, то ненароком могу зацепить коррумпированного прапорщика, тем самым, осложнив с ним дальнейшее нормальное общение.</rus>
		<eng>Sidorovich warned me that it was better to go to the Research Institute at Agroprom for the documents during daylight hours, because at night there is a warrant officer in the barracks, who could be useful later on, and I could talk with him and conduct business only in the morning or in the afternoon, when he leaves the base and stands under the power line, not far from here. If I go to get the documents at night, I may inadvertently catch the corrupt warrant officer, thus complicating further communication with him.</eng>
		<ukr>Сидорович попередив мене, що за документами в колишній НДІ Агропром краще йти у світлий час доби, так як вночі у казармі відпочиває якийсь прапорщик, який може мені бути надалі корисний, а спокійно поговорити з ним і вести справи можна тільки вранці або вдень, коли він йде з бази і встає під опору ЛЕП, неподалік. І, якщо я полізу за документами вночі, то ненароком можу зачепити корумпованого прапорщика, тим самим, ускладнивши з ним подальше нормальне спілкування.</ukr>
		<fra>===Sidorovitch предупредил меня, что за документами в бывший l'institut de recherches "Agroprom" лучше идти в светлое время суток, так как ночью в казарме отдыхает некий прапорщик, который может мне быть в последствии полезен, а спокойно поговорить с ним и вести дела можно только утром или днём, когда он уходит с базы и встаёт под опору ЛЭП, неподалёку. И, если я полезу за документами ночью, то ненароком могу зацепить коррумпированного прапорщика, тем самым, осложнив с ним дальнейшее нормальное общение.</fra>
		<pln>===Сидорович предупредил меня, что за документами в бывший НИИ Агропром лучше идти в светлое время суток, так как ночью в казарме отдыхает некий прапорщик, который может мне быть в последствии полезен, а спокойно поговорить с ним и вести дела можно только утром или днём, когда он уходит с базы и встаёт под опору ЛЭП, неподалёку. И, если я полезу за документами ночью, то ненароком могу зацепить коррумпированного прапорщика, тем самым, осложнив с ним дальнейшее нормальное общение.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_opinions">
		<rus>Первые впечатления</rus>
		<eng>First impressions</eng>
		<ukr>Перші враження</ukr>
		<fra>Premières impressions</fra>
		<pln>Pierwsze wrażenia</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_opinions_text">
		<rus>Так-так-так... Воздухом подышал, зверушек местных увидел... кстати, их я хоть и смутно, но вроде помню... местный "аттракцион" под названием аномалии опробовал... Судя по тому, что выжил, с ними тоже сталкивался, но вот голова моя вспоминать что-либо упрямо отказывается... Сидорович, хитрый жук, понял, что меня теперь использовать практически даром можно и этим хочет воспользоваться. Хотя может всё-таки поможет с поисками этого чёртового Стрелка... Потому как он - единственная нить, связывающая меня с прошлым.\n Единственное, что пока для себя вывел, что в Зоне не нужно полагаться на авось. Если собрался куда-то, то надо идти, не откладывая это в "долгий ящик", особенно, если человеку помогать подрядился. А то пока лясы точишь, человек и сгинуть может, Зона она ведь таких ошибок не прощает. Лучше уже не обещать помогать кому-то, если не уверен, что прямо сейчас сможешь. А то человек понадеется, а ты его подведёшь, потом вообще никто со мной дел иметь не захочет.</rus>
		<eng>Well, well... Got some fresh air, saw the local wildlife... Interestingly I seem to remember some of it already, but it's all in a haze... Had a chance to try the local "amusement" called anomalies... Judging by the fact that I survived I've probably come across them before, but my brain stubbornly refuses to remember... Sidorovich is one clever bastard - he knows he can use me almost for free and that's exactly what he wants to do. Still, maybe he'll help me find this bloody Strelok fella... He's my only connection with my past.\n The only thing I've learned so far is that one should never rely on luck in the Zone. If you're going somewhere, you should go without putting it off, especially if you're helping someone. Otherwise, while you're busy, the man can perish and the Zone does not forgive such mistakes. It's better not to promise to help someone if you're not sure that you can right now. Otherwise, the person will hope, and you will let him down, and then no one wants to do business with me at all.</eng>
		<ukr>«Так... Повітрям подихав, звіряток місцевих побачив - до речі, їх я хоч і мляво, а наче пам'ятаю... Місцевий атракціон під назвою «Аномалії» випробував... Судячи з того, що вижив, із ними теж стикався, але тут голова моя згадувати щось уперто відмовляється... Сидорович - хитрий жучило! Зрозумів, що мене тепер використовувати майже задарма можна і хоче з того скористатися. З іншого боку, він може усе-таки допомогти із пошуками цього чортового Стрільця... єдиної нитки, що єднає мене з минулим.»\n Єдине, що поки для себе вивів, що в Зоні не потрібно покладатися на авось. Якщо зібрався кудись, то треба йти, не відкладаючи це в "довгий ящик", особливо, якщо людині допомагати підрядився. А то поки ляси гостриш, людина і згинути може, Зона вона адже таких помилок не прощає. Краще вже не обіцяти допомагати комусь, якщо не впевнений, що прямо зараз зможеш. А то людина понадіється, а ти її підведеш, потім взагалі ніхто зі мною справ мати не захоче.</ukr>
		<fra>===Bien, bien... J'ai pris l'air, j'ai observé la faune locale... Je suis content, je commence à retrouver la mémoire, par bribes... J'ai eu l'occasion de tester "l'attraction" locale, les anomalies... Puisque j'y ai survécu, c'est que j'ai déjà dû en rencontrer par le passé, mais mon cerveau refuse obstinément de s'en souvenir... Sidorovitch est un petit malin, il sait qu'il peut m'utiliser quasiment à l’œil et c'est exactement ce qu'il compte faire. Ceci dit, il m'aidera peut-être à trouver ce satané Strelok... Il est mon seul lien avec mon passé.\n Единственное, что пока для себя вывел, что в Зоне не нужно полагаться на авось. Если собрался куда-то, то надо идти, не откладывая это в "долгий ящик", особенно, если человеку помогать подрядился. А то пока лясы точишь, человек и сгинуть может, Зона она ведь таких ошибок не прощает. Лучше уже не обещать помогать кому-то, если не уверен, что прямо сейчас сможешь. А то человек понадеется, а ты его подведёшь, потом вообще никто со мной дел иметь не захочет.</fra>
		<pln>===No, no, no... Pooddychałem świeżym powietrzem, widziałem miejscową zwierzynę... Co ciekawe, wydaje mi się, że część z nich kojarzę, ale pamiętam je jak przez mgłę... Miałem okazję zobaczyć tutejsze "atrakcje" zwane anomaliami... Wnosząc po tym, że jeszcze żyję, pewnie już przez nie kiedyś przechodziłem, ale mój mózg uparcie odmawia udzielenia mi na ten temat informacji... Sidorowicz to sprytny sukinsyn - wie, że może wykorzystywać mnie niemal za darmo i to właśnie zamierza robić. No, ale możliwe, że dzięki niemu uda mi się odnaleźć tego gościa, Striełoka... To jedyny łącznik z moją przeszłością.\n Единственное, что пока для себя вывел, что в Зоне не нужно полагаться на авось. Если собрался куда-то, то надо идти, не откладывая это в "долгий ящик", особенно, если человеку помогать подрядился. А то пока лясы точишь, человек и сгинуть может, Зона она ведь таких ошибок не прощает. Лучше уже не обещать помогать кому-то, если не уверен, что прямо сейчас сможешь. А то человек понадеется, а ты его подведёшь, потом вообще никто со мной дел иметь не захочет.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_fox_meet">
		<rus>Встреча с Лисом</rus>
		<eng>Meeting Fox</eng>
		<ukr>Зустріч із Лисом</ukr>
		<fra>Rencontre avec Renard</fra>
		<pln>Spotkanie z Lisem</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_fox_meet_text">
		<rus>Встретился с Лисом. Есть две новости, одна - плохая: о Стрелке он знает мало, другая - хорошая: я получил информацию, что его брат, Серым кличут, знает о Стрелке больше. Серый, я так понял, километрах в двух на север, где-то среди свалки радиоактивных отходов, в ангаре. Так что задача понятна - успеть с ним встретиться, пока он не перебрался в другое место.</rus>
		<eng>I met up with Fox. It's that bad news, good news scenario. The bad news is that he knows little about Strelok. The good news is that his brother called Grey knows more. It seems Grey is in a hangar about 2 kilometers North of here, in some dump full of radioactive waste. My task is clear: get there before he leaves.</eng>
		<ukr>«Зустрівся із Лисом. Є дві новини, і перша - погана: про Стрільця він знає мало. Друга - гарна: я отримав інформацію, що його брат - Сірим кличуть - знає про Стрільця більше. Сірий, я так зрозумів, сидить кілометра за два на північ, в якомусь ангарі посеред звалища радіоактивних відходів, який тут кличуть Звалищем. Отже, задача тепер така - встигнути із ним зустрітися, доки він не перебрався кудись в інше місце.»</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai rencontré Renard. Il y a une bonne et une mauvaise nouvelle. La mauvaise, c'est qu'il ne sait pratiquement rien sur Strelok. La bonne, c'est que son frère, un certain Gris, a l'air d'en savoir un peu plus. Apparemment, Gris serait dans un hangar à environ 2 kilomètres au nord d'ici, dans une décharge remplie de déchets radioactifs. Mon objectif est clair : le rejoindre avant qu'il ne s'en aille.</fra>
		<pln>Spotkałem się z Lisem. Oczywiście jest dobra i zła wiadomość. Zła wiadomość to taka, że niewiele wie o Striełoku. Dobra wiadomość to taka, że jego brat, Sieryj, wie więcej. Wygląda na to, że Sieryja znajdę w hangarze, około dwóch kilometrów na północ stąd, na jakimś wysypisku radioaktywnych odpadów. Moje zadanie jest jasne: dotrzeć tam, zanim stamtąd zniknie.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_kuznecov_meet">
		<rus>Встреча с Кузнецовым</rus>
		<eng>Meeting Kuznetsov</eng>
		<ukr>Зустріч з Кузнєцовим</ukr>
		<fra>Rencontre avec Kouznetsov</fra>
		<pln>===Spotkanie z Lisem</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_kuznecov_meet_text">
		<rus>Познакомился с майором Кузнецовым, командиром блокпоста под разрушенным мостом на Кордоне. За бутылку водки можно договориться и тебя пропустят. Причём, целый час можно ходить туда-сюда и никто из бойцов тебе слова не скажет. Но после полуночи этот номер не прокатит. Те бойцы, которые охраняют насыпь, приходят к костерку погреться и отдохнуть, а в пять утра снова уходят на свой боевой пост - охранять насыпь. Так вот в этот промежуток, с 12 ночи и до 5 утра, лучше не приближаться к блокпосту, хоть с водкой, хоть без неё.\n Ещё у Кузнецова, судя по всему, есть много заданий для меня, а также можно разжиться армейскими аптечками и патронами к калашу за водку, так что с ним лучше дружить и "пылинки с него сдувать".</rus>
		<eng>I met Major Kuznetsov, the commander of the roadblock under the destroyed bridge at Cordon. For a bottle of vodka you can make a deal and they'll let you through. Moreover, you can walk back and forth for an hour and none of the soldiers will say a word to you. But after midnight, it's not going to work. The men who guard the embankment come to the fire to warm up and have a rest, and at five in the morning they go back to their combat post - to guard the embankment. So in this interval, from 12 o'clock at night until 5 o'clock in the morning, it is better not to approach the checkpoint, with or without vodka.</eng>
		<ukr>Познайомився з майором Кузнєцовим, командиром блокпоста під зруйнованим мостом на Кордоні. За пляшку горілки можна домовитися і тебе пропустять. Причому, цілу годину можна ходити туди-сюди і ніхто з бійців тобі слова не скаже. Але після опівночі цей номер не пройде. Ті бійці, які охороняють насип, приходять до вогнища погрітися і відпочити, а о п'ятій ранку знову йдуть на свій бойовий пост - охороняти насип. Так ось у цей проміжок, з 12 ночі і до 5 ранку, краще не наближатися до блокпоста, хоч з горілкою, хоч без неї.\n Ще у Кузнєцова, судячи з усього, є багато завдань для мене, а також можна розжитися армійськими аптечками і патронами до калаша за горілку, так що з ним краще дружити і "пилинки з нього здувати".</ukr>
		<fra>===Познакомился с major Kouznetsov, командиром блокпоста под разрушенным мостом на Кордоне. За бутылку водки можно договориться и тебя пропустят. Причём, целый час можно ходить туда-сюда и никто из бойцов тебе слова не скажет. Но после полуночи этот номер не прокатит. Те бойцы, которые охраняют насыпь, приходят к костерку погреться и отдохнуть, а в пять утра снова уходят на свой боевой пост - охранять насыпь. Так вот в этот промежуток, с 12 ночи и до 5 утра, лучше не приближаться к блокпосту, хоть с водкой, хоть без неё.\n Ещё у Kouznetsov, судя по всему, есть много заданий для меня, а также можно разжиться армейскими аптечками и патронами к калашу за водку, так что с ним лучше дружить и "пылинки с него сдувать".</fra>
		<pln>===Познакомился с майором Кузнецовым, командиром блокпоста под разрушенным мостом на Кордоне. За бутылку водки можно договориться и тебя пропустят. Причём, целый час можно ходить туда-сюда и никто из бойцов тебе слова не скажет. Но после полуночи этот номер не прокатит. Те бойцы, которые охраняют насыпь, приходят к костерку погреться и отдохнуть, а в пять утра снова уходят на свой боевой пост - охранять насыпь. Так вот в этот промежуток, с 12 ночи и до 5 утра, лучше не приближаться к блокпосту, хоть с водкой, хоть без неё.\n Ещё у Кузнецова, судя по всему, есть много заданий для меня, а также можно разжиться армейскими аптечками и патронами к калашу за водку, так что с ним лучше дружить и "пылинки с него сдувать".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_monolith_off">
		<rus>Отключение "Монолита"</rus>
		<eng>Turn off the Monolith</eng>
		<ukr>Відключення Моноліту</ukr>
		<fra>Désactiver le Monolithe</fra>
		<pln>Wyłączenie Monolitu</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_monolith_off_text">
		<rus>Сети пси-установок установлены по всей Зоне. "Монолит" - это такая же пси-установка по зомбированию людей с отличием только в одном - в саркофаге не поленились создать гигантскую голограмму некоего колоссоподобного кристалла. А при приближении пси-установка явно коверкает мозги "счастливчикам", которые сумели к ней добраться. Кстати, возможно и внушает людям исполнение их желаний. Попадал ли я под действие этого гада раньше? Не знаю. Но скоро те, кто всё это придумал, будут отвечать на мои вопросы сами! Тем более, что меня даже пригласили. Ну что ж - ждите в гости, засранцы!</rus>
		<eng>I am only a step away from the people who created this damn network of psi-units all over the Zone. The Monolith is just another zombifier it seems, with the exception that someone took the care to install a hologram in the shape of a huge crystal inside the sarcophagus. When the "lucky" ones approach it, it messes up their brains. Maybe it even makes them believe that their wishes have come true, who knows? Have I been affected by this shit before? I'm not sure, but whoever is behind this will soon be answering my questions. They even invited me... Well, here I come, you bastards!</eng>
		<ukr>«Я за два кроки від творців усієї цієї маячні, себто мережі псі-установок по всій Зоні. Моноліт - це така сама псі-установка, призначена для зомбування людей. Відмінність лише в одному - у Саркофазі не полінувалися створити гігантську голограму якогось велетенського кристала. За наближення до неї установка явно перекручує мізки «щасливчикам», які зуміли до неї дістатися. До речі, можливо, вона справді вкладає їм у голову, що їхні бажання виконано. Чи трапляв я у зону дії цієї гидоти раніше? Не знаю. Але незабаром ті, хто все це придумав, відповідатимуть на мої питання - тим більше, що мене навіть запросили. То що ж, чекайте у гості, засранці!»</ukr>
		<fra>Je ne suis sur le point de trouver les gens qui ont créé ce fichu réseau d'unités psi quadrillant toute la Zone. Apparemment, le Monolithe n'est qu'un zombifieur, sauf que quelqu'un a pris soin d'installer un hologramme en forme d'immense cristal dans le sarcophage. Les "chanceux" qui s'en approchent se font ratatiner la cervelle. Ça peut même leur faire croire que leurs voeux sont exaucés, qui sait ? Est-ce que j'ai été victime de cette merde ? J'en sais rien, mais ceux qui sont derrière tout ça ne vont pas tarder à répondre à mes questions. Ils m'ont même invité... Eh bien, me voilà, bande d'enfoirés !</fra>
		<pln>Już tylko jeden krok dzieli mnie od ludzi, którzy stworzyli w całej Zonie tę cholerną sieć jednostek psionicznych. Wygląda na to, że Monolit to po prostu kolejny zombifikator, z tym że ktoś zadbał o to, żeby stworzyć w sarkofagu hologram w kształcie ogromnego kryształu. Kiedy "szczęśliwcy" zbliżają się do niego, miesza im w głowach. Może nawet dzięki temu wierzą, że ich życzenia się spełniły - kto wie? Ciekawe, czy to gówno miało już na mnie jakiś wpływ? Pewności nie mam - ale ktokolwiek za tym stoi, wkrótce odpowie mi na kilka pytań. Nawet mnie zaprosili... No, to nadchodzę, sukinsyny!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_provodnik">
		<rus>Проводник</rus>
		<eng>Guide</eng>
		<ukr>Провідник</ukr>
		<fra>Guide</fra>
		<pln>Przewodnik</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_provodnik_text">
		<rus>Получил информацию от Проводника, что Доктор сейчас боится какой-то слежки и будет находиться в старом схроне Стрелка. Ну что ж, придётся наведаться туда.</rus>
		<eng>Guide said Doctor thinks he's being followed and will stay at Strelok's old hideout. Well, I guess I'll have to pay him a visit there.</eng>
		<ukr>«Отримав інформацію від Провідника, що Доктор зараз боїться якогось стеження і знаходитиметься у старому схроні Стрільця. Добре, значить, навідаюсь туди.»</ukr>
		<fra>Guide a dit que Docteur croit être suivi et qu'il va rester dans l'ancienne planque de Strelok. Eh bien, je crois que je vais aller lui rendre une petite visite.</fra>
		<pln>Wiem od Przewodnika, że Doktor czuje się śledzony i postanowił zostać w starej kryjówce Striełoka. Wygląda na to, że muszę mu tam złożyć wizytę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_seryi_meet">
		<rus>Встреча с Серым</rus>
		<eng>Meeting Grey</eng>
		<ukr>Зустріч із Сірим</ukr>
		<fra>Rencontre avec Gris</fra>
		<pln>Spotkanie z Sieryjem</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_seryi_meet_text">
		<rus>Надежды всё быстро узнать о Стрелке рушатся. Информация Серого не более чем отсылает меня к сталкеру по прозвищу Крот, который вроде бы знает место расположения тайника группы Стрелка... Впрочем, если информация подтвердится, то тайник - это уже что-то материальное; глядишь, там найду действительно полезную информацию.</rus>
		<eng>My hopes of learning something about Strelok must be put on hold for a while longer: Grey sent me to meet a stalker called Mole, who apparently knows the location of Strelok's secret stash... Not much, but if he's right, at least I would have something... Who knows, maybe I'll learn something useful there.</eng>
		<ukr>«Надії швидко взнати усе про Стрільця немає: інформація Сірого лише відсилає мене до сталкера на прізвисько Кріт, який начебто має знати місце розташування схованки групи Стрільця... Втім, якщо дані підтвердяться, то схованка - це вже щось матеріальне. Можливо, там я знайду справді корисну інформацію.»</ukr>
		<fra>Je vais encore devoir attendre pour en savoir plus sur Strelok: Gris m'a envoyé voir un stalker surnommé Taupe qui connaîtrait l'emplacement de la planque secrète de Strelok... Si c'est le cas, je n'aurai pas perdu mon temps... Qui sait, j'y apprendrai peut-être quelque chose d'utile.</fra>
		<pln>Oddala się wizja zdobycia informacji o Striełoku - Sieryj wysłał mnie na spotkanie ze stalkerem zwanym Kretem, który wydaje się znać położenie kryjówki Striełoka... To niewiele, ale jeśli ma rację, przynajmniej coś będę miał... Kto wie - może dowiem się tam czegoś przydatnego.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_usefull_info">
		<rus>Полезная информация от торговца</rus>
		<eng>The trader's useful information</eng>
		<ukr>Корисна інформація</ukr>
		<fra>Les informations utiles du marchand</fra>
		<pln>Przydatne informacje handlarza</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_usefull_info_text">
		<rus>Хм-м... торговец не подвёл, и я ему благодарен - дал в руки нить в плане поиска Стрелка. А именно, наводку на сталкера по прозвищу Лис. Он тут рядом засветился, просит о помощи. Сидорович думает, что он знает Стрелка.</rus>
		<eng>Hmm... The trader didn't let me down and I'm grateful to him - he gave me a leg up in my search for Strelok. Apparently a stalker called Fox has shown up nearby and he's asking for help. Sidorovich thinks Fox might know Strelok.</eng>
		<ukr>«Хм-м... Крамар не підвів, за що я йому вдячний - маю в руках нитку до пошуку Стрільця. Значить, є такий сталкер, котрого кличуть Лисом… Він тут поруч засвітився, прохає про допомогу. Сидорович вважає, що Лис знає Стрільця.»</ukr>
		<fra>Hmm... Le marchand ne m'a pas laissé tomber, je lui en suis reconnaissant. Il m'a aidé dans mes recherches sur Strelok. Apparemment, un stalker dénommé Renard s'est pointé dans le coin pour demander de l'aide. Sidorovitch pense que Renard peut connaître Strelok.</fra>
		<pln>Hm... Handlarz mnie nie zawiódł i jestem mu za to wdzięczny - pomógł mi w poszukiwaniach Striełoka. Najwyraźniej stalker zwany Lisem pojawił się w okolicy i szuka pomocy. Sidorowicz sądzi, że Lis może znać Striełoka.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_wishmaster_legend">
		<rus>Легенда об Исполнителе желаний</rus>
		<eng>The legend of the wish-granting machine</eng>
		<ukr>Легенда про Виконавець Бажань</ukr>
		<fra>La légende de la machine à exaucer les voeux</fra>
		<pln>Legenda o "Spełniaczu Życzeń"</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_wishmaster_legend_text">
		<rus>Узнал легенду местную. Говорят, есть некий Исполнитель Желаний в глубинах Зоны... где находится не известно, где-то в центре Зоны. Мол, приходишь к нему, и... и жить становится легче. Хм-м... может прийти к нему и сказать: "Хочу вспомнить всё!" - и конец моим проблемам... Правда, жалко желание тратить, вдруг вспомню всё и окажется, что я гад редкостный... обидно будет... Интересно, он сколько желаний выполняет?</rus>
		<eng>A bit of the local folklore I picked up: Legend has it there is a wish-granting machine deep inside the Zone... The exact location is unknown but it's somewhere in the center. Apparently, all you need to do is get to it and... all of a sudden your life becomes much, much easier. Hmm... How about finding it and saying "I want to remember everything about my past!" Then again, I wouldn't want to waste a wish - what if I remembered everything and it turns out I am a complete bastard? Wouldn't that be a bummer. I wonder how many wishes it grants.</eng>
		<ukr>«Почув місцеву легенду. Подейкують, є такий собі Виконавець Бажань у глибинах Зони. Де саме знаходиться, невідомо - десь близько центру Зони. Мовляв, приходиш до нього, і... і, значить, жити легшає. Хм-м... може, прийти до нього, сказати «Хочу згадати усе!» - і кінець моїм проблемам... Щоправда, шкода бажання витрачати - раптом згадаю все і виявиться, що я гад рідкісний? Ото буде весело... Цікаво, скільки бажань він виконує?»</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai fait connaissance avec une partie du folklore local : selon la légende, il y aurait une machine à exaucer les voeux au coeur de la Zone... Personne ne connaît son emplacement exact, mais elle serait quelque part dans le centre. Apparemment, il suffit juste de s'en approcher et... tout à coup, la vie devient beaucoup, beaucoup plus facile. Hmm... Et si j'essayais de la trouver ? Je pourrais lui dire : "Je veux me souvenir de mon passé !" Mais ce serait dommage de gâcher un voeu... Et si, en retrouvant la mémoire, je découvrais que j'étais un enfoiré de première ? Ce serait nul. Je me demande combien de voeux elle accorde.</fra>
		<pln>A oto miejscowa legenda. Podobno w głębi Zony znajduje Spełniacz Życzeń... Nikt nie wie gdzie dokładnie, gdzieś w centrum Zony. Podobno wystarczy się do niego dotrzeć i... Wtedy życie staje się dużo, dużo łatwiejsze. Hm... może go znaleźć i powiedzieć: "Chcę sobie wszystko przypomnieć!" - wtedy koniec z moimi kłopotami... Choć z kolei szkoda marnować życzenie - co, jeśli sobie wszystko przypomnę i okaże się, że jestem kompletnym sukinsynem... Będzie wstyd... Ciekawe, ile może spełnić życzeń?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_seriy_flash_info">
		<rus>Бугай пишет Серому: "Крот и компания раскопали тайник Стрелка на Агропроме, сходи, узнай что там и как. Серый отвечает Бугаю: "Всё равно они будут идти после этого в Бар, я их лучше на Свалке подожду, на дороге".</rus>
		<eng>Bruiser writes to Grey: Mole and Co dug up Strelok's stash at the Institute. Find out what's going on. Grey to Bruiser: They'll go to the Bar afterwards anyway so I'll just wait for them on the way at the Garbage.</eng>
		<ukr>Бугай пише Сірому: «Кріт із товаришами розкопали схованку Стрільця на Агропромі - то навідайся, взнай, що там і як.» Сірий - Бугаєві: «Усе одно вони йтимуть після того на Бар. Я їх краще на Звалищі почекаю на дорозі.»</ukr>
		<fra>Cogneur écrit à Gris: Taupe et compagnie ont trouvé la planque de Strelok à l'Agroprom. Essaie de savoir ce qui se passe. Gris à Cogneur: De toute façon, en rentrant, ils iront au bar, alors je les attendrai à la Décharge.</fra>
		<pln>Bysior pisze do Sieryja: "Kret i spółka dokopali się do skrytki Striełoka na Agropromie. Dowiedz się, co się tam wyprawia".\n Sieryj odpowiada Bysiorowi: "I tak po wszystkim pójdą do Baru, lepiej na nich poczekam na Wysypisku, na drodze".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_darklab_documents_txt">
		<rus>Бармен: "По тем документам, которые ты принёс из НИИ Агропром, кое-что начинает проясняться, но данных не хватает. Есть информация о некоем Выжигателе мозгов, который преграждает путь на север, но что это такое - никому не известно. Также упоминается некая лаборатория X-18, описания сходятся с заброшенными подземными помещениям в Тёмной Долине. Что там творится - не известно, да к тому же бандиты сейчас в Тёмной Долине свою базу основали.\nКак раз недавно отправились туда несколько долговцев, пока от них никаких вестей.\nДля того чтобы проникнуть в лабораторию тебе понадобится два электронных ключа, один я тебе дам, а второй придётся забрать у Борова, лидера бандитов.\n\nИтак, тебе надо забрать второй ключ от лаборатории у Борова. Затем проникнуть в лабораторию и достать документы".\n%c[255,255,255,0]Крайне не рекомендуется отправляться в Тёмную Долину с пустыми карманами, очень желательно иметь при себе хотя бы тысяч 40-50, пригодятся.</rus>
		<eng>Barkeep: "According to the documents you brought from Agroprom, things are starting to clear up, but some data is missing. There is evidence to suggest the presence of a Brain Scorcher which blocks the road to the North, but no one knows exactly what it is. Also, there is mention of Lab X18 whose description matches that of abandoned underground structures in the Dark Valley. Its present activity is unknown and besides, bandits have now set up their base in the Dark Valley.\n Several Duty scouts went there very recently, but so far there is no news from them.\n To get inside the lab, you will need two electronic keys; I will give you one, but the second one you will have to take from Hog, the bandit leader. \n\n So, you need to take the second key to the lab from Hog, then sneak inside the lab and get the documents. \n%c[255,255,255,0]It is highly recommended to not go to the Dark Valley with empty pockets. It may be a good idea to have at least 40-50 thousand, it will come in handy.</eng>
		<ukr>Бармен: «За тими документами, котрі ти приніс з Агропрома, дещо починає прояснюватися, але даних не вистачає. Є інформація про якийсь Випалювач Мізків, що перепиняє шлях на північ, але що це воно таке - нікому не відомо. Також згадується якась лабораторія X-18… описи нагадують закинуті підземні приміщенням у Темній долині. Що там коїться, невідомо, та до того ж бандити зараз у Темній долині свою базу зробили.\n Туди якраз відправилися кілька розвідників із «Долгу», та поки від них жодних вістей.\n Для того, щоб проникнути до лабораторії, тобі знадобляться два електронних ключі. Один я тобі дам, а другий доведеться забрати в Кабана, лідера бандитів. \n\n Отже, тобі треба забрати другий ключ від лабораторії в Сікача. Потім проникнути до лабораторії й дістати документи.».\n%c[255,255,255,0]Вкрай не рекомендується відправлятися у Темну Долину з порожніми кишенями, дуже бажано мати при собі хоча би 40-50 тисяч, стануть у нагоді.</ukr>
		<fra>===Barman: "D'après les documents que tu as rapportés d'Agroprom, les choses sont plus claires, mais il manque encore des données. Il y aurait un lobotomisateur qui bloquerait la route menant au nord, mais on n'en sait pas plus. Il y est aussi question d'un Labo X18 dont la description correspond aux structures souterraines abandonnées de la Vallée obscure. Rien sur les activités qui s'y déroulent et en plus, des bandits viennent d'installer leur base dans la Vallée obscure.\n Plusieurs éclaireurs du Devoir y sont allés récemment, mais pas de nouvelles pour le moment.\n Pour t'introduire dans le labo, il va te falloir deux clés électroniques; je t'en donnerai une. Quant à la deuxième, tu devras la dérober au Ragot, le chef des bandits. \n\n Après t'être procuré cette deuxième clé, introduis-toi dans le labo et récupère les documents.</fra>
		<pln>===Barman: "Z dokumentów, które przyniosłeś z Agropromu wynika, że sytuacja zaczyna się polepszać, ale ciągle brakuje niektórych danych. Mamy dowody na obecność jakiegoś "Mózgozwęglacza", który blokuje drogę na północ - jednak nikt nie wie dokładnie, co to jest. Jest tam również wzmianka o laboratorium X18, którego opis pasuje do opisu opuszczonych podziemnych konstrukcji w Dolinie Mroku. Nie wiemy, co tam się teraz dzieje, a poza tym bandyci rozbili obóz w Dolinie Mroku.\n Całkiem niedawno wybrało się tam kilku zwiadowców "Powinności", ale jak dotąd nie dali znaku życia. \n Żeby dostać się do laboratorium, potrzeba dwóch kluczy elektronicznych - jeden dostaniesz ode mnie, ale drugi będziesz musiał zdobyć od Borowa, przywódcy bandytów. \n\n Czyli tak: musisz zabrać Borowowi drugi klucz do laboratorium, potem wkraść się do środka i zdobyć dokumenty".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_darklab_documents2_txt">
		<rus>Необходимо найти документы об исследованиях, проводившихся в лаборатории X-18. Они могут пролить свет на Выжигатель мозгов.</rus>
		<eng>It's necessary to find the documents about the researches previously done in lab X-18. They can shed some light on the "Brain Scorcher".</eng>
		<ukr>Необхідно знайти документи про дослідження, що проводилися у лабораторії X-18. Вони можуть пролити світло на Випалювач Мізків.</ukr>
		<fra>Il faut à tout prix trouver les documents relatifs aux recherches précédemment menées dans le Labo X-18. Elles nous en diront plus sur le "lobotomisateur".</fra>
		<pln>Koniecznie trzeba znaleźć dokumenty dotyczące badań przeprowadzanych w laboratorium X-18. Rozjaśnią trochę sprawę "Mózgozwęglacza".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_codedoor_1_txt">
		<rus>Путь в глубь лаборатории преграждён дверью с кодовым замком. Необходимо найти кого-то, кто знает код.</rus>
		<eng>A combination lock is blocking the way into the depths of the lab. You must find someone who knows the combination.</eng>
		<ukr>Шлях у глиб лабораторії перекрито дверима із кодовим замком. Необхідно знайти когось, хто знає код.</ukr>
		<fra>Une serrure à combinaisons bloque l'entrée aux profondeurs du laboratoire. Tu dois trouver quelqu'un qui connaît la bonne combinaison.</fra>
		<pln>Drogi w głąb laboratorium strzeże zamek szyfrowy. Musisz znaleźć kogoś, kto zna szyfr.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_codedoor_2_txt">
		<rus>Ещё одна дверь, за ней что-то есть, это факт. Необходимо отыскать код для этой двери.</rus>
		<eng>There is another door, and there certainly is something behind it. You must discover the code that opens this door.</eng>
		<ukr>Ще одні двері - і за ними щось є, це факт. Необхідно відшукати код до цих дверей.</ukr>
		<fra>Il y a une autre porte qui doit certainement cacher quelque chose. Tu dois découvrir le code qui ouvre cette porte.</fra>
		<pln>Są jeszcze inne drzwi, za którymi na pewno kryje się coś ważnego. Musisz odkryć kod, dzięki któremu je otworzysz.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document1">
		<rus>Начало эксперимента</rus>
		<eng>The beginning of the experiment</eng>
		<ukr>Початок експерименту</ukr>
		<fra>Le début de l'expérience</fra>
		<pln>Początek eksperymentu</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document2">
		<rus>Вторая стадия эксперимента</rus>
		<eng>The second stage of the experiment</eng>
		<ukr>Друга стадія експерименту</ukr>
		<fra>La seconde phase de l'expérience</fra>
		<pln>Drugi etap eksperymentu</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document3">
		<rus>Отчёт охраны</rus>
		<eng>Security report</eng>
		<ukr>Звіт охорони</ukr>
		<fra>Rapport de sécurité</fra>
		<pln>Raport ochrony</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document4">
		<rus>Нападение на персонал</rus>
		<eng>Attack on the personnel</eng>
		<ukr>Напад на персонал</ukr>
		<fra>Attaque du personnel</fra>
		<pln>Atak na personel</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_document5">
		<rus>Завершение эксперимента</rus>
		<eng>The last stage of the experiment</eng>
		<ukr>Завершення експерименту</ukr>
		<fra>La dernière phase de l'expérience</fra>
		<pln>Ostatni etap eksperymentu</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="documents_4">
		<rus>Начальник охраны: "Вчера эксперимент чуть не вышел из-под контроля. Вырвалось десятка два подопытных, разнесли в щепки две комнаты лаборатории. Хорошо хоть исследовательский персонал успел закрыться наверху. Нам было приказано зачистить помещение главной лаборатории. В результате трое из охранников пострадали от укусов. Надеюсь, что с ними всё будет нормально. Поскорее бы они закончили свои эксперименты".</rus>
		<eng>Chief of Security: Yesterday the experiment almost got out of control. Two dozen test subjects broke out and vandalised two laboratory rooms. Fortunately, the research personnel were able to lock themselves up upstairs. We were ordered to clear the main laboratory room. In the course of the operation, three guards suffered bites. Hopefully, they will be OK. I wish the experiment is soon over.</eng>
		<ukr>Начальник охорони: «Учора експеримент ледь не вийшов з-під контролю. Вирвалося приблизно два десятка піддослідних, які рознесли на друзки усе в двох приміщеннях лабораторії. Добре, що дослідницький персонал встиг зачинитися нагорі. Нам було наказано зачистити приміщення головної лабораторії, у процесі чого троє охоронців постраждали від укусів. Сподіваюся, із ними усе буде гаразд. Скоріше б вони закінчили свої експерименти.»</ukr>
		<fra>Chef de la sécurité : L'expérience d'hier s'est révélée catastrophique. Plus d'une vingtaine de cobayes se sont échappés et ont saccagé deux salles du laboratoire. Heureusement, les chercheurs ont réussi à s'enfermer à l'étage. On nous a ordonnés de nettoyer la salle principale du laboratoire. Au cours de l'opération, trois gardes ont été victimes de morsures. J'espère qu'ils vont se remettre et j'ai hâte que cette expérience se termine.</fra>
		<pln>Szef Ochrony: "Wczorajszy eksperyment niemal wymknął się spod kontroli. Ponad dwudziestu badanych wydostało się z cel i zdewastowało dwa pomieszczenia laboratoryjne. Na szczęście pracownikom prowadzącym badania udało się zamknąć ich na górze. Nakazano nam oczyścić główne pomieszczenie laboratoryjne. W trakcie działań pogryzieni zostali trzej strażnicy. Mam nadzieję, że nic im nie będzie. Chciałbym, żeby eksperyment wkrótce dobiegł końca".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="LabX18 first key">
		<rus>Код допуска 2-го уровня</rus>
		<eng>2nd level access code</eng>
		<ukr>Код допуску другого рівня</ukr>
		<fra>Code d'accès au 2e étage</fra>
		<pln>Kod dostępu na drugi poziom</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="LabX18 second key">
		<rus>Код допуска 1-го уровня</rus>
		<eng>1st level access code</eng>
		<ukr>Код допуску першого рівня</ukr>
		<fra>Code d'accès au 1er étage</fra>
		<pln>Kod dostępu na pierwszy poziom</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="LabX18_information">
		<rus>Информация из X-18</rus>
		<eng>Information from X-18</eng>
		<ukr>Інформація з X-18</ukr>
		<fra>Informations issues du X18</fra>
		<pln>Informacje z X-18</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="pass_to_1st_door">
		<rus>Отлично, коллега. Я рад, что Вы получили доступ 2-го уровня. Наконец Вы узнаете, чем занимается наша лаборатория. Ваш код доступа - 1243. Заведующий лабораторией Х-18, Калугин Пётр Ильич.</rus>
		<eng>Excellent, Colleague. I'm glad that you've received 2nd level access. At last you will find out what goes on in our laboratory. Your access code is 1243. Chief of Laboratory X-18, Piotr Ilyich Kalugin.</eng>
		<ukr>Відмінно, колего! Я радий, що Ви отримали доступ другого рівня. Нарешті Ви довідаєтеся, чим займається наша лабораторія. Ваш код доступу - 1243. Завідувач лабораторією Х-18 Калугін Петро Ілліч.</ukr>
		<fra>Parfait, cher collègue. Je suis ravi que vous ayez obtenu l'accès au 2e étage. Vous allez enfin savoir ce qui se passe dans notre laboratoire. Votre code d'accès est le 1243. Responsable du Laboratoire X-18, Piotr Ilitch Kalugin.</fra>
		<pln>Wspaniale, szanowny kolego. Cieszę się, że uzyskałeś dostęp do poziomu drugiego. Wreszcie dowiesz się, co robimy w naszym laboratorium. Twój kod dostępu to 1243. Dyrektor laboratorium X-18, Piotr Iljicz Kaługin.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="pass_to_2nd_door">
		<rus>Коллега, напоминаю, что Вы с завтрашнего дня приступаете к обслуживанию резервуаров в центральной лаборатории. Необходимо проверять их с периодичностью в два часа. Обо всём докладывать мне лично. Код к центральной лаборатории - 9524. Заведующий лабораторией Х-18, Калугин Пётр Ильич.</rus>
		<eng>Dear colleague, may I remind you that starting tomorrow you will attend to the container in the central laboratory room. You must inspect the containers every two hours. Report everything directly to me. The code to the central laboratory room is 9524. Chief of Laboratory X18, Piotr Ilyitch Kalugin.</eng>
		<ukr>Колего, нагадую, що Ви із завтрашнього дня приступаєте до обслуговування резервуарів у центральній лабораторії. Необхідно перевіряти їх із періодичністю раз на дві години. Про все доповідати мені особисто. Код до центральної лабораторії - 9524. Завідувач лабораторією Х-18 Калугін Петро Ілліч.</ukr>
		<fra>Cher collègue, Puis-je vous rappeler qu'à partir de demain, vous vous occuperez du conteneur situé dans la salle du laboratoire central. Vous devrez l'inspecter toutes les deux heures et me tenir informé de la situation. Le code d'accès à la salle du laboratoire central est le 9524. Responsable du Laboratoire X18, Piotr Ilyitch Kalugin.</fra>
		<pln>Szanowny kolego, chciałbym ci przypomnieć, że od jutra będziesz się zajmować pojemnikami w głównym pomieszczeniu laboratoryjnym. Pojemniki należy sprawdzać co dwie godziny. Raporty składaj bezpośrednio u mnie. Kod do głównego pomieszczenia laboratoryjnego to 9524. Dyrektor laboratorium X-18, Piotr Iljicz Kaługin.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_x18_dream_name">
		<rus>Странный сон</rus>
		<eng>A strange dream</eng>
		<ukr>Дивний сон</ukr>
		<fra>Un rêve bizarre</fra>
		<pln>Dziwny sen</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_x18_dream_text">
		<rus>Приснился странный сон. Громада Чернобыльской станции в полумраке. Всё выглядит мирно. Появляется одинокий человек. Я вижу его со спины на фоне станции. Начинает дуть ветер. Внезапно море крыс начинает разбегаться от станции в разные стороны. Человек стоит ко мне спиной и стреляет в крыс. Вдруг раздаётся окрик: "Стрелок!" Человек вздрагивает, застывает на мгновение и медленно начинает поворачиваться ко мне, но за миг до того, как я увидел бы его лицо, я проснулся... Что значит этот сон? Не знаю... Но мне кажется, это то, что я когда-то видел.</rus>
		<eng>I had a strange dream. The colossal Chernobyl power plant emerges in the twilight. Everything looks peaceful. A lonely man appears. I see him from behind against the background of the plant. The wind starts to blow. Suddenly hordes of rats begin to skitter away from the station in all directions. The man, with his back still turned to me, shoots at the rats. There is an abrupt scream: "Strelok!". The man shudders, freezes for a moment, then starts to turn slowly in my direction, but... just an instant before I am to get a glance at his face, I wake up. What does this dream mean? I don't know, but I think it's something I have seen before.</eng>
		<ukr>«Наснився дивний сон. Гора Чорнобильської станції, занурена у напівморок. Усе виглядає доволі мирно. З'являється самотня людина: я бачу її зі спини на тлі станції. Потім починається вітер - і море пацюків починає розбігатися від станції у різні боки. Людина так само стоїть до мене спиною і стріляє по пацюках. Раптом чути вигук: «Стрілець!». Людина здригається, застигає на мить і повільно починає обертатися, але за мить до того, як я побачив би її обличчя, прокидаюсь… Що значить той сон? Не знаю. Але мені здається, що я колись бачив це насправді.»</ukr>
		<fra>J'ai fait un rêve bizarre. La centrale nucléaire de Tchernobyl émerge dans le crépuscule. Tout est paisible. Un homme apparaît. Je le vois de dos, devant la centrale. Le vent se lève. Soudain, des hordes de rats surgissent de la centrale en courant dans toutes les directions. L'homme, toujours de dos, tire sur les rats. Puis, on entend un cri : "Strelok!". L'homme tressaille, s'immobilise un moment, puis se retourne lentement dans ma direction, mais... juste au moment où j'allais voir son visage, je me suis réveillé. Quelle est la signification de ce rêve ? Je l'ignore, mais je pense que j'ai déjà vécu cette scène.</fra>
		<pln>Miałem dziwny sen. Z półmroku wyłania się olbrzymia elektrownia w Czarnobylu. Wszystko wydaje się spokojne. Pojawia się samotnie idący człowiek. Widzę jego plecy, a w tle elektrownię. Zrywa się wiatr. Nagle z elektrowni zaczynają uciekać chmary szczurów - biegną we wszystkich kierunkach. Mężczyzna, który ciągle stoi do mnie tyłem, strzela do nich. Nagle słyszę krzyk: "Striełok!". Mężczyzna wzdryga się, na moment zastyga w bezruchu, a potem powoli zaczyna się obracać w moją stronę, ale... na sekundę przed tym jak mam zobaczyć jego twarz, budzę się. Co znaczy ten sen? Nie wiem, ale sądzę, że kiedyś już widziałem to coś.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="val_captive_help_txt">
		<rus>Долговец Пуля просит помочь ему освободить напарника, попавшего в плен к бандитам. Его должны скоро конвоировать на заброшенную фабрику.</rus>
		<eng>Duty member Bullet wants me to rescue his partner who was captured by bandits. He is soon to be escorted to the deserted factory.</eng>
		<ukr>«Долговець» Куля прохає допомогти йому звільнити напарника, який потрапив у полон до бандитів. Його мають незабаром конвоювати на стару фабрику.</ukr>
		<fra>Balle, un membre du Devoir, veut que je libère son partenaire capturé par les bandits. Il va bientôt être escorté jusqu'à l'usine désaffectée.</fra>
		<pln>Członek "Powinności", Nabój, chce, żebym uratował jego partnera schwytanego przez bandytów. Mają go wkrótce odstawić do opuszczonej fabryki.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_help_art_txt">
		<rus>Долговец: "У них есть ещё один наш, Серёга. Его держат в подвале... там здание такое... большое, недостроенное. Помоги ему, ладно? А то они его тоже..."</rus>
		<eng>Dutyer: "They have another one of ours: Serega. They're keeping him in the cellar...there's a large building there...not finished...Help him out, okay? Or they'll put an end to him too..."</eng>
		<ukr>«Долгівець»: «У них є ще один наш, Сергій. Його тримають у підвалі... там будівля така... велика, недобудована. Допоможи йому, добре? А то вони його теж…»</ukr>
		<fra>Membre du Devoir : "Ils ont encore capturé un des nôtres : Serega. Ils l'ont enfermé dans une cellule... Il y a un grand bâtiment... pas fini... Va l'aider, OK? Ou ils vont le tuer, lui aussi..."</fra>
		<pln>Członek "Powinności": "Mają kolejnego z naszych, Sieriogę. Trzymają go w piwnicy. Jest tam duży budynek... Niewykończony... Pomógłbyś mu, dobrze? Albo jego też zabiją..."</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="val_x18_conclusion">
		<rus>Лаборатория Х-18</rus>
		<eng>Lab X-18</eng>
		<ukr>Лабораторія Х-18</ukr>
		<fra>Laboratoire X-18</fra>
		<pln>Laboratorium X18</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="val_x18_conclusion_txt">
		<rus>М-да... Невесёлое это место - лаборатория Х-18... и её нынешние обитатели... Даже не думал, что такая нечисть может существовать на свете. Нашёл какие-то документы... Из них мало что понял - это некие технические спецификации на какие-то блоки к излучателям Кайманова. Но вот что интересно, блоки эти предназначались для другой лаборатории с кодом Х-16 и, судя по всему, тоже засекреченной.</rus>
		<eng>Hell... Lab X18 wasn't fun...and its current residents...I didn't think things like that existed. I found some documents...I didn't understand much of what was written in there except that they contained technical specifications for some components for Kaimanov emitters. What's interesting is that the parts were destined for another lab with the codename X16 and it's probably a secret one too.</eng>
		<ukr>Ет, невеселе це місце - лабораторія Х-18... та її нинішні мешканці. Навіть не думав, що така гидота може існувати на світі. Знайшов якісь документи... З них мало що зрозуміло - то якісь технічні специфікації на блоки до випромінювачів Кайманова. Але от що цікаво: блоки ці призначалися для іншої лабораторії із кодом Х-16 - і, зважаючи на все, теж засекреченої.</ukr>
		<fra>Bon sang... Quelle galère, ce labo X18 !... Sans compter ses occupants... Comment ça peut exister des choses pareilles ? J'ai trouvé des documents... Je n'y ai pas compris grand-chose, sauf qu'ils contenaient les spécifications techniques de composants d'émetteurs de Kaymanov. L'important, c'est que ces pièces étaient destinées à un autre labo portant le nom de code X-16, encore un labo secret, j'imagine.</fra>
		<pln>Psiakrew... W laboratorium X-18 nie było zbyt przyjemnie... A jego obecni mieszkańcy... Nie sądziłem, że takie coś może istnieć. Znalazłem jakieś dokumenty... Nie rozumiem za bardzo, o co w nich chodzi - na pewno zawierają jakieś szczegóły techniczne dotyczące części do emiterów Kajmanowa. Co ciekawe, komponenty te miały dotrzeć do innego laboratorium o kryptonimie X-16, które prawdopodobnie również jest tajne.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_find_ghost_descr">
		<rus>... узнал, что одного из группы Стрелка зовут Призраком. Хоть какая-то зацепка. Если смогу найти Призрака - смогу найти и Стрелка.</rus>
		<eng>...found our that one of Strelok's guys is called Ghost. At least some hint. If I can find Ghost - I'll be able to find Strelok too.</eng>
		<ukr>...Довідався, що одного із групи Стрільця кличуть Привидом. Хоч якась зачіпка! Якщо зможу знайти Привида, можливо, знайду і Стрільця.</ukr>
		<fra>... j'ai découvert qu'un des types de Strelok s'appelle Spectre. Enfin un indice. Si je réussis à trouver ce Spectre, je réussirai à trouver Strelok.</fra>
		<pln>... Dowiedziałem się, że jeden z grupy Striełoka nosi ksywkę Duch. To przynajmniej jakiś trop. Jeśli znajdę Ducha, będę również w stanie znaleźć Striełoka.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_journal_cache">
		<rus>Ну что ж, тайник выдал мне дальнейшее направление поиска. Я нашёл флешку, которую группа Стрелка использовала как некий бортовой журнал. Сообщений там было немного, но этого хватило, чтобы понять - в группу Стрелка, кроме него самого, входило 2-е: Призрак и Клык. Был упомянут ещё некий общий знакомый, но входил ли он в группу, неизвестно. А вот то, что он оказывал значительную помощь группе Стрелка - факт. Далее, по сообщению Призрака, Клык погиб, когда они попали в засаду. Итак, пока имеем имя одного человека, который точно знает Стрелка - это Призрак. Наконец-то что-то конкретное. А самого Стрелка, судя по переписке, действительно нужно искать в северных районах Зоны.</rus>
		<eng>Well, it seems that the stash gave me a new direction to follow. I found a flash drive with what appears to be a diary used by Strelok's group. Despite the few entries, I could work out that the group had two other members: Ghost and Fang. The diary also mentioned a "mutual friend" but I don't know whether he was part of the group. He definitely helped them out, that's for sure. According to Ghost's entry, Fang died when they were ambushed. So, at last, I have something solid: the name of someone who definitely knows Strelok - Ghost. As for Strelok himself, he may be somewhere in the North of the Zone.</eng>
		<ukr>Отже… схованка дала мені подальший напрямок пошуку. Я знайшов флешку, котру група Стрільця використовувала як такий собі бортовий журнал. Повідомлень там було небагато, але цього вистачило, щоб зрозуміти: до групи Стрільця, крім нього самого, на той момент входило ще двоє - Привид та Клик. Пригадали також якогось загального знайомого… але чи входив він до групи, невідомо. А ось те, що той невідомий надавав значну допомогу групі Стрільця - факт... Далі, за повідомленням Привида, Клик загинув, коли вони втрапили у засідку. Отже, поки маємо ім'я лише одної людини, яка точно знає Стрільця: це Привид. Хоч щось конкретне... А самого Стрільця, судячи з переписки, насправді потрібно шукати у північних районах Зони.</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, visiblement, la planque m'a mis sur une autre voie. J'ai trouvé une clé USB contenant ce qui ressemble au journal du groupe de Strelok. Malgré le peu d'entrées, j'ai réussi à comprendre que le groupe était constitué de deux autres membres: Spectre et Croc. Ce journal fait également mention à un "ami mutuel", mais je ne sais pas s'il faisait parti de ce groupe. Certes, il les a beaucoup aidés. D'après l'entrée de Spectre, Croc est mort lors de l'embuscade. Et j'ai enfin quelque chose de solide: le nom de quelqu'un qui connaît Strelok - Spectre. Quant à Strelok, il doit se trouver quelque part au nord de la zone.</fra>
		<pln>No cóż, kryjówka wskazała mi kierunek dalszych poszukiwań. Znalazłem fleszkę, którą grupa Striełoka używała w charakterze dziennika pokładowego. Nie było tam wiele wpisów, ale udało mi się dowiedzieć, że grupa liczy jeszcze dwóch członków: Ducha i Kła. W dzienniku wspomniano również o jakimś wspólnym znajomym, ale nie wiadomo, czy należy on do grupy. Na pewno im pomógł - co do tego nie ma wątpliwości. Z wpisu Ducha wynika, że Kieł zginął, gdy wpadli w zasadzkę. Więc przynajmniej jednego jestem pewien - imienia osoby, która na pewno zna Striełoka - Ducha. A jeśli chodzi o Striełoka, może się znajdować gdzieś na północy Zony.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_journal_krot">
		<rus>Ну что ж, встреча с Кротом была продуктивной. Видимо, тайник группы - это реальность, и находится он в катакомбах Агропрома... Предстоит путь в подземелья. Что ждёт меня там неизвестно... Надеюсь, этот тайник откроет и мою тайну...</rus>
		<eng>Well, meeting Mole paid off - it seems that the group's stash really exists and it's located in the catacombs below the Institute...I'll have to go there. I don't know what I'll find there...but I hope this stash helps me solve my own mystery...</eng>
		<ukr>Отже, зустріч із Кротом була продуктивною. Вочевидь, схованка групи - це реальність, і знаходиться вона у катакомбах Агропрома… Має бути шлях до підземелля. Що чекає на мене там - невідомо. Сподіваюся, ця схованка допоможе відкрити й мою таємницю.</ukr>
		<fra>Eh bien, cette rencontre avec Taupe a payé... Il semble que la planque du groupe existe bel et bien et qu'elle se trouve dans les catacombes, sous l'Agroprom... Je vais y aller. Je ne sais pas ce que j'y trouverai... Mais j'espère que cette planque m'aidera à percer mon propre mystère...</fra>
		<pln>Spotkanie z Kretem opłaciło się. Wygląda na to, że kryjówka grupy naprawdę istnieje, i że mieści się w katakumbach pod Instytutem... Będę musiał się tam wybrać. Nie wiem, co mnie tam czeka... Mam nadzieję, że ta kryjówka pomoże mi rozwikłać moją własną tajemnicę...</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_secret_info">
		<rus>Крот: "... вниз по винтовой лестнице в комнату с колоннами, идём до выхода, попадаем в большую комнату с трубами на потолке. Оттуда вниз - ко второму выходу, выходим в тоннель и поворачиваем налево. В конце будет ход направо. Там маленькая комната, пересекаем её и поворачиваем направо. Ищем на левой стене дыру, рядом надпись "Не влезай - убьёт!". Это и есть вход в тайник Стрелка..."</rus>
		<eng>Mole: "Follow the spiral staircase down into the room with the columns. Move across the room towards the exit and enter a large room with pipes in the ceiling. Go down to the second exit, enter the tunnel and turn left. There will be a right turn at the end. Go directly to the exit from the small room and turn right. Look for a hole in the left wall next to the words "Don't enter - you'll die". That's the entrance to Strelok's stash."</eng>
		<ukr>Кріт: «…униз крученими сходами до кімнати з колонами, потім до виходу. Потрапляємо до великої кімнати із трубами на стелі. Звідти вниз до другого виходу, виходимо до тунелю і повертаємо ліворуч. Наприкінці буде хід праворуч. Там маленька кімната. Перетинаємо її та повертаємо праворуч. Шукаємо на лівій стіні діру, поруч напис «Не влезай - убьёт!». Це і є вхід до схованки Стрільця.»</ukr>
		<fra>Taupe: "...suis l'escalier en spirale jusqu'à la salle abritant les colonnes. Traverse la pièce en direction de la sortie et entre dans une grande pièce avec des tuyaux au plafond. Descends vers la deuxième sortie, entre dans le tunnel et tourne à gauche. Tout au bout, tu verras un virage à droite. Cherche un trou dans le mur de gauche, à côté de l'écriteau "Ne pas entrer - Danger de mort". C'est l'entrée de la cache de Strelok."</fra>
		<pln>Kret: "...w dół kręconymi schodami do pomieszczenia z kolumnami. Idź do wyjścia i trafisz do dużego pomieszczenia z rurami na suficie. Stamtąd wzdłuż ściany - do drugiego wyjścia. Przejdź do tunelu i skręć na lewo. Na końcu będzie skręt w prawo.Tam jest niewielkie pomieszczenie - przetnij je i skręć w prawo. Na ścianie po lewej, obok słów "Nie wchodź, bo zginiesz" poszukaj dziury. To jest wejście do kryjówki Striełoka..."</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_secret_info_name">
		<rus>Тайник Стрелка</rus>
		<eng>Strelok's stash</eng>
		<ukr>Схованки Стрільця</ukr>
		<fra>Cache de Strelok</fra>
		<pln>Kryjówka Striełoka</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_military_case">
		<rus>\nОтчёт следственной группы.\nДля служебного пользования.\nРуководителю проекта "Истина"\nполковнику СБУ Кручельникову В. М.\nот руководителя группы "Поиск-2"\nкапитана Максименко Д. Ф.\n\nДокладная записка.\nНаша группа в составе 3-х следователей и отделения спецназа СБУ в период с 12.05.2012 по 25.05.2012 провела обследование помещений бывшего научно-исследовательского института земледелия на радиоактивно-заражённых почвах НИИ Агропром. Большинство оборудования и документации исчезли в неизвестном направлении, однако даже то немногое, что удалось найти, позволяет сделать следующий вывод: в период с 2005 по 2008 годы институт научными изысканиями по своему профилю не занимался. Все результаты его работ, полученные Министерством Сельского хозяйства, сфабрикованы. В то же время, получая под государственные программы финансирование, оборудование и расходные материалы, руководство НИИ в лице доктора Стрижа Петра Даниловича по липовым накладным переправляло всё это в некую лабораторию Х-18 под видом проведения экспериментов в подсобном хозяйстве института. Судя по всему, используется кодовое название, принятое у группы лиц проходящих по данному делу, поскольку лаборатории с подобными номером в нашей базе данных нет. Исходя из анализа найденных документов, можно предположить, что она находится на расстоянии часа езды на машине от НИИ Агропром. Вероятней всего речь идёт о глубоко-законспирированной лаборатории, поэтому предлагаю подключить для её поиска наш аналитический отдел. Чем занималась эта лаборатория, понять из имеющейся информации не представляется возможным. В найденных документах речь идёт о небезызвестном профессоре Чубко и упоминается некая Группа. По моему глубокому убеждению, на сей раз мы нашли конец нити, и аналитическому отделу будет чем себя занять.\nВ приложении заархивированный файл с накладными передачи расходных материалов и оборудования в некое подсобное хозяйство института и отрывок переписки Стрижа с Чубко.\nКапитан Максименко Д. Ф. 26.05.2012\n\nПрофессору Чубко В. М.\nот руководителя НИИ Агропром\nдоктора аграрных наук Стрижа П.Д.\n\nЗдравствуйте, Вадим Михайлович. Как мы и договаривались, отсылаю в наше подопытное хозяйство очередную партию расходных материалов и оборудования для проведения Ваших столь нужных для сельского хозяйства экспериментов. Финансирование экспериментов я провёл, как натурные эксперименты по темам нашего института, так что в Министерстве проблем не будет. Как идут эксперименты? Я до сих пор нахожусь под впечатлением того, что Вы показали мне в прошлый раз. Искренне Ваш, Стриж П. Д.\n\nДоктору аграрных наук Стрижу П. Д.\n\nПремного благодарен, Пётр Данилович, всё получили. Мои ребята в восторге от лазерного спектрометра, если бы не Вы, я бы долго пробивал через своих эту модель. Ну а Министерство сельского хозяйства, конечно, будет благодарно получить НАШИ результаты... рассмешили старика. Эксперименты идут свои чередом и то, что Вы видели в прошлый раз, меркнет по сравнению с тем, что мы уже достигли. Приезжайте почаще - всегда рад Вас видеть. Тем более, что на машине до "нашего подопытного хозяйства", как Вы выразились, Вам ехать час, не больше. Да, совсем забыл, у меня для Вас новость - в следующий понедельник я буду обсуждать Вашу кандидатуру с Группой. Я думаю, они меня поддержат. Искренне Ваш, Профессор Чубко В. М.\n\nПрофессору Чубко В. М.\nот руководителя НИИ Агропром\nдоктора аграрных наук Стрижа П. Д.\n\nВадим Михайлович, спасибо за доверие. Я тронут и постараюсь оправдать его. Участвовать в подобном эксперименте, я думаю, мечтает любой учёный, и, если меня примут в Группу, я буду просто счастлив. Искренне Ваш, Стриж П. Д.\nP.S. Я выбил в Министерстве два новейших японских широкополосных осциллографа и переправлю их Вам с первой же оказией. \n \n \n \n \n</rus>
		<eng>\nInvestigation report.\n For official use only.\n To SBU Colonel V.M. Kruchelnikov, head of project "TRUTH".\n From Captain D.F. Maksimenko, \ncommander of "Search-2" group.\n\n Memo.\n Our group consisting of 3 investigators and a squad of SBU Special Forces conducted searched at Agroprom, the former Research Institute for agriculture on radiation-affected soil, from 12.05.2012 to 25.05.2012. Most of the equipment and documentation was missing however the few things we were able to find allow us to come to the following conclusion: over the period from 2005 to 2008, the Institute did not conduct any research in its official fields of study. All the results of its "work" sent to the Ministry of Agriculture were falsified. Simultaneously, the Institute's management, specifically Dr. Petr Danilovich Strizh, continued to receive state financing, equipment and consumables and transferred them to a laboratory designated X18 using forged consignment notes, which provided cover for the operation by indicating that the materials were being transferred to an auxiliary facility for experiments. X18 appears to be a code name adopted by the group of people implicated in this affair, since our database contains no mention of this laboratory. Judging by the analysis of the documents we found, this laboratory is located within an hour's drive from the Institute. It is likely to be a clandestine facility so I would request the involvement of our analytical department. The lab's field of research is not clear and available documents contain no helpful information in this regard but do make references to the infamous professor Chubko and also mention some "Group". It is my firm belief that we have come to the end of the line and the analytical department will now have plenty of work to do.\n\n Attached is an archived file containing consignment notes for consumable materials and equipment transferred to some auxiliary facility and an extract from correspondence between Strizh and Chubko.\n\n Captain D.F. Maksimenko 26.05.2012\n To professor V.M. Chubko. From P.D. Strizh, Head of Agroprom Research Institute, Doctor of Agricultural Sciences. Dear Vadim Mikhailovich, As agreed, I am sending the next batch of consumable materials and equipment to our experimental facility to help you with your research, which is so essential for agriculture. I arranged financing for the experiments by describing them as pilot experiments in fields studied by the Institute so there won't be any problems with the Ministry. How are the experiments progressing? I am still deeply impressed by what you showed me last time. Sincerely yours, P.D. Strizh \n\nTo P.D. Strizh Please accept my gratitute, Petr Danilovich, we've received everything. My team is very impressed with the laser spectrometer - if not for you, it would take me eons to acquire this model through my channels. Of course the Ministry of Agriculture will be happy to receive OUR results...you really made an old man laugh with that one! The experiments are continuing normally and the things you saw last time are dwarfed by our latest achievements. You should visit more often - I am always happy to see you and it's only an hour's drive to our "experimental facility" as you called it :) I almost forgot, I have news for you: next Monday I will be discussing your candidacy with the Group. I think they will support me. Sincerely yours, professor V.M. Chubko To professor V.M. Chubko From P.D. Strizh, Head of Agroprom Research Institute, Doctor of Agricultural Sciences Dear Vadim Mikhailovich, thank you for your trust. I am touched and will do my best to prove you right. I think it is every scientist's dreams to take part in such an experiment and I will be absolutely delighted to be accepted into the Group. Sincerely yours, P.D. Strizh P.S. I managed to get two of the latest Japanese broadband oscilloscopes from the Ministry and will send them over at the earliest opportunity.</eng>
		<ukr>\nДоповідь слідчої групи.\n Для службового користування.\n Керівникові проекту «ІСТИНА»\n полковнику СБУ Кручельникову В.М.\n Від керівника групи «Пошук-2», \n капітана Максименка Д.Ф.\n\n Доповідна записка.\n Наша група у складі трьох слідчих та відділення спецназу СБУ в період із 12.05.2012 по 25.05.2012 провела обстеження приміщень колишнього науково-дослідного інституту землеробства на радіоактивно-забруднених грунтах НДІ «Агропром». Більшість устаткування та документації зникли у невідомому напрямку, однак знайдені рештки дозволяють зробити такий висновок: у період із 2005 по 2008 роки інститут науковими розробками за своїм профілем не займався. Таким чином, усі результати, отримані Міністерством сільського господарства, є сфабрикованими. У той самий час, отримуючи під державні програми грошове фінансування, устаткування та різного роду матеріали, керівництво НДІ в особі доктора Стрижа Петра Даниловича за підробленими накладними переправляло усе зазначене до т. зв. лабораторії Х-18 під виглядом проведення експериментів у підсобному господарстві інституту. Судячи з усього, Х-18 - кодова назва, прийнята серед групи осіб, причетних до цієї справи, оскільки лабораторії із подібним індексом у нашій базі даних немає. Виходячи з аналізу знайдених документів, можна припустити, що вона знаходиться на відстані години їзди машиною від НДІ «Агропром». Найвірогідніше, йдеться про глибоко законспіровану лабораторію, тому пропоную підключити для її пошуку наш аналітичний відділ. Зробити впевнений висновок щодо того, чим займалася ця лабораторія, за наявної інформації не видається можливим. У знайдених документах йдеться про відомого професора Чубка і згадується якась Група. \n\n До цієї доповіді додається файл із накладними передачі матеріалів та устаткування до підсобного господарства інституту, а також уривок переписки Стрижа із Чубком.\n\n 26.05.2012\n Професорові Чубку В.М. від керівника НДІ «Агропром» доктора аграрних наук Стрижа П.Д. Вітаю, Вадиме Михайловичу! Як ми й домовлялися, надсилаю до нашого піддослідного господарства чергову партію матеріалів та устаткування для проведення Ваших, настільки потрібних для сільського господарства експериментів. Фінансування я провів як за натурні експерименти за темами нашого інституту, тож у міністерстві проблем не має бути. Як проходять експерименти? Я дотепер знаходжуся під враженням від того, що Ви показали мені минулого разу. Щиро Ваш Стриж П.Д. Д. а. н. Стрижу П.Д. Щиро вдячний, Петре Даниловичу, одержали все. Мої хлопці у захваті від лазерного спектрометра - якби не Ви, я б іще довго пробивав через своїх цю модель. Ну, а міністерство, звісно, із радістю отримає наші результати... звеселили Ви мене, старого! Експерименти тривають, як то й належить - і те, що Ви бачили минулого разу, ніщо порівняно із тими новими вершинами, котрих ми досягли. Під’їжджайте частіше, завжди буду радий Вас бачити! Тим більше, що машині до нашого піддослідного господарства, як Ви влучно висловилися, Вам їхати лише з годину, не більше. До речі, ледь не забув! Маю для Вас новину: наступного понеділка я обговорюватиму Вашу кандидатуру із Групою. Я думаю, вони мене підтримають. Щиро Ваш, проф. Чубко В.М.\nПрофесорові Чубку В.М. від керівника НДІ «Агропром» доктора аграрних наук Стрижа П.Д. Вадиме Михайловичу, дякую за довіру. Я зворушений і намагатимуся виправдати її. Брати участь у подібному експерименті, я думаю, мріє будь-хто з учених, тож якщо мене приймуть до Групи, я буду просто щасливий. Щиро Ваш, Стриж П.Д. P.S. Я вибив у міністерстві два найкращих широкосмугових осцилографи й відправлю їх Вам за першої ж нагоди.</ukr>
		<fra>\nRapport d'Investigation\n Personnel habilité uniquement\nÀ : Col. V.M. Kruchelnikov, directeur du projet "VÉRITÉ"\n De : Cap. D.F. Maksimenko,\ncommandant du groupe "Recherche-2"\n\n Rapport\nNotre groupe composé de 3 chercheurs et d'une patrouille des Forces Spéciales a effectué une recherche à Agroprom, ancien Institut de Recherche en agriculture sur sol irradié, du 12.05.2012 au 25.05.2012. La plupart de l'équipement et des documents manquait mais le peu que nous avons réussi à trouver nous permet de conclure ceci : pendant les années 2005 à 2008, l'Institut n'a conduit aucune recherche dans ses domaines d'étude. Tous les résultats du "travail" envoyés au Ministère de l'Agriculture étaient falsifiés. Pour autant, la direction de l'Institut, en particulier Petr Danilovich Strizh, a continué à recevoir le financement et l'équipement de l'état ; qu'elle a transférés à un laboratoire nommé X18 par le biais de faux documents, masquant l'opération en indiquant que l'équipement était transféré vers un site auxiliaire pour des expériences. X18 semble être un nom de code adopté par le groupe impliqué dans cette affaire, étant donné l'absence de toute mention de ce laboratoire dans notre base de données. À en juger par l'analyse des documents trouvés, il serait situé à une heure de route de l'Institut. C'est certainement un site clandestin, par conséquant je recommande la participation du département d'analyse. Le sujet des recherches du laboratoire n'est pas clair et les documents disponibles ne contiennent aucune information à ce sujet mais font référence au tristement célèbre professeur Chubko. Il y est également fait mention d'un certain "Groupe". J'ai l'intime conviction que nous sommes proches de la fin et le département d'analyse a désormais fort à faire.\n\nCi-joint un fichier d'archive contenant des ordres de transfert de matériel vers un site auxiliaire ainsi qu'un extrait de l'échange entre Strizh et Chubko.\n\nCapitaine D.F. Maksimenko 26.05.2012\nÀ: professeur V.M. Chubko. De : P.D. Strizh, Directeur de l'Institut de Recherche Agroprom, Docteur en Agronomie. Cher Vadim Mikhailovich, Comme prévu, j'envoie le lot de matériel et d'équipement suivant vers votre site expérimental afin d'aider vos recherches, si importantes pour l'agriculture. J'ai obtenu financement pour les expériences en les faisant passer pour des expériences pilotes dans les domaines étudiés par l'Institut. Il n'y aura aucun problème avec le Ministère. Comment les expériences avancent-elles? Je suis encore impressionné par ce que j'ai vu la dernière fois. Sincèrement votre, P.D. Strizh \n\nÀ: P.D. Strizh Veuillez accepter ma gratitude, Petr Danilovich, nous avons tout reçu. Mon équipe est très impressionnée par le spectrometre laser (sans vous, il m'aurait fallu des siècles pour obtenir ce modèle moi-même). Bien évidemment, le Ministère de l'Agriculture sera heureux de recevoir NOS résultats... vous m'avez bien fait rire, vous savez ! Les expériences continuent normalement et ce que vous avez vu la dernière fois n'est rien comparé à nos dernières trouvailles. Vous devriez nous rendre visite plus souvent (j'ai toujours plaisir à vous voir et notre "site expérimental", comme vous l'appelez, n'est qu'à une heure de route). J'allais oublier, j'ai des nouvelles pour vous : lundi prochain, je parlerai de votre candidature au Groupe. Je pense qu'ils seront de mon avis. Sincèrement votre, professeur V.M. Chubko\n À : professeur V.M. Chubko De: P.D. Strizh, Directeur de l'Institut de Recherche Agroprom, Docteur en Agronomie Cher Vadim Mikhailovich, merci pour votre confiance. J'en suis touché et je ferai de mon mieux pour ne pas vous décevoir. C'est le rêve de tout scientifique de prendre part à une telle expérience et je serai ravi d'être accepté au sein du Groupe. Sincèrement votre, P.D. Strizh\n P.S. J'ai réussi à obtenir 2 des derniers oscilloscopes Japonais du Ministère que j'enverrai dès que possible.</fra>
		<pln>\nRaport grupy śledczej.\n Tylko do użytku służbowego.\n Do naczelnika projektu "PRAWDA"\npułkownika SB Ukrainy W.M. Kruczelnikowa\n Od dowódcy grupy "Poszukiwania 2"\nkapitana D.F. Maksimienki\n\n Notatka.\n W dniach od 12.05.2012 do 25.05.2012 nasza grupa, składająca się z trzech oficerów śledczych oraz oddziału sił specjalnych Służby Bezpieczeństwa, przeprowadziła przegląd pomieszczeń byłego Instytutu Naukowo-Badawczego Agroprom, zajmującego się rolnictwem na glebie skażonej promieniowaniem. Na miejscu brakowało większości sprzętu oraz dokumentacji, lecz na podstawie tego, co udało nam się odnaleźć, doszliśmy do wniosku, że w okresie od 2005 do 2008 Instytut nie prowadził żadnych badań w dziedzinach, którymi zajmował się oficjalnie. Wszystkie wyniki "prac" przesłane do Ministerstwa Rolnictwa zostały sfałszowane. Równocześnie kierownictwo Instytutu, zwłaszcza Piotr Daniłowicz Striż, nieprzerwanie było finansowane przez państwo, otrzymywało sprzęt oraz artykuły konsumpcyjne i przekazywało je do laboratorium oznaczonego jako X18. Działo się tak dzięki podrobionym listom przewozowym, które tworzyły przykrywkę dla całej operacji, podając, że materiały przewożono do obiektu pomocniczego w celu przeprowadzenia eksperymentów. X18 wydaje się być kryptonimem wybranym przez grupę osób zamieszanych w tę sprawę, gdyż nasza baza danych nie zawiera informacji na temat takiego laboratorium. Na podstawie znalezionych dokumentów szacujemy, że laboratorium znajduje się najwyżej godzinę jazdy od Instytutu. Zapewne jest to obiekt tajny, więc proszę o pomoc działu analiz. Nie mamy pewności co do obszaru badań laboratorium, gdyż w odnalezionych dokumentach nie ma informacji na ten temat, znajdują się w nich jednak wzmianki o niesławnym profesorze Czubko oraz o pewnej "Grupie". Jestem przekonany, iż nic więcej nie możemy już uczynić i że dział analiz będzie miał dużo pracy.\n\n Załączam zarchiwizowany plik z listami przewozowymi na artykuły konsumpcyjne, sprzęt przetransportowany do pewnego obiektu pomocniczego oraz fragment korespondencji między Striżem i Czubką.\n\n Kapitan D.F. Maksimienko 26.05.2012\n Do profesora W.M. Czubko.\n Od doktora nauk rolniczych P.D. Striża, Dyrektora Instytutu Badawczego Agroprom.\n Drogi Wadimie Michajłowiczu, tak jak uzgodniliśmy, przesyłam do naszego obiektu eksperymentalnego kolejną partię artykułów konsumpcyjnych oraz sprzętu. Mam nadzieję, że pomoże to panu w badaniach tak niezbędnych dla dobra rolnictwa. Zdobyłem fundusze, określając eksperymenty "pilotażowymi" w dziedzinach, w których Instytut przeprowadza badania, więc nie będzie żadnych problemów z ministerstwem. Jak postępują eksperymenty? Ciągle jestem pod wrażeniem tego, co pokazał mi pan ostatnim razem.\n Z poważaniem, P.D. Striż.\n\n Do P.D. Striż.\n Piotrze Daniłowiczu, proszę przyjąć moje podziękowania - wszystko dotarło na miejsce. Moja ekipa podziwia laserowy spektrometr - gdyby nie pańska pomoc, zdobycie tego modelu zajęłoby całe wieki. Oczywiście, że Ministerstwo Rolnictwa ucieszy się z wyników NASZYCH badań... Naprawdę ubawił pan tym staruszka! Eksperymenty idą w dobrym kierunku, a to, co widział pan ostatnio, jest niczym w porównaniu z najnowszymi osiągnięciami. Powinien pan częściej nas odwiedzać - to dla mnie zawsze ogromna przyjemność, a poza tym, podróż samochodem do naszego "obiektu eksperymentalnego" zajmuje jedynie godzinę. Niemal bym zapomniał: w przyszły poniedziałek przedyskutuję z "Grupą" pańską kandydaturę. Sądzę, że mnie poprą.\n Z poważaniem, profesor W.M. Czubko.\n\n Do profesora W.M. Czubko.\n Od P.D. Striż, Dyrektora Instytutu Badawczego Agroprom.\n Drogi Wadimie Michajłowiczu, dziękuję za zaufanie. Jestem głęboko poruszony i zrobię wszystko, żeby upewnić pana co do słuszności tej decyzji. Sądzę, że udział w takim eksperymencie jest marzeniem każdego naukowca i będę zachwycony, jeśli "Grupa" zdecyduje się przyjąć mnie do swego grona.\n Z poważaniem, P.D. Striż.\n P.S. Udało mi się wydobyć od ministerstwa dwa najnowsze japońskie oscyloskopy - przyślę je przy najbliższej okazji. \n \n \n \n \n</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_military_case_name">
		<rus>Отчёт следственной группы</rus>
		<eng>Investigation report</eng>
		<ukr>Звіт слідчої групи</ukr>
		<fra>Rapport d'enquête</fra>
		<pln>Raport ze śledztwa</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_nii_security_plan">
		<rus>На схеме отмечены патрули, караулы, вышки. На третьем этаже института расположен штаб. Там хранятся документы. Днём территория патрулируется полностью. Ночью патрулей меньше. После одиннадцати вечера происходит смена караула, в это время в главном здании почти никого нет. Если ты хочешь на базу пролезть, то через ворота не пройдёшь, реальный путь - через катакомбы.</rus>
		<eng>The chart details the patrols, sentries and guard towers. The HQ is on the third floor of the Institute. That's where the documents are kept. By day the area is infested with patrols. There are less of them at night and the guards are relieved at 11pm. There are few people in the main building at this time. If you want to get into the base, you should choose the catacombs, the gate is not an option.</eng>
		<ukr>На схемі позначено патрулі, варти, вишки. На третьому поверсі інституту - штаб, де й зберігаються документи. Територія постійно патрулюється, причому вночі патрулів менше. Після одинадцятої вечора відбувається зміна варти, тому на той момент у головній будівлі майже нікого немає. Якщо ти хочеш на базу пролізти, то через ворота не пройдеш. Реальний шлях - через катакомби.</ukr>
		<fra>La carte détaille les patrouilles, sentinelles et postes de garde. Le QG se trouve au troisième étage de l'Institut et abrite les documents. En journée, la zone grouille de patrouilles. Celles-ci sont moins nombreuses de nuit et la relève des gardes a lieu à 23h00. À cette heure là, il n'y a pas beaucoup de monde dans le bâtiment principal. Si tu veux rejoindre la base, choisis les catacombes ; la porte n'étant pas envisageable.</fra>
		<pln>Na mapie widać patrole, wartowników i wieże strażnicze. Kwatera główna znajduje się na drugim piętrze Instytutu. To tam trzymane są dokumenty. W dzień wszędzie roi się od patroli. W nocy jest ich mniej, a strażnicy zmieniani są o 23:00. Wtedy w głównym budynku jest mało ludzi. Jeśli chcesz się dostać do bazy, wybierz katakumby - brama nie wchodzi w grę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_nii_security_plan_name">
		<rus>Карта-схема охраны НИИ Агропром</rus>
		<eng>Agroprom Research Institute guard chart</eng>
		<ukr>Карта-схема охорони НДІ</ukr>
		<fra>Carte de la sécurité de l'institut de recherche "Agroprom"</fra>
		<pln>Mapa - schemat ochrony INB Agroprom</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_rats_n_soldiers_text">
		<rus>Военных донимают крысы, которые лезут из коллекторов. Провинившихся военных отправляют в коллекторы.</rus>
		<eng>The army is annoyed by rats which climb out of the collectors. They punish soldiers by sending them into the collectors.</eng>
		<ukr>Військовим дошкуляють пацюки, що лізуть із колекторів. Тих, хто у чомусь завинив, відправляють до колекторів.</ukr>
		<fra>L'armée a fort à faire avec tous les rats qui s'échappent des collecteurs. En guise de punition, les soldats sont envoyés dans ces collecteurs.</fra>
		<pln>Wojsko ma już dość szczurów wychodzących z katakumb. W ramach kary żołnierze muszą do nich wchodzić.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_case">
		<rus>Торговец: "Как только сопрёшь кейс с территории бывшего НИИ Агропром, отнесёшь его к Бармену. Он заправляет делами в сталкерском баре "100 Рентген", что на территории бывшего завода "Росток".</rus>
		<eng>Trader: "As soon as you steal the briefcase from the Institute take it to Barkeep. He runs the 100 Rads - the stalker bar. It's located on the site of the former Rostok factory."</eng>
		<ukr>Крамар: «Як тільки свиснеш кейс із території колишнього НДІ «Агропром», віднесеш його до Бармена. Він заправляє справами у сталкерському барі «100 рентген», що на території колишнього заводу «Росток».</ukr>
		<fra>Marchand : "Après avoir volé la mallette de l'institut de recherches "Agroprom", apporte-la au Barman. Il tient le bar *100*Rads, le bar des stalkers qui se trouve à l'endroit de l'ancienne usine de Rostok."</fra>
		<pln>Handlarz: "Jak już wykradniesz dokumenty z Instytutu w Agropromie, zabierz je do Barmana. To właściciel "100 Rentgenów" - baru dla stalkerów na terenie byłej fabryki "Rostok".</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="article_agr_krot_sos">
		<rus>СОС, военные режут нашего брата сталкера. Мужики, все кто меня слышат - помогите!</rus>
		<eng>SOS, the army is killing a fellow stalker! Guys, if you can hear me - help!</eng>
		<ukr>SOS, військові ріжуть нашого брата-сталкера!.. Мужики, усі, хто мене чує, - допоможіть!</ukr>
		<fra>SOS, l'armée flingue un Stalker! Les gars, si vous m'entendez, à l'aide!</fra>
		<pln>SOS, wojsko zabija braci stalkerów! Ludzie, jeśli mnie słyszycie, pomocy!</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="article_agr_krot_sos_name">
		<rus>Встреча с Кротом</rus>
		<eng>Meeting Mole</eng>
		<ukr>Зустріч із Кротом</ukr>
		<fra>Rencontre avec Taupe</fra>
		<pln>Spotkanie z Kretem</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="article_agr_krot_sos1">
		<rus>Крот: "Помогите. Сейчас убьют!"</rus>
		<eng>Mole: "Help me, I'm gonna get killed!"</eng>
		<ukr>Кріт: «Допоможіть. Зараз уб'ють!»</ukr>
		<fra>Taupe: "À l'aide, je vais y passer!"</fra>
		<pln>Kret: "Pomocy, zaraz mnie zabiją!"</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="st_operation_agroprom">
		<rus>Операция "Агропром"</rus>
		<eng>The Agroprom operation</eng>
		<ukr>Операція «Аропром»</ukr>
		<fra>Opération "Agroprom"</fra>
		<pln>Operacja "Agroprom"</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_gunslinger_flash_info">
		<rus>Получено от Призрака:\n\n"Стрелок, у меня хреновые новости. Клык погиб. Нас ждали в деревне возле складов. И ждали давно. Трое. По виду обычные нейтралы. Клык их как-то почуял. Сам знаешь, чутьё у него - что надо было. Двоих мы завалили - явно шпана, а вот третий поумней оказался - сидел с «Винторезом» метрах в 100. В общем, нету больше Клыка. Так что в следующий раз к Центру вдвоём пойдём. И вот, что ещё... у этих двоих наше описание было. Я ума не приложу, кто именно нас заказал. Хотя вообще-то многие зуб на нас имеют. Третьего я упустил. По-моему, один из наёмников. На лице сильный шрам. Глаза светлые. Постараюсь его найти.\nТакие вот дела. Будь начеку, удачи."\nПризраку\n\n"Здорова, дружище.\nОставляю тебе инфу. На связь не выхожу. Заметил слежку.\nБрат, я ушёл на север... Туда, где мы были... Постараюсь проскочить в одиночку... Извини, но ждать тебя времени нет... Потом объясню.\nА тот урод, который убил Клыка, ещё пожалеет, что на свет родился... На ремни порежу... Ты узнай пока, кто он, а я скоро вернусь - разберёмся.\nВстречаемся у нашего общего знакомого. Сам знаешь, у какого и где.\nУдачи.\nСтрелок"\n\nСтрелку\n\n"Привет. Был. Тебя не застал. Зря ты один к центру пошёл. Впрочем, дело хозяйское. У кого и где тебя искать - знаю.\nПризрак" \n \n \n \n \n</rus>
		<eng>Received from Ghost: \n \n Strelok, I have some shitty news. Fang died. They were waiting for us in the village by the warehouses, and I think they were waiting a long time. Three of them. Seems like your average neutrals. Fang sensed them somehow. You know full well he has a good sense. We ran two of the down - clearly bandits - but the third turned out smarter than his buddies. He was sitting with Vintar about 100 meters away. Anyway, there's no more Fang. So next time we'll go to the center together, just the two of us. And here's another thing: those two had our descriptions. I can't figure out who would want us killed, although actually there are quite a few who have something against us. I let the third one get away - I think it was one of the mercs. Had a big scar on his face. Hazel eyes. I'll try to find him. \n So that's the deal. Keep an eye out and good luck. \n Ghost \n \n to Ghost \n\n "Hey there buddy. \n Leaving you some info, won't try to get connected, noticed someone following me. \n Dude, I went North...There where we were...Will try to make it through solo...Sorry but had no time to wait for you...Will explain later. \n And that freak that killed Fang will be sorry he was ever born...I'll cut him to pieces...you find out who he is, and I'll be back soon - we'll have it out with him. \n We're meeting at our mutual friend's place - you know who and where :) \n Good luck. \n Strelok” \n \n To Strelok \n \n “Hey. Came. You weren’t there. You shouldn’t have gone to the center alone. But no big deal. I know where and with whom to find you :) \n Ghost” \n \n \n \n</eng>
		<ukr>Отримано від Привида: \n \n «Стрільцю, в мене паскудні новини. Клик загинув. Нас чекали у селищі біля складів - і, я думаю, чекали давно. Троє, з вигляду звичайні нейтрали. Клик їх якимсь чином вчув. Сам знаєш, чуття в нього що треба. Двох ми завалили - явно шпана, а от третій розумніший був: засів із гвинтарем у сотні метрів від них... Коротше, немає більше Клика. Значить, наступного разу до центру вдвох підемо. Іще... в цих двох наш опис був. Поки що не дотумкаю, хто саме нас замовив. Хоча, звісно, на нас багато хто має зуб… Так цього третього я просрав. Думаю, він був із найманців. На обличчі помітний шрам. Очі світлі. Спробую його знайти. \n Такі, значить, справи... Будь напоготові - і хай щастить. \n Привид \n \n Привидові \n \n «Добридень, друзяко. \n Лишаю тобі інфу. На зв'язок не виходжу: помітив стеження. \n Я пішов на північ - туди, де ми були... Спробую проскочити сам... Вибач, але чекати на тебе немає часу... Потім поясню. \n А той виродок, який убив Клика, ще пошкодує, що на світ народився - на шматки поріжу... Ти довідайся поки, хто він, а я незабаром повернуся - розберемося. \n Зустрічаємося в нашого загального знайомого. Сам знаєш, у якого й де.:) \n Щасти. \n Стрілець» \n \n Стрільцеві. \n \n «Привіт. Був. Тебе не застав. Даремно ти один до центру пішов… утім, ти вже не маленький хлопцик. У кого і де тебе шукати - знаю.\n Привид»</ukr>
		<fra>===Message de Spectre:\n\nStrelok, j'ai une mauvaise nouvelle. Croc est mort. Ils nous attendaient au village, près des entrepôts, et je crois qu'ils étaient là depuis un bout de temps. Ils étaient trois. Ils ressemblaient à des neutres. Croc avaient senti leur présence. Il avait un sixième sens. On en a eu deux (sûrement des bandits), mais le troisième était plus malin que les autres. Il nous visait avec un Vintar BC à une centaine de mètres de là. Bref, Croc n'est plus là. La prochaine fois qu'on ira dans le centre, on ne sera que tous les deux. Autre chose: ces deux bandits avaient nos descriptions. J'ignore qui veut nous tuer. Ceci dit, il y a un paquet de gens qui ont de quoi nous en vouloir. J'ai laissé le troisième s'enfuir - je crois que c'était un mercenaire. Il avait une grande balafre sur le visage et des yeux noisette. Je vais essayer de le retrouver.\n Voilà toute l'histoire. Sois vigilant et bonne chance.\nSpectre\n\nÀ Spectre\n\nSalut, mon pote.\n Je te laisse des infos, n'essaie pas de me contacter, je crois que quelqu'un me suit.\n</fra>
		<pln>Od Ducha: \n \n Striełok, mam gówniane wieści. Kieł nie żyje. Czekali na nas we wsi przy magazynach. Trzech gości - wydawali się być tam już jakiś czas... Wyglądali na neutralnych. Kieł ich jakoś wyczuł - wiesz jakie miewał przeczucia. Zdjęliśmy dwóch, zwykłych oprychów, ale trzeci był sprytny. Czekał około 100 metrów dalej z wintarem. I to był koniec Kła. Następnym razem do centrum będziemy się mogli wybrać tylko we dwóch. I jeszcze jedno: tych dwóch miało nasze rysopisy. Nie mam pojęcia, kto mógł zlecić nasze zabójstwo. Choć w sumie jest sporo ludzi, którym byłoby to na rękę. Dałem temu trzeciemu uciec. Sądzę, że to jeden z najemników. Miał na twarzy sporą bliznę, orzechowe oczy. Postaram się go znaleźć. \n To chyba na tyle. Bądź ostrożny i powodzenia. \n Duch \n \n Do Ducha \n \n "Hej! \n Zostawiam ci trochę informacji. Nie mogę teraz się kontaktować - jestem śledzony. \n Człowieku, jestem na północy... Tam, gdzie byliśmy wcześniej... Spróbuję poradzić sobie sam... Przepraszam, ale nie mogę na ciebie czekać... Później wyjaśnię. \n Ten sukinsyn, który zabił Kła, pożałuje, że się w ogóle urodził... Potnę go na kawałki... Dowiedz się tylko, kim jest, niedługo wrócę, to wyrównamy z nim rachunki. \n Spotkajmy się u naszego wspólnego znajomego. Znasz miejsce i osobę :)  \n Powodzenia. \n Striełok " \n \n Do Striełoka \n \n "Cześć. Byłem tam, ale ciebie nie było. Nie powinieneś był iść do centrum samemu. Zresztą nieważne. Taa, wiem, gdzie i u kogo cię znaleźć :) \n Duch" \n \n \n \n \n</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_task_0_art">
		<rus>Доктор: "Когда мы виделись последний раз, ты оставил мне ключ от тайника в Припяти и схему, как его найти... я сумел их сохранить... наёмники не нашли... Держи... Возможно, там что-то найдёшь... А ещё ты бормотал постоянно, что с Монолитом какой-то подвох... Это точно..."</rus>
		<eng>Doctor: When we last met, you left me the key from the secret stash at Pripyat and the diagram which showed how to find it...I managed to save them...the Mercs didn't find them...Here...Maybe you'll find something else there....And also you kept on mumbling that there was something shady with Monolith...That's for sure...</eng>
		<ukr>Доктор: "Коли ми бачилися востаннє, ти залишив мені ключ від схованки в Прип'яті і схему, як її знайти... я зумів їх зберегти... найманці не знайшли... Тримай... Можливо, там щось знайдеш... А ще ти бурмотів постійно, що з Монолітом якийсь підступ... Це точно..."</ukr>
		<fra>Le Docteur: La dernière fois qu'on s'est rencontrés, tu m'as donné la clé d'une planque secrète située à Pripyat ainsi qu'un plan pour s'y rendre... J'y suis arrivé... Mais pas les Mercenaires... Tu y trouveras peut-être quelque chose... Tu n'arrêtais pas de dire que quelque chose clochait avec le Monolithe... Ça, c'est sûr...</fra>
		<pln>Doktor: "Podczas naszego ostatniego spotkania zostawiłeś mi klucz do schowka w Prypeci oraz plan pokazujący, jak tam trafić... Udało mi się je zachować... Najemnicy ich nie znaleźli... Proszę, weź je... Może coś jeszcze tam znajdziesz... Poza tym cały czas mamrotałeś, że w Monolicie, w tym kamieniu, tkwi jakiś podstęp... Co do tego nie ma wątpliwości..."</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_military_task">
		<rus>Операция "Монолит"</rus>
		<eng>Operation Monolith</eng>
		<ukr>Операція «Моноліт»</ukr>
		<fra>Opération Monolithe</fra>
		<pln>Operacja "Monolit"</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_military_task_head">
		<rus>Обстановка</rus>
		<eng>Situation</eng>
		<ukr>Обстановка</ukr>
		<fra>Situation</fra>
		<pln>Sytuacja</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_soldier_info">
		<rus>План действий военных\n\n Личный состав:\n Командир операции: позывной «Квартет»\n Семь десантно-штурмовых отрядов: «Сапсан», «Коршун», «Ястреб», «Пустельга», «Сокол», «Гриф», «Лунь».\n Снайперский расчёт: «Сова»\n Поддержка:\n Воздух: «018» «030» «031» «048» «049» «051» «052» «064» «065» «097» «098»\n Земля: «Броненосец-1» «Броненосец-2» «Броненосец-3»\n Обстановка: Возможно сильное сопротивление в районе моста(23,45), ворот(26,78), дорога вдоль главного корпуса станции(12,23-53,76). Вероятно использование противником тяжёлого оружия.\n Ожидаемая численность противника 70-100. Наличие бронетехники - нет.\n Возможно тяжёлое снайперское прикрытие со стороны врага.\n Погода: Видимость - 700, возможно наличие ранее неизвестных аномалии.\n \n \n \n \n</rus>
		<eng>Military action plan\n\n Personnel:\n Operation Commander: callsign Quartet\n Seven air assault units: Sapsan, Milvus, Yastreb, Pustelga, Sokol, Grif, Lun. \n Sniper team: Sova\n Support:\n Air: «018» «030» «031» «048» «049» «051» «052» «064» «065» «097» «098»\n Ground: Armadillo 1, Armadillo 2, Armadillo 3\n Situation: Possible strong resistance in the vicinity of the bridge (23,45), gate (26,78) and the road along the main building of the station (12,23-53,76). The enemy is likely to deploy heavy weaponry. \n Expected number of enemy personnel: 70-100. Armored vehicles: none.\n Possible heavy sniper cover from the enemy.\n Weather conditions: Visibility - 700, possible previously unencountered anomalies.</eng>
		<ukr>План дій військових\n\n Особовий склад:\n Командир операції: позивний «Квартет»\n Сім десантно-штурмових загонів: «Сапсан», «Шуліка», «Яструб», «Боривітер», «Сокіл», «Гриф», «Лунь».\n Снайперська група: «Сова»\n Підтримка:\n Повітря: «018» «030» «031» «048» «049» «051» «052» «064» «065» «097» «098»\n Земля: «Броненосець-1» «Броненосець-2» «Броненосець-3»\n Обстановка: Можливий сильний опір у районі мосту (23,45), воріт (26,78), дорога уздовж головного корпусу станції (12,23-53,76). Очікується застосування ворогом важкої зброї.\n Оцінювана чисельність супротивника: 70-100. Наявність бронетехніки: немає.\n Можливе сильне снайперське прикриття з боку ворога.\n Погода: Видимість - 700, можлива наявність раніше невідомих аномалій.</ukr>
		<fra>Plan d'action militaire\n\n Personnel:\nCommandant de l'opération : indicatif Quartet\n Sept unités d'assaut aérien : Pèlerin, Milan, Lanier, Crécerelle, Faucon, Vautour, Busard.\nÉquipe de snipers: Chouette\n Appui:\nAir: «018» «030» «031» «048» «049» «051» «052» «064» «065» «097» «098»\nSol: Armadillo 1, Armadillo 2, Armadillo 3\n Situation : Grande résistance possible aux abords du pont (23,45), de la porte (26,78) et de la route menant au bâtiment principal de la centrale (12,23-53,76). Il est probable que l'ennemi y déploie des armes lourdes.\nPersonnel ennemi attendu: 70-100. Véhicules blindés: aucun.\nGrosse couverture de snipers possible de la part de l'ennemi.\nConditions météo: Visibilité - 700 m, possibilités de nouvelles anomalies.</fra>
		<pln>Plan działań wojskowych\n\n Personel:\n Dowódca Operacji: sygnał wywoławczy "Kwartet"\n Siedem oddziałów desantowo-szturmowych: "Krogulec", "Orzeł", "Jastrząb", "Pustułka", "Sokół", "Gryf", "Błotniak". \n Drużyna snajperska: "Sowa"\n Wsparcie:\n Powietrze: «018» «030» «031» «048» «049» «051» «052» «064» «065» «097» «098»\n Ziemia: "Pancernik 1", "Pancernik 2", "Pancernik 3"\n Sytuacja: Możliwy zacięty opór w okolicy mostu (23,45), bramy (26,78) i drogi biegnącej wzdłuż głównego budynku elektrowni (12,23-53,76). Wróg prawdopodobnie rozmieścił broń ciężką. \n Szacowana liczebność personelu wroga: 70-100. Pojazdy opancerzone: brak.\n Możliwa silna osłona snajperska ze strony wroga.\n Warunki pogodowe: widoczność - 700, możliwa obecność wcześniej nierozpoznanych anomalii.\n \n \n \n \n</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_x16_documents_name">
		<rus>Выжигатель мозгов рукотворен?</rus>
		<eng>Is the Brain Scorcher man-made?</eng>
		<ukr>Випалювач мізків рукотворний?</ukr>
		<fra>Le lobotomisateur construit par l'homme</fra>
		<pln>"Mózgozwęglacz" to dzieło człowieka?</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_research_normal">
		<rus>...как оказалось, излучение прежде всего воздействует на высшие области мышления. Опыты показали, что только человек и животные с высокоорганизованным мышлением, такие как собаки, лошади, чувствительны к этому излучению. Из них лишь человек полностью подвержен эффекту погружения в транс, на подопытных животных эффект оставался в пределах сильного страха. Исходя из этих предпосылок, можно сделать вывод о специализации воздействия исключительно на человеческий мозг. Продолжительные эксперименты на добровольцах показали, что эффект транса может быть снят при медикаментозном лечении. Также нами были разработаны экспериментальные устройства, которые защищают человеческий мозг от дозированного воздействия излучения. По нашим расчётам, источник излучения находится в центре озера Янтарь, вероятнее всего, природа источника искусственная, и его вполне возможно отключить. Также есть опасность, что неблагонадёжные элементы могут получить доступ к источнику излучения и попытаться взять его под свой контроль.</rus>
		<eng>... as it turns out, the emissions affect primarily the advanced spheres of cognitive activity. Experiments show that only humans and animals with developed cognitive processes, such as dogs and horses are susceptible to these emissions. Of the above, only humans enter a state of trance - in animals the effect is limited to a strong feeling of fear. Judging by this evidence, it would be reasonable to conclude that the emissions are geared specifically towards the human brain. Extensive studies on "volunteers" have shown that subjects will leave the trance state if given medicamental treatment. We also developed experimental devices that will protect, to a certain extent, the human brain from these emissions. According to our calculations, the source of these emissions is located in the center of Lake Yantar. The source itself is likely to be artificial in nature, which means that it can be disabled. There is also the danger of criminals attempting to reach the source of the emissions and gaining control over it.</eng>
		<ukr>... як виявилося, випромінювання насамперед впливає на вищі області мислення. Досліди показали, що тільки людина і тварини з високоорганізованим мисленням, такі як собаки, коні, чутливі до цього випромінювання. З них лише людина повністю піддається ефекту занурення в транс, на піддослідних тварин ефект залишався в межах сильного страху. Виходячи з цих передумов, можна зробити висновок про спеціалізацію впливу виключно на людський мозок. Тривалі експерименти на добровольцях показали, що ефект трансу може бути знятий при медикаментозному лікуванні. Також нами були розроблені експериментальні пристрої, які захищають людський мозок від дозованого впливу випромінювання. За нашими розрахунками, джерело випромінювання знаходиться в центрі озера Янтар, найімовірніше, природа джерела штучна, і його цілком можливо відключити. Також є небезпека, що неблагонадійні елементи можуть отримати доступ до джерела випромінювання і спробувати взяти його під свій контроль.</ukr>
		<fra>Il s'est avéré que les radiations affectent principalement les zones de pensée les plus élevées. Des expériences ont montré que seuls les hommes et les animaux à pensée très organisée, tels que les chiens et les chevaux, sont sensibles à ce rayonnement. Parmi ceux-ci, seule une personne est complètement soumise à l'effet de l'immersion dans une transe, l'effet sur les animaux de laboratoire restant dans les limites d'une forte peur. Sur la base de ces hypothèses, on peut conclure à la spécialisation des effets exclusivement sur le cerveau humain. Des expériences à long terme sur des volontaires ont montré que l’effet de la transe peut être éliminé avec un traitement médical. Nous avons également mis au point des dispositifs expérimentaux qui protègent le cerveau humain contre l'exposition au rayonnement mesurée. Selon nos calculs, la source de rayonnement est située au centre du lac Yantar. Il est fort probable que la nature de la source soit artificielle et qu'il est tout à fait possible de l'éteindre. Il existe également un risque que des éléments non fiables accèdent à la source de rayonnement et tentent de prendre le contrôle de celle-ci.</fra>
		<pln>...Okazuje się, że emisje mają wpływ głównie na zaawansowane sfery aktywności poznawczej. Eksperymenty dowodzą, że jedynie ludzie oraz zwierzęta takie jak konie czy psy, u których występują skomplikowane procesy poznawcze, są wrażliwe na te emisje. Natomiast z pośród już wspomnianych gatunków jedynie ludzie wpadają w swoisty trans - u zwierząt efekt jest ograniczony do odczuwania silnego strachu. Na podstawie tych dowodów można wyciągnąć uzasadniony wniosek, że wspomniane emisje mają na celu oddziaływanie na mózg ludzki. Szeroko zakrojone badania przeprowadzone na "ochotnikach" dowodzą, że badani wybudzają się z transu dzięki opiece medycznej. Stworzyliśmy również prototypy urządzeń, które do pewnego stopnia będą chronić ludzki mózg przed tymi emisjami. Zgodnie z obliczeniami źródło emisji znajduje się pośrodku Jeziora Jantar. Samo źródło prawdopodobnie nie jest pochodzenia naturalnego, co znaczy, że można je wyłączyć. Istnieje również niebezpieczeństwo, że przestępcy będą chcieli się do niego dostać i przejąć nad nim kontrolę.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_tunel_gordon_diary">
		<rus>12.01.2012 \nЧёрт бы побрал это начальство. Не дадут покоя старику. Сперва "Чёрная Месса", затем непонятный город в России. Теперь вот опять: "Поезжай-ка ты, старина, в бескрайние степи Украины. Держи свою фомку и удачного времяпровождения". \n\n20.03.2012 \nПробрался в Зону. Неужели здесь нет медведей? И с кем мне тогда предстоит сражаться? В целом осваиваюсь с трудом. За мясные консервы пришлось отдать ломик. \n\n26.04.2012 \nНачался Выброс. Бармен сказал, чтобы я поскорее спрятал свою задницу и не высовывался. Выгнал из заброшенного тоннеля нескольких крыс. Надеюсь переждать в нём непогоду.</rus>
		<eng>12.01.2012 \n God damn my bosses...won't leave an old man alone. First Black Mesa, then some strange town in Russia. And now they send poor little Gordon into the endless Ukrainian plains. Take your jemmy and have fun. \n \n 20.03.2012 \n Made it into the Zone. Are there really no bears here? Who am I going to fight then? I'm not finding my bearings too well in this place. I had to give my little crowbar away for a can of meat. \n \n 26.04.2012 \n The blowout has started. Barkeep told me to hide my ass and keep it hidden. I chased some rats out of an abandoned tunnel. I hope to wait out the bad weather in here.</eng>
		<ukr>12.01.2012 \nЧорти б забрали це начальство. Не дадуть спокою старому. Спершу "Чорна Меса", потім незрозуміле місто в Росії. Тепер ось знову: "Їдь-но ти, старий, в безкраї степи України. Тримай свою фомку і вдалого проведення часу". \n\n20.03.2012 \nПробрався в Зону. Невже тут немає ведмедів? І з ким мені тоді належить битися? В цілому освоююся насилу. За м'ясні консерви довелося віддати ломик. \n\n26.04.2012 \nПочався Викид. Бармен сказав, щоб я скоріше сховав свою дупу і не висовувався. Вигнав з покинутого тунелю кількох щурів. Сподіваюся перечекати в ньому негоду.</ukr>
		<fra>12.01.2012\nFoutus patrons... Ils me foutront donc jamais la paix. D'abord Mesa, et puis cette ville étrange en Russie. Et maintenant, ils envoient ce pauvre Gordon au fin fond de l'Ukraine. Prends ton pied-de-biche et amuse-toi bien.\n\n20.03.2012\n Je suis rentré dans la Zone. C'est vrai qu'il n'y a pas d'ours ici ? Alors, avec qui je vais me battre? J'ai du mal à me repérer. J'ai dû échanger mon pied-de-biche contre une boîte de conserve.\n\n26.04.2012\nC'est le déluge. Le Barman m'a dit de me trouver une planque et d'y rester. J'ai chassé quelques rats d'un tunnel abandonné. J'espère que je vais pouvoir attendre ici jusqu'à ce que le temps s'améliore.</fra>
		<pln>12.01.2012 \n Szlag by trafił moich szefów... Nie dadzą spokoju staremu człowiekowi. Najpierw "Black Mesa", potem jakieś dziwne miasto w Rosji. A teraz wysyłają biednego Gordona na niekończące się ukraińskie równiny. Weź łom i baw się dobrze. \n \n 20.03.2012 \n Dotarłem do Zony. Czyli tutaj naprawdę nie ma niedźwiedzi? To z czym niby mam walczyć? Nie mam tu zbyt dobrego rozeznania. Musiałem oddać swój łom za puszkę mięsa. \n \n 26.04.2012 \n Rozpoczęła się emisja. Barman poradził mi się schować i nie ruszać z miejsca. Wygoniłem szczury z jakiegoś opuszczonego tunelu. Mam nadzieję, że uda mi się tu przeczekać.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="d6_blend_pda">
		<rus>КПК Бленда</rus>
		<eng>Blend's PDA</eng>
		<ukr>КПК Бленда</ukr>
		<fra>===КПК Бленда</fra>
		<pln>===КПК Бленда</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_blend_pda">
		<rus>КПК Бленда. Содержит послание Стрелку.</rus>
		<eng>Blend's PDA. Contains a message to Strelok.</eng>
		<ukr>КПК Бленда. Містить послання Стрільцю.</ukr>
		<fra>===КПК Бленда. Содержит послание Стрелку.</fra>
		<pln>===КПК Бленда. Содержит послание Стрелку.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_blend_info">
		<rus>Стрелок, если ты читаешь это сообщение, значит уже добрался до Бункера Д-6 и сейчас разносишь группировку Последний День.\n Ты уже догадался, что мы не здешние, так сказать. Есть много миров за пределами вашего. Наши учёные, проводя какие-то эксперименты, случайно открыли портал в ваш мир. И попали именно в Зону. Нас поразило, насколько богат ваш мир, и сколько свободной энергии накапливает это место. Выбросы в Зоне - это высвобождение накопленной энергии или, другим словом, разрядка. Это порождает мутацию у некоторых животных, рождение аномалий и артефактов. Да, не все мутанты порождения Зоны. Некоторые выведены вашими учёными в лабораториях путём экспериментов с артефактами, радиацией и пси-энергией, другие прибыли из нашего мира... Ну и сам понимаешь, наши боссы не могли оставить это без внимания. Начался постепенный захват этой территории, закрытие лабораторий, уничтожение информации и людей. Некоторых вербуют в наши ряды, неугодных уничтожают. Но люди вашего мира упрямы и любопытны, и у вас есть такое понятие, как дружба и защита себе подобных.\n Со временем я понял, что мы пришли сюда, чтобы разрушить всё это. Всю уникальность Зоны и её красоту. После этого обязательно последует захват территорий уже за пределами Зоны, а я не хочу участвовать в этом. Я хочу остаться здесь, в вашем мире. Я покинул клан со своими людьми и попробую жить простым человеком.\n Стрелок, в Тёмной Долине ты проявил благоразумие и не стал вступать со мной в конфликт. Спасибо тебе за это. В благодарность я оставляю тебе этот тайник. Надеюсь, он тебя порадует.\n На этом прощай, вряд ли мы ещё с тобой увидимся.</rus>
		<eng>Strelok, if you're reading this message, it means you've already made it to Bunker D-6 and are now destroying the Last Day faction.\n You've already guessed that we're not from here, so to speak. There are many worlds beyond yours. Our scientists, conducting some experiments, accidentally opened a portal to your world. And it was precisely to the Zone. We were struck by how rich your world is and how much free energy this place accumulates. Blowouts in the Zone are a release of stored energy, or in other words, a discharge. It generates mutations in some animals, the birth of anomalies and artifacts. Yes, not all mutants are from the Zone. Some are bred by your scientists in laboratories through experiments with artifacts, radiation and psi energy, others came from our world... Well, you know, our bosses couldn't let that go unnoticed. They began a gradual takeover of this area, shutting down laboratories, destroying information and killing people. Some are recruited into our ranks, the unwanted are destroyed. But the people of your world are stubborn and curious, and you have such a concept as friendship and protecting your own kind.\n Over time, I realized that we came here to destroy it all. All the uniqueness of the Zone and its beauty. After that, surely a takeover of lands outside the Zone would follow, and I don't want to be a part of that. I want to stay here in your world. I left the faction with my people and will try to live as a simple man.\n Strelok, you were reasonable in Dark Valley, and you didn't confront me. Thank you for that. As a thank you, I leave you this stash. I hope it pleases you.\n Goodbye, I don't think I'll be seeing you again.</eng>
		<ukr>Стрілок, якщо ти читаєш це повідомлення, значить вже добрався до Бункера Д-6 і зараз розносиш угруповання Останній День.\n Ти вже здогадався, що ми не тутешні, так би мовити. Є багато світів за межами вашого. Наші вчені, проводячи якісь експерименти, випадково відкрили портал у ваш світ. І потрапили саме в Зону. Нас вразило, наскільки багатий ваш світ і скільки вільної енергії накопичує це місце. Викиди в Зоні - це вивільнення накопиченої енергії, розрядка так би мовити. Це породжує мутацію у деяких тварин, народження аномалій і артефактів. Так, не всі мутанти, породження Зони. Деякі виведені вашими вченими в лабораторіях, шляхом експерементів з артефактами, радіацією і псі-енергією... Ну і сам розумієш, наші боси не могли залишити це без уваги. Почалося поступове захоплення цієї території, закриття лабораторій, знищення інформації і людей. Деяких вербують в наші ряди, неугодних знищують. Але люди вашого світу вперті і цікаві і у вас є таке поняття, як дружба і захист собі подібних.\n Згодом я зрозумів, що ми прийшли сюди, щоб зруйнувати все це. Всю унікальність Зони і її красу. Після цього обов'язково піде захоплення територій вже за межами Зони, а я не хочу брати участь у цьому. Я хочу залишитися тут, у вашому світі. Я покинув клан зі своїми людьми і спробую жити простою людиною.\n Стрілець, в Темній Долині ти проявив розсудливість і не став вступати зі мною в конфлікт. Спасибі тобі за це. На знак подяки я залишаю тобі цю схованку. Сподіваюся, вона тебе порадує.\n На цьому прощавай, навряд чи ми ще з тобою побачимося.</ukr>
		<fra>===Стрелок, если ты читаешь это сообщение, значит уже добрался до Бункера Д-6 и сейчас разносишь группировку Последний День.\n Ты уже догадался, что мы не здешние, так сказать. Есть много миров за пределами вашего. Наши учёные, проводя какие-то эксперементы, случайно открыли портал в ваш мир. И попали именно в Зону. Нас поразило, насколько богат ваш мир и сколько свободной энергии накапливает это место. Выбросы в зоне - это высвобождение накопленной энергии, разрядка так сказать. Это порождает мутацию у некоторых животных, рождение аномалий и артефактов. Да, не все мутанты, порождение Зоны. Некоторые выведены вашими учёными в лабораториях, путём эксперементов с артефактами, радиацией и пси-энергией... Ну и сам понимаешь, наши боссы не могли оставить это без внимания. Начался постепенный захват этой территории, закрытие лабораторий, уничтожение информации и людей. Некоторых вербуют в наши ряды, неугодных уничтожают. Но люди вашего мира упрямы и любопытны и у вас есть такое понятие, как дружба и защита себе подобных.\n Со временем я понял, что мы пришли сюда, что бы разрушить всё это. Всю уникальность Зоны и её красоту. После этого обязательно последует захват территорий уже за пределами Зоны, а я не хочу участвовать в этом. Я хочу остаться здесь, в вашем мире. Я покинул клан со своими людьми и попробую жить простым человеком.\n Стрелок, в Тёмной Долине ты проявил благоразумие и не стал вступать со мной в конфликт. Спасибо тебе за это. В благодарность я оставляю тебе этот тайник. Надеюсь, он тебя порадует.\n На этом прощай, вряд ли мы ещё с тобой увидимся.</fra>
		<pln>===Стрелок, если ты читаешь это сообщение, значит уже добрался до Бункера Д-6 и сейчас разносишь группировку Последний День.\n Ты уже догадался, что мы не здешние, так сказать. Есть много миров за пределами вашего. Наши учёные, проводя какие-то эксперементы, случайно открыли портал в ваш мир. И попали именно в Зону. Нас поразило, насколько богат ваш мир и сколько свободной энергии накапливает это место. Выбросы в зоне - это высвобождение накопленной энергии, разрядка так сказать. Это порождает мутацию у некоторых животных, рождение аномалий и артефактов. Да, не все мутанты, порождение Зоны. Некоторые выведены вашими учёными в лабораториях, путём эксперементов с артефактами, радиацией и пси-энергией... Ну и сам понимаешь, наши боссы не могли оставить это без внимания. Начался постепенный захват этой территории, закрытие лабораторий, уничтожение информации и людей. Некоторых вербуют в наши ряды, неугодных уничтожают. Но люди вашего мира упрямы и любопытны и у вас есть такое понятие, как дружба и защита себе подобных.\n Со временем я понял, что мы пришли сюда, что бы разрушить всё это. Всю уникальность Зоны и её красоту. После этого обязательно последует захват территорий уже за пределами Зоны, а я не хочу участвовать в этом. Я хочу остаться здесь, в вашем мире. Я покинул клан со своими людьми и попробую жить простым человеком.\n Стрелок, в Тёмной Долине ты проявил благоразумие и не стал вступать со мной в конфликт. Спасибо тебе за это. В благодарность я оставляю тебе этот тайник. Надеюсь, он тебя порадует.\n На этом прощай, вряд ли мы ещё с тобой увидимся.</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="saving_muha">
		<rus>Спасение Мухи</rus>
		<eng>Saving Fly</eng>
		<ukr>Порятунок Мухи</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="saving_muha_text">
		<rus>Чёрт бы побрал эту Зону, этого Звездочёта и иже с ними! Ничего кроме бабок и власти не видят. Жизнь простого человека для них ничто. Даже жизнь ребёнка, случайно попавшего в Зону. Попробую спасти эту невинную девчонку. Чёрный Доктор ждёт в Госпитале, говорит, что для оживления Мухи нужны арты - "Сердце полтергейста", который я давал Клёнову для экспериментов, и тот арт, что стащила девчонка и найденный мною на этой трижды проклятой ЧАЭС-2, забравшей жизнь моего друга. В общем, забираю нужные арты и двигаю в Госпиталь, а там видно будет.</rus>
		<eng>Damn this Zone, this Skygazer and others! They see nothing but money and power. The life of an ordinary man is nothing to them. Not even the life of a child who accidentally got into the Zone. I'll try to save this innocent girl. Black Doctor is waiting in the hospital, saying that in order to revive Fly, an artifact is needed - the "Poltergeist's Heart", which I gave Klyonov for the experiments, the art that the girl stole and I found on this thrice-cursed Chernobyl-2, which took my friend's life. I need to take the artifact to the Hospital, and then we'll see what happens.</eng>
		<ukr>Чорт би взяв цю Зону, цього Звіздаря і йому подібних! Нічого крім бабок та влади не бачать. Життя простої людини для них – ніщо. Навіть життя дитини, яка випадково потрапила до Зони. Спробую врятувати це невинне дівчисько. Чорний Лікар чекає у Шпиталі, каже, що для оживлення Мухи потрібні арти - "Серце полтергейста", який я давав Кльонову для експериментів, і той арт, що вкрало дівчисько і знайдений мною на цій тричі проклятій ЧАЕС-2, яка забрала життя мого друга. Загалом забираю потрібні арти і рухаю до Шпиталю, а там видно буде.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_secret_sprey_name">
		<rus>Любопытная информация от Сидоровича</rus>
		<eng>Curious information from Sidorovich</eng>
		<ukr>Цікава інформація від Сидоровича</ukr>
		<fra>===Любопытная информация от Сидоровича</fra>
		<pln>===Любопытная информация от Сидоровича</pln>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_secret_sprey_text">
		<rus>Сидор поделился со мной весьма любопытной информацией:\n Помимо исследования возможностей человека, влияния на его сознание, испытания новых образцов оружия и экспериментов с телепортацией, в Зоне Отчуждения активно проводился и более мелкий по значимости спектр исследований. Одно из самых удачных направлений такой деятельности - химический спрей "Свояк-29", который был выпущен экспериментальной партией в одной из подземных лабораторий с литерой "Х" на основе удачных разработок НИИ "Злынка", засекреченного объекта в лесах Брянской области. Спрей, созданный на основе симбиоза органики и синтетических составляющих последнего поколения, при нанесении на х/б ткань позволял владельцу костюма становится "невидимым" для подавляющей части хищников, мелких грызунов и даже насекомых, как естественного происхождения, так и подвергшихся мутациям. Принцип "невидимости" основывался на том, что животные принимали владельца обработанного костюма за своего и не испытывали к нему никакой агрессии.\n После коротких испытаний, когда эффективность спрея "Свояк" была доказана, он быстро вошёл в моду в Зоне Отчуждения, но повсеместного распространения не получил. Одна из частных коммерческих фирм военной направленности быстро сориентировалась, выкупила формулу разработки и на промышленной основе, хоть и мелкими партиями, начала выпускать уже готовую ткань, пропитанную спреем для самых разнообразных костюмов и брони, использовавшейся по большей части только в Зоне Отчуждения. В дальнейшем, основными владельцами изделий с пропитанной тканью стали военные и наёмники, но в конечном счёте окольными, нелегальными путями доступ к ней получили самые различные группировки и даже бандиты. Компания-производитель строго следила за монополией на выпуск "Свояка" и количеством распространяемой ткани. Поговаривают, что весь бизнес контролировали силовики, что косвенно подтверждает крупный пожар в НИИ "Злынка", случившийся сразу после отказа от коммерческих прав на свой удачный продукт. Оставшийся после пожара персонал расформировали и направили на другие разработки в другие институты. Надо ли говорить, что рецепт и сопроводительная документация на "Свояк-29" при этом были утеряны или погребены огненной стихией...\n Что касается лаборатории с литерой "Х", в которой была выпущена первая экспериментальная партия спрея, то по слухам она по прежнему существует на просторах Зоны Отчуждения, и её активно ищут не только сталкеры-нейтралы, но и новые группировки, в надежде, что в ней остались хоть какие-то секреты или запасы так нужной всем удачной разработки...\n Сидор попросил меня, в случае, если я нападу на след этой загадочной лаборатории "Х" и проникну туда, поделиться с ним любой информацией, касающейся этого спрея. \n \n \n \n \n</rus>
		<eng>Sidorovich shared some very interesting bit of information with me:\n In addition to research on human capabilities, influence on human consciousness, testing of new weapons, and experiments with teleportation, a smaller range of studies were also actively conducted in the Exclusion Zone. One of the most successful cases of such activity was the "Svoyak-29" chemical spray, which was produced in an experimental batch in one of the underground "X" laboratories, based on the successful development of the "Zlynka" Research Institute, a classified facility in the forests of Bryansk. The spray was based on a mix of the latest generation organic and synthetic compounds. When applied to cotton fabric, it allowed the wearer to become "invisible" to the overwhelming majority of predators, small rodents and even insects of both natural origin and those that had undergone mutations. The invisibility works by making animals take the wearer of the treated suit for one of their own and therefore do not feel any aggression towards them.\n After brief tests, when the effectiveness of the "Svoyak" spray was proven, it quickly became popular in the Exclusion Zone, but it did not become widespread. One of the private military commercial firms quickly found it, bought the formula and began to produce small batches of pre-impregnated fabric for a wide variety of suits and armor, mostly used only in the Exclusion Zone. Later on, the military and mercenaries became the main customers of the impregnated cloth products, but eventually, through backdoor, illegal means, a variety of factions and even bandits gained access to it. The manufacturing company kept a strict monopoly on the production of the "Svoyak" and the amount of fabric distributed. It is rumored that the entire business was controlled by the power-hungry military generals. Suspiciously, the research material in the "Zlynka" Research Institute were destroyed by a large fire just after giving up the commercial rights to the product. The staff that survived the fire was transferred to other research institutes. Needless to say, the recipe and documentation for "Svoyak-29" were lost or destroyed by the fire...\n As for the "X" laboratory, which produced the first experimental batch of spray, is rumored to still exist in the vastness of the Exclusion Zone, and it is actively searched for not only neutral stalkers, but also new factions, in the hope that it left at least some secrets or supplies needed for successful production of the spray.\n Sidorovich asked me, in case I caught wind of this mysterious "X" lab and infiltrated it, to share any information regarding this spray. \n \n \n \n \n</eng>
		<ukr>Сидор поділився зі мною цікавою інформацією:\n Крім дослідження можливостей людини, впливу на її свідомість, випробування нових зразків зброї та експериментів з телепортацією, у Зоні Відчуження активно проводився і дрібніший за значимістю спектр досліджень. Один із найвдаліших напрямків такої діяльності - хімічний спрей "Свояк-29", який був випущений експериментальною партією в одній із підземних лабораторій з літерою "Х" на основі вдалих розробок НДІ "Злинка", засекреченого об'єкта у лісах Брянської області. Спрей, створений на основі симбіозу органіки та синтетичних складових останнього покоління, при нанесенні на бавовняну тканину дозволяв власнику костюма стати "невидимим" для переважної частини хижаків, дрібних гризунів і навіть комах, як природного походження, так і мутацій. Принцип "невидимості" ґрунтувався на тому, що тварини приймали власника обробленого костюма за свого та не відчували до нього жодної агресії.\n Після коротких випробувань, коли ефективність спрею "Свояк" була доведена, він швидко увійшов у моду в Зоні Відчуження, але повсюдного поширення не набув. Одна з приватних комерційних фірм військової спрямованості швидко зорієнтувалася, викупила формулу розробки і на промисловій основі, хоч і дрібними партіями, почала випускати вже готову тканину, просочену спреєм для найрізноманітніших костюмів та броні, яка використовувалася здебільшого лише у Зоні Відчуження. Надалі, основними власниками виробів з просоченою тканиною стали військові та найманці, але в кінцевому рахунку манівцями, нелегальними шляхами доступ до неї отримали різні угруповання і навіть бандити. Компанія-виробник суворо стежила за монополією на випуск "Свояка" і кількістю тканини, що розповсюджується. Подейкують, що весь бізнес контролювали силовики, що опосередковано підтверджує велику пожежу в НДІ "Злинка", що сталася відразу після відмови від комерційних прав на свій вдалий продукт. Персонал, що залишився після пожежі, розформували і направили на інші розробки в інші інститути. Чи треба говорити, що рецепт та супровідна документація на "Свояк-29" при цьому були втрачені або поховані вогненною стихією.\n Що стосується лабораторії з літерою "Х", в якій була випущена перша експериментальна партія спрею, то за чутками вона як і раніше існує на просторах Зони Відчуження, і її активно шукають не тільки сталкери-нейтрали, а й нові угруповання, сподіваючись, що в ній залишилися хоч якісь секрети чи запаси такої потрібної всім вдалої розробки...\n Сидор попросив мене, якщо я нападу на слід цієї загадкової лабораторії "Х" і проникну туди, поділитися з ним будь-якою інформацією щодо цього спрею. \n \n \n \n \n</ukr>
	</string>

</string_table>