<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="flame_reload_1">
		<text>Ты говорил, что можешь перезарядить огнемёт? Думаю, сейчас самое время это сделать.</text>
		<eng>You said that you could reload a flame-thrower? I think now's the very time to do it.</eng>
		<ukr>Ти казав, що можеш перезарядити вогнемет? Думаю, зараз саме час це зробити.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_2">
		<text>Ага, могу. Горючку нашёл? Или мне самому придётся мучиться? Предупреждаю, если я всё сам буду искать, это тебе обойдётся в 30 тысяч. Да и на трезвую голову может не получиться... Так что бутылочку водки тоже прихвати!</text>
		<eng>Yes, sure. Did you find the fuel? Or do I need to trouble myself about it? I'm warning you, if I need to look for myself, it will cost you 30 grand. And I need to get something in my system to do that... So bring me a bottle of vodka too!</eng>
		<ukr>Ага, можу. Горючку знайшов? Або мені самому доведеться мучитися? Попереджаю, якщо я все сам буду шукати, це тобі обійдеться в 30 тисяч. Та й на тверезу голову може не вийти... Так що пляшечку горілки теж прихопи!</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_3">
		<text>Опять водка?! Нет уж, обойдёшься. И с деньгами сейчас напряг. Как-нибудь без огнемёта проживу.</text>
		<eng>Booze again?! No, not this time. And considering my financial problems right now, I'll get along without a flame-thrower.</eng>
		<ukr>Знову горілка?! Ні вже, обійдешся. І з грошима зараз напряг. Як-небудь без вогнемета проживу.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_4">
		<text>Сколько ж ты можешь выпить? На, держи. И горючку я добыл. Только давай быстрее.</text>
		<eng>How can you drink so much? Okay, here you go. And the fuel too. Just get it done.</eng>
		<ukr>Скільки ж ти можеш випити? На, тримай. І горючку я добув. Тільки давай швидше.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_5">
		<text>Минут 30 подождать придётся.</text>
		<eng>Now just wait about half an hour.</eng>
		<ukr>Хвилин 30 почекати доведеться.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_6">
		<text>Ладно. Но учти, я спешу.</text>
		<eng>Agreed. But I'm in a hurry, don't forget it.</eng>
		<ukr>Гаразд. Але врахуй, я поспішаю.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_7">
		<text>Нет, ничего я не нашёл. Вот, бери 30 штук и пузырь. Шустрей работай только!</text>
		<eng>No, I couldn't find anything. Here, take your 30 grand and a bottle. Be swift, please!</eng>
		<ukr>Ні, нічого я не знайшов. Ось, бери 30 штук і пляшку. Пошвидше працюй тільки!</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_8">
		<text>Так... Спасибо. Ну, думаю, тебе стоит зайти через денёк.</text>
		<eng>Yeah... Thanks. Well, come back in a day.</eng>
		<ukr>Так... Дякую. Ну, думаю, тобі варто зайти через день.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_9">
		<text>Ни фига себе! Денёк... Спасибо, мастер... по литрболу... Счастливо!</text>
		<eng>Shoot me! In a day... Thank you... Drunken master... Good-bye!</eng>
		<ukr>Ні фіга собі! Деньок... Спасибі, майстер... по літрболу... Щасливо!</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_10">
		<text>Что там с заправкой моего огнемёта?</text>
		<eng>What about my flame-thrower?</eng>
		<ukr>Що там із заправкою мого вогнемета?</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_11">
		<text>Всё в лучшем виде! Иначе я и не делаю! Забирай.</text>
		<eng>In a superior shape! I couldn't do otherwise! Take it.</eng>
		<ukr>Все в кращому вигляді! Інакше я і не роблю! Забирай.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_12">
		<text>Благодарствую! До встречи.</text>
		<eng>Thanks a lot! See you later.</eng>
		<ukr>Гарно дякую! До зустрічі.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_13">
		<text>Погоди ты пока! Дело это непростое. Позже зайди.</text>
		<eng>Come on, wait a bit! It's not so easy. Come back later.</eng>
		<ukr>Стривай ти поки! Справа ця непроста. Пізніше зайди.</ukr>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_14">
		<text>Ясно. Давай активнее!</text>
		<eng>Of course. Get on with it!</eng>
		<ukr>Ясно. Давай активніше!</ukr>
	</string>
</string_table>